<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-1109.08</num>
  <heading>Formation of a replacement independent interstate legal entity.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law and pursuant to the authority and subject to the requirements set forth in 49 U.S.C. ยง 5329, to enable the Metropolitan Washington Council of Governments ("COG") to assist the District in the formation of an independent interstate legal entity to replace the Tristate Oversight Committee as the joint state oversight agency contemplated by <cite path="9|11|V">this subchapter</cite>, the Mayor is authorized to transfer funds by contract, grant, subgrant, or other available means to COG.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The authority under this section shall include the authority to transfer:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Federal funds received by the District for expenses related to the formation of the replacement independent interstate legal entity; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any matching funds required to be appropriated by the District in order to receive and spend such federal funds.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any agreement or proposal to form an independent interstate legal entity to replace the joint state oversight agency authorized by <cite path="9|11|V">this subchapter</cite> shall be submitted to the Council for approval.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-20" type="History" path="ยง8a">Sept. 23, 1997, D.C. Law 12-20, ยง 8a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="ยง2262" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
