<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-1108.11</num>
  <text>
            *NOTE: This section includes amendments by temporary legislation that will expire on February 4, 2022. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite path="§9-1108.11(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
         </text>
  <heading>Requirements for appointment and service on the Board of Directors of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person who is appointed to serve on the Board of Directors of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (“Board”) shall comply with the following requirements:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The person shall not have been an employee of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (“WMATA”) within one year of appointment to the Board.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The person shall have experience in at least one of the following areas:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Transit planning;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Transportation planning;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Land use planning;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Transit or transportation management or other public-sector management;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Engineering;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Finance;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Public Safety;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Homeland security;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>Human resources;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>Law; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(K)</num>
        <text>Knowledge of the WMATA region’s transportation issues.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The person shall be a patron of services provided by the WMATA.</text>
    </para>
    <para placeholder="Repealed">
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Persons appointed to the Board shall file an annual report with the Council on or before April 30 of each calendar year. The report shall include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The dates of attendance at WMATA Board meetings;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The reason for not attending a meeting;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Dates and attendance at other WMATA-related public events; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>An affirmation of the member’s use of the bus, rail, or paratransit services of the WMATA since submission of the previous report.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For the purpose of transitioning to a composition of staggered terms, initial appointments to the Board shall be made on July 1, 2013, as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A principal member shall be appointed for a term of 4 years;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An alternate member shall be appointed for a term of 3 years;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A principal member shall be appointed for a term of 2 years; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>An alternate member shall be appointed for a term of one year.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Thereafter, members shall be appointed for 4-year terms.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Appointments, including appointments for the completion of an unexpired term, for fewer than 3 years shall not count for the purposes of term limits.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>To prevent extended vacancies on the Board, each person appointed may continue to serve until replaced or reappointed, for a period not to exceed 12 months.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Each person appointed to the Board shall serve at the pleasure of the Council and may be removed for any reason, including failure to adhere to the requirements of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-286" type="History" path="§2">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-286, § 2, 60 DCR 2319</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2 and 3 of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Board of Directors Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-216, November 23, 2013,  60 DCR 16522, 20 STAT 2606).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Board of Directors Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-105, July 9, 2013,  60 DCR 10598, 20 DCSTAT 1812).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Board of Directors Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-39">D.C. Law 20-39</cite>, Nov. 5, 2013,  60 DCR 12151).</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-30" path="§816" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-17" eff="2021-03-17">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-30" path="§816">§ 816 of Coronavirus Support Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-30, Mar. 17, 2021, 68 DCR 003101)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-17" doc="D.C. Act 24-30" eff="2021-03-17" path="§816" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-96" path="§816" codified:display="Note" app="2021-06-07" eff="2021-06-07">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-96" path="§816">§ 816 of Coronavirus Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-96, June 7, 2021, 68 DCR 006025)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-06-07" doc="D.C. Act 24-96" eff="2021-06-07" path="§816" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-06-24" doc="D.C. Law 24-9" eff="2021-06-24" path="§816" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-06-24" doc="D.C. Law 24-9" eff="2021-06-24" path="§816" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 24-9" path="§816" codified:display="Note" app="2021-06-24" eff="2021-06-24">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-9" path="§816">§ 816 of Coronavirus Support Temporary Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Law 24-9, June 24, 2021, 68 DCR 004824)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
