<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-204.24</num>
  <heading>Implementation of public space, street, and alley names.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Following the effective date of an act to designate the official name of an alley or street, or portion thereof, the Mayor shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Update relevant records of the District of Columbia to reflect the official name of an alley or street, or portion thereof, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department records;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency records;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B-i)</num>
        <text>District Department of Transportation and Office of the Chief Technology Officer records;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>District of Columbia maps; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Any other record of the District of Columbia used for way-finding or address purposes;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Notify the United States Postal Service, other relevant government agencies as determined by the Mayor, and relevant private sector entities as determined by the Mayor, of the official name of the alley or street, or portion thereof; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Install signage indicating the official name of the alley or street, or portion thereof, using procedures established by the District Department of Transportation, and remove any signs with a previous name; provided, that at least one sign bearing the previous name of the alley or street, or portion thereof, shall be transferred to the Archives of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Following the effective date of an act to designate an official name of a public space other than an alley or street, or portion thereof, the Mayor may install signage denoting the public space name.  The signage shall conform to the policies of the agency with jurisdiction over the public space.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Following the effective date of an act to designate an official name of an alley or street, or portion thereof, or other public space, the Surveyor of the District of Columbia shall record a copy of the act and the Surveyor's plat in the Office of the Surveyor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>When legislation to designate a symbolic name for an alley or street, or portion thereof, or other public space becomes effective, the Mayor may install signage denoting the area of the designation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The design used for signage for a symbolic name of an alley or street, or portion thereof, including any replacement signage, shall be uniform and distinct from the design used for signage for official names, except for those signs installed before October 8, 2016.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-201" type="History" path="§424">Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-201, § 424</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-161" eff="2016-10-08" path="§2|(h)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-161" eff="2016-10-08" path="§2|(h)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§1142|(e)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-07-20" eff="2017-07-20">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§1142|(e)">§ 1142(e) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104, July 20, 2017, 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-07-20" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" eff="2017-07-20" path="§1142|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§1142|(e)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-10-24" eff="2017-10-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§1142|(e)">§ 1142(e) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167, Oct. 24, 2017, 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-10-24" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" eff="2017-10-24" path="§1142|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1142|(e)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
