<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-204.21</num>
  <heading>Designation of official names of streets and alleys.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any designation of an alley or street, or portion thereof, with an official name shall meet the requirements of §§ <cite path="§9-204.02">9-204.02</cite> and <cite path="§9-204.03">9-204.03</cite>, as well as the requirements of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>At least 15 days, but no more than 60 days, before the date of a Council hearing to consider legislation to designate the official name of an alley or street, or portion thereof, the initiator of the proposal to designate the official name of an alley or street, or portion thereof, shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Give written notice of the date, time, and location of the Council hearing to each owner of property and household occupying property that abuts the alley or street, or portion thereof, proposed to be designated with an official name; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Post signs that indicate the date, time, and location of the Council hearing at each intersection with any other alley or street of the portion of the alley or street proposed to be designated.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall make available the signs to be posted pursuant to subsection (b)(2) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>At least 30 days before the date of a Council hearing to consider legislation to designate the official name of an alley or street, or portion thereof, the initiator of the proposal to designate the official name of an alley or street, or portion thereof, shall submit a copy of the proposed legislation for review and comment to each Advisory Neighborhood Commission in which the portion of the alley or street to be designated is located.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The initiator of a proposal to designate the official name of an alley or street, or portion thereof, shall certify to the Council that the notice required by subsection (b) of this section has been given.  A post-office receipt of proof of mailing of the notice to each resident's or property owner's last known address and a photograph of each posted sign shall be sufficient proof that the required notice was given.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>At least 5 days before the date of a Council hearing to consider legislation to designate an official name for an alley or street, or portion thereof, the initiator of the proposal to designate the official name of an alley or street, or portion thereof, shall submit to the Council letters or a petition in support of the proposal that have been signed by a majority of the owners of property and households occupying property that abuts the portion of the alley or street proposed to be designated with an official name.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Before consideration by the Council, including a vote by a committee of the Council, of a bill to designate an official name for an alley or street, or portion thereof, the Mayor shall provide the Council with a surveyor's plat showing:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The alley or street, or portion thereof, to be designated;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The square or squares in which the portion of the alley or street to be designated is located and any adjacent squares; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The recorded lots in the square or squares depicted.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may establish, by rulemaking, fees to be paid by the initiator of a proposal to designate an official name of an alley or street, or portion thereof, to recoup costs associated with satisfying the requirements of this section, including obtaining consideration of the proposal by the Council and implementation of the proposal by the Mayor; provided, that fees shall not be assessed pursuant to this subsection on an initiator that is a governmental entity, including an Advisory Neighborhood Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>If there is no initiator within the meaning of <cite path="§9-201.01|(4A)">§ 9-201.01(4A)</cite>, the Mayor shall discharge the responsibilities of the initiator set forth in this section; provided, that the requirements of subsection (f) of this section shall not apply and no fee shall be assessed pursuant to subsection (h) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-201" type="History" path="§421">Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-201, § 421</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-161" eff="2016-10-08" path="§2|(h)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-161" eff="2016-10-08" path="§2|(h)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§1142|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-07-20" eff="2017-07-20">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§1142|(b)">§ 1142(b) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104, July 20, 2017, 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-07-20" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" eff="2017-07-20" path="§1142|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§1142|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-10-24" eff="2017-10-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§1142|(b)">§ 1142(b) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167, Oct. 24, 2017, 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-10-24" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" eff="2017-10-24" path="§1142|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1142|(b)|(1)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1142|(b)|(1)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1142|(b)|(2)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1142|(b)|(2)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1142|(b)|(3)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1142|(b)|(3)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1142|(b)|(3)|(C)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1142|(b)|(4)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1142|(b)|(5)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
