<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>9-204.22</num>
  <heading>Designation of official names for other public spaces.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>At least 30 days before the date of a Council hearing to consider legislation to designate an official name for a public space other than an alley or street, or portion thereof, the initiator of the proposal to designate the official name of the public space shall submit a copy of the legislation for review and comment to each Advisory Neighborhood Commission in which the public space is located.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Before the date of a Council hearing to consider legislation to designate an official name for a public space other than an alley or street, or portion thereof, the Mayor shall provide the Council with comments on the proposed designation submitted by any District agency with jurisdiction over the public space to be designated.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Before consideration by the Council, including a vote of a committee of the Council, of a bill to designate an official name for a public space other than an alley or street, or portion thereof, the Mayor shall provide the Council with a surveyor's plat showing:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The public space to be designated; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The square or squares in which the public space is located and any adjacent squares.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may establish, by rulemaking, fees to be paid by the initiator of a proposal to designate an official name of a public space to recoup costs associated with satisfying the requirements of this section, including obtaining consideration of the proposal by the Council and implementation of the proposal by the Mayor; provided, that fees shall not be assessed pursuant to this subsection on an initiator that is a governmental entity, including an Advisory Neighborhood Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If there is no initiator within the meaning of <cite path="§9-201.01|(4A)">§ 9-201.01(4A)</cite>, the Mayor shall discharge the responsibilities of the initiator set forth in this section; provided, that no fee shall be assessed pursuant to subsection (d) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-201" type="History" path="§422">Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-201, § 422</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-161" eff="2016-10-08" path="§2|(h)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-161" eff="2016-10-08" path="§2|(h)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§1142|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-07-20" eff="2017-07-20">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§1142|(c)">§ 1142(c) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104, July 20, 2017, 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-07-20" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" eff="2017-07-20" path="§1142|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§1142|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-10-24" eff="2017-10-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§1142|(c)">§ 1142(c) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167, Oct. 24, 2017, 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-10-24" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" eff="2017-10-24" path="§1142|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1142|(c)|(1)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1142|(c)|(1)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1142|(c)|(1)|(C)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1142|(c)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1142|(c)|(3)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
