<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>9-201.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this chapter the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Alley” means any public alley, as recorded in the records of the Office of the Surveyor, from its intersection with a street or another alley to its next intersection with a street or alley, or where it dead-ends.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Council” means the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2A)</num>
      <text>“DDOT” means the District Department of Transportation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“District” means the District of Columbia government.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>“Highway plan” means the plan of the permanent system of highways developed pursuant to <cite path="§9-103.01">§ 9-103.01</cite> et seq.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4A)</num>
      <text>"Initiator" means the individual or entity that makes a request to the Mayor or a Councilmember to sponsor legislation proposing the designation of an official or symbolic name of an alley or street, or portion thereof, or an official name of a public space other than an alley or street, or portion thereof, and shall not include the Mayor, the Council, or any Councilmember.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>“Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia, or the Mayor’s designated representative.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5A)</num>
      <text>"Official name" means the legal designation of an alley or street, or portion thereof, for use in a mailing address and other official purposes.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5B)</num>
      <text>"Other public space" means a public space other than an alley or street.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>“Owner” means the owner(s) of record as shown on the records in the Department of Finance and Revenue.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>“Street” means any public right-of-way, recorded as a street, road, or highway in the records of the Office of the Surveyor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>“Surveyor” means the Surveyor of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Symbolic name" means a ceremonial name given to an alley or street, or portion thereof, or other public space that is in addition and subordinate to its official name.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-201" type="History" path="§101">Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-201, § 101, 30 DCR 148</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-110" type="History">Apr. 18, 1996, D.C. Law 11-110, § 18, 43 DCR 530</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-246" type="History">Oct. 22, 2008, D.C. Law 17-246, § 2(a), 55 DCR 9010</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Pursuant to the Office of the Chief Financial Officer’s “Notice of Public Interest” published in the April 18, 1997, issue of the District of Columbia Register ( 44 DCR 2345) the Office of Tax and Revenue assumed all of the duties and functions previously performed by the Department of Finance and Revenue, as set forth in Commissioner’s Order 69-96, dated March 7, 1969. This action was made effective January 22, 1997, nunc pro tunc.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-246">D.C. Law 17-246</cite> added par. (2A).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-411.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Surveyor of the District of Columbia, duties, see <cite path="§1-1301">§ 1-1301</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-161" eff="2016-10-08" path="§2|(a)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-161" eff="2016-10-08" path="§2|(a)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§1142|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-07-20" eff="2017-07-20">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§1142|(a)">§ 1142(a) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104, July 20, 2017, 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-07-20" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" eff="2017-07-20" path="§1142|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§1142|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-10-24" eff="2017-10-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§1142|(a)">§ 1142(a) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167, Oct. 24, 2017, 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-10-24" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" eff="2017-10-24" path="§1142|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1142|(a)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
