<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-132.04</num>
  <heading>Coordination of school security efforts between DCPS and MPD.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>By October 1, 2020, DCPS and MPD shall enter into a MOA for the purpose of coordinating the agencies' respective security obligations at DCPS schools. The MOA shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Reflect DCPS's role as the administrator of any security-related contract;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Include provisions for effectuating the transfer of any personnel, property, funds, or records necessary to transfer responsibility for any existing security-related contract from MPD to DCPS;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Delineate lines of authority, supervision, and communication between MPD and DCPS, including how school resource officers deployed at each school will provide security in coordination with the school's principal and school security personnel; provided, that during emergencies, incident command shall be consistent with the District of Columbia response plan, as defined by <cite path="§7-2301|(1A)">§ 7-2301(1A)</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Include a process for resolving disagreements between DCPS and MPD at all levels; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Provide for MPD advice and consultation on DCPS school building security and emergency operations plans.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-350" type="History" path="§104">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-350, § 104, 52 DCR 2005</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5 of School Safety and Security Contracting Procedures Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-3, January 19, 2005,  52 DCR 2675).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5 of School Safety and Security Contracting Procedures Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-596, November 30, 2004,  51 DCR 11219).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5 of Metropolitan Police Department School Safety and Security Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-496, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8797).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 5 of School Safety and Security Contracting Procedures Temporary Amendment Act of 2004 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-318">D.C. Law 15-318</cite>, April 8, 2005, law notification  52 DCR 4707).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§5-132.06">§ 5-132.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="§4102|(e)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
