<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>5-1404</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section has been amended by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
      </text>
  <heading>Former duties of coroner; oaths; teaching; other duties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The CME shall be responsible for all the medical functions formerly performed by the coroner in the District consistent with the provisions of this chapter. The CME and such other medical examiners as may be appointed may administer oaths and affirmations and take affidavits in connection with the performance of their duties.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>The CME may provide pathology and toxicology services to other District government agencies, non-District government agencies, and private entities, and may establish fees or require the payment of costs for the provision of such services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The CME, and OCME employees authorized by the CME, may teach post-secondary, medical, and law school classes, conduct special classes for government personnel, conduct research, and engage in other activities related to their work.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The CME shall inform the Registrar of Vital Records of all deaths of children 18 years of age or younger as soon as practicable, but in any event, within 5 business days.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The CME, or the CME's designee, shall attend all reviews of deaths by District government fatality review committees and fatality review boards. The CME shall coordinate with such committees and boards in their investigations of deaths.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History" path="§2905">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 2905, 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 4619(a), 48 DCR 6981</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 19(a) of Child Fatality Review Committee Establishment Legislative Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-82, July 9, 2001,  48 DCR 6355).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 19(a) of Child Fatality Review Committee Establishment Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-40, April 25, 2001,  48 DCR 5917).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2905 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 19(a) of Child Fatality Review Committee Establishment Temporary Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-20">D.C. Law 14-20</cite>, September 6, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 9090).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-28">D.C. Law 14-28</cite> added subsecs. (c) and (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 11-2303.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§3072|(d)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§3072|(d)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§3072|(d)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§3072|(d)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§3072|(d)|(4)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§3072|(d)|(5)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§3072|(d)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-08-23" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§3072|(d)">§ 3072(d) of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
