<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-1501.06a</num>
  <heading>Department Laboratory Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Department of Forensic Sciences Laboratory Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Director in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Revenue from the following sources shall be deposited in the Fund:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Annual revenue transferred from the United States Department of Homeland Security for the BioWatch program; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Fees collected for forensic science services provided by the Department.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall only be used to fund the expenses of the Department's laboratories, including the funding of forensic science services, materials, non-grant funded research, equipment, laboratory staff, and trainings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-18" type="History" path="§7a">Aug. 17, 2011, D.C. Law 19-18, § 7a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§3002|(a)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§3002|(a)" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2017-12-13" eff="2017-12-13">
          For temporary (90-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§3002|(a)">§ 3002(a) of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017, effective July 20, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104; 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.
          </annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§3002|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§3002|(a)" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2017-12-13" eff="2017-12-13">
          For temporary (90-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§3002|(a)">§ 3002(a) of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017, effective October 24, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167; 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.
          </annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
