<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-655.01</num>
  <heading>Physical examinations; maintaining eligibility.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In order to be eligible to make a claim under <cite path="5|6A">this chapter</cite> that relies on a presumption created by <cite path="5|6A|II">this subchapter</cite>, a member shall, in addition to meeting any other requirements as required by <cite path="5|6A|II">this subchapter</cite> or rules issued pursuant to <cite path="§5-655.03">§ 5-655.03</cite>, have undergone a pre-employment physical examination and complied with any subsequent physical examination requirements, such as annual physical examinations, that are, or were during the period of covered service, applicable to all members.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In order to be eligible to make a claim under <cite path="5|6A">this chapter</cite> that relies on a presumption created by <cite path="5|6A|II">this subchapter</cite>, an EMS employee shall, in addition to meeting any other requirements as required by <cite path="5|6A">this chapter</cite> or rules issued pursuant to <cite path="§5-655.03">§ 5-655.03</cite>, have undergone a pre-employment physical examination and complied with any subsequent physical examination requirements, such as annual physical examinations, that are, or were during the period of covered service, applicable to all EMS employees.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For any member or EMS employee hired after May 1, 2013, the District may require additional, appropriate laboratory and other diagnostic studies to be included as part of the pre-employment physical examination; provided, that any such requirements shall be applicable to all members or EMS employees.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2004-09-30" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" eff="2004-09-30" path="VI" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2004-09-30" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" eff="2004-09-30" path="§655a" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2013-05-01" doc="D.C. Law 19-311" eff="2013-05-01" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3052|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
