<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>21-2231.03</num>
  <heading>Hospital discharge plan.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>As soon as practicable before the patient's discharge, the hospital shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Consult with the lay caregiver and the patient or authorized representative regarding the lay caregiver's capabilities and limitations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide a copy of the discharge plan to the lay caregiver;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Consult with, and provide instruction to, the lay caregiver regarding the patient's discharge plan; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Provide contact information for any health care, community resources, and long-term care services and supports necessary to carry out the patient's discharge plan.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>At a minimum, the discharge plan described in subsection (a) of this section shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name and contact information of the lay caregiver;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A description of all after-care tasks necessary to maintain the patient's ability to reside in the patient's residence; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Contact information for any health care, community resources, and long-term care services and supports necessary to carry out the patient's discharge plan.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At a minimum, the instruction to the lay caregiver described in subsection (a) of this section shall include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An opportunity for a demonstration at the hospital of the after-care tasks; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An opportunity for the lay caregiver and the patient to ask questions and receive answers to questions about the after-care tasks; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The instruction provided shall be documented in the patient's medical record and shall include, at minimum, the date, time, and contents of the instruction.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-07-01" doc="D.C. Law 21-132" eff="2016-07-01" path="ยง2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
