<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>21-2221.02</num>
  <heading>Creation of a MOST Form.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 9 months after February 27, 2016, DOH shall develop, and make available online, a MOST Form and instructions for health care institutions, health care professionals, and patients and authorized representatives completing and using the MOST Form.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>DOH shall evaluate the design and use of a MOST Form, including compliance or non-compliance with a MOST Form by EMS personnel and health care professionals, at least every 3 years.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>DOH shall require, and provide for, ongoing training of health care professionals and EMS personnel about best practices regarding the use of a MOST Form.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The training shall include, at a minimum:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The importance of talking to each patient or the patient's authorized representative about the patient's prognosis, the likely course of illness, and personal goals of care;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Methods for presenting choices for care that elicit information concerning each patient's preferences and respecting those preferences without directing patients toward a particular care option;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The importance of fully informing patients about the benefits and risks of an immediately effective MOST Form;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Awareness of factors that may affect the use of a MOST Form, including race, ethnicity, age, gender, socioeconomic position, immigrant status, sexual orientation, language disability, homelessness, mental illness, and geographic area of residence; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Procedures for properly completing and effectuating a MOST Form.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-72" type="History">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-72, § 2(d), 63 DCR 208</annotation>
    <annotation type="Applicability">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-72">D.C. Law 21-72</cite>: Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-72">D.C. Law 21-72</cite> provided (a) that the act shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan; (b) that the Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification; and (c) that the Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register and that the date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of the act.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-02-27" doc="D.C. Law 21-72" eff="2016-02-27" path="§2|(d)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§7011" codified:display="Note" app="2017-07-20" eff="2017-07-20">For temporary (90 days) repeal of § 4 of D.C. Law 21-72, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§7011">§ 7011 of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104, July 20, 2017, 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-07-20" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" eff="2017-07-20" path="§7011" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§7011" codified:display="Note" app="2017-10-24" eff="2017-10-24">For temporary (90 days) repeal of § 4 of D.C. Law 21-72, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§7011">§ 7011 of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167, Oct. 24, 2017, 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-10-24" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" eff="2017-10-24" path="§7011" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§7011" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2017-12-13" eff="2017-12-13"><cite doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§7011">Section 7011 of D.C. Law 22-33</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-72" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 21-72</cite>. Therefore the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-72">D.C. Law 21-72</cite> has been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§7011" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
