<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>21-2512</num>
  <heading>Disclosure of contents of electronic communications held in trust when trustee not original user.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise ordered by the Superior Court, directed by the user, or provided in a trust, a custodian shall disclose to a trustee that is not an original user of an account the content of an electronic communication sent or received by an original or successor user and carried, maintained, processed, received, or stored by the custodian in the account of the trust if the trustee gives the custodian:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A written request for disclosure in physical or electronic form;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A certified copy of the trust instrument, or a certification of the trust pursuant to<cite path="§19-1310.13"> § 19-1310.13</cite> that includes consent to disclosure of the content of electronic communications to the trustee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A certification by the trustee, under penalty of perjury, that the trust exists, and the trustee is a currently acting trustee of the trust; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If requested by the custodian:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A number, username, address, or other unique subscriber or account identifier assigned by the custodian to identify the trust's account; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Evidence linking the account to the trust.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-189" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-189" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
