<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>21-2516</num>
  <heading>Custodian compliance and immunity.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Not later than 60 days after receipt of the information required under §§ <cite path="§21-2507">21-2507</cite> through <cite path="§21-2514">21-2514</cite>, a custodian shall comply with a request under <cite path="21|25">this chapter</cite> from a fiduciary or designated recipient to disclose digital assets or terminate an account. If the custodian fails to comply, the fiduciary or designated recipient may apply to the Superior Court for an order directing compliance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An order under subsection (a) of this section directing compliance must contain a finding that compliance is not in violation of 18 U.S.C. § 2702.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Unless a custodian has been notified that a user is deceased, the custodian shall notify the user that a request for disclosure or to terminate an account was made under <cite path="21|25">this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A custodian may deny a request under <cite path="21|25">this chapter</cite> from a fiduciary or designated recipient for disclosure of digital assets or to terminate an account if the custodian is aware of any lawful access to the account following the receipt of the fiduciary's request.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text><cite path="21|25">This chapter</cite> does not limit a custodian's ability to obtain or require a fiduciary or designated recipient requesting disclosure or termination under <cite path="21|25">this chapter</cite> to obtain a court order that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Specifies that an account belongs to the protected individual or principal;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Specifies that there is sufficient consent from the protected individual or principal to support the requested disclosure; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Contains a finding required by law other than <cite path="21|25">this chapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A custodian and its officers, employees, and agents are immune from liability for an act or omission done in good faith in compliance with <cite path="21|25">this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-189" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-189" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
