<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>21-2514</num>
  <heading>Disclosure of digital assets to conservator of protected individual.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After an opportunity for a hearing under <cite path="§21-2054">§ 21-2054</cite>, the Superior Court may grant a conservator access to the digital assets of a protected individual.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise ordered by the Superior Court or directed by the user, a custodian shall disclose to a conservator the catalogue of electronic communications sent or received by a protected individual and any digital assets, other than the content of electronic communications, in which the protected individual has a right or interest if the conservator gives the custodian:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A written request for disclosure in physical or electronic form;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A certified copy of the court order that gives the conservator authority over the digital assets of the protected individual; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If requested by the custodian:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A number, username, address, or other unique subscriber or account identifier assigned by the custodian to identify the account of the protected individual; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Evidence linking the account to the protected individual.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A conservator with general authority to manage the assets of a protected individual may request a custodian of the digital assets of the protected individual to suspend or terminate an account of the protected individual for good cause. A request made under this section shall be accompanied by a certified copy of the court order giving the conservator authority over the protected individual's property.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-189" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-189" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
