<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>21-2221.05</num>
  <heading>Completion and execution of the MOST Form.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A patient shall be given the option to complete a MOST Form, but no patient shall be required to complete or execute a MOST Form.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Only an authorized health care professional treating a patient may complete a MOST Form for that patient.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The authorized health care professional shall complete the MOST Form in accordance with the instructions of the patient or the patient's authorized representative.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Only the following persons may execute a MOST Form:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Any patient who is 18 years of age or older, on behalf of himself or herself; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An authorized representative.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Execution of a MOST Form shall be evidenced by the patient's or the authorized representative's signature.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The MOST Form shall be reviewed by an authorized health care professional with the patient or with the patient's authorized representative at least once per year and:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Whenever the patient's condition changes significantly; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>At the patient's or the patient's authorized representative's request.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a patient with a MOST Form is transferred from one health care institution to another, the health care institution transferring the patient shall communicate the existence of the MOST Form to the receiving health care institution before the transfer.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The MOST Form shall accompany the patient to the receiving health care institution and remain in effect.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Within 72 hours after a patient is transferred, the MOST Form shall be reviewed by an authorized health care professional and the patient, provided that the patient is not incapacitated, or the patient's authorized representative, if present.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-72" type="History">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-72, § 2(d), 63 DCR 208</annotation>
    <annotation type="Applicability">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-72">D.C. Law 21-72</cite>: Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-72">D.C. Law 21-72</cite> provided (a) that the act shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan; (b) that the Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification; and (c) that the Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register and that the date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of the act.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-02-27" doc="D.C. Law 21-72" eff="2016-02-27" path="§2|(d)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§7011" codified:display="Note" app="2017-07-20" eff="2017-07-20">For temporary (90 days) repeal of § 4 of D.C. Law 21-72, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§7011">§ 7011 of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104, July 20, 2017, 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-07-20" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" eff="2017-07-20" path="§7011" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§7011" codified:display="Note" app="2017-10-24" eff="2017-10-24">For temporary (90 days) repeal of § 4 of D.C. Law 21-72, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§7011">§ 7011 of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167, Oct. 24, 2017, 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-10-24" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" eff="2017-10-24" path="§7011" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§7011" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2017-12-13" eff="2017-12-13"><cite doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§7011">Section 7011 of D.C. Law 22-33</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-72" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 21-72</cite>. Therefore the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-72">D.C. Law 21-72</cite> has been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§7011" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
