<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>21-2231.02</num>
  <heading>Lay caregiver designation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A hospital shall provide each patient or authorized representative an opportunity to designate a lay caregiver as soon as practicable following the patient's inpatient admission into a hospital and before the patient's discharge.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the patient or authorized representative designates an individual as a lay caregiver, the hospital shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Provide notice to the lay caregiver as soon as practicable following the designation and before the patient's discharge;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Promptly request the written consent of the patient or authorized representative to release medical information to the patient's lay caregiver in accordance with the hospital's procedures for releasing personal health information and in compliance with all federal and District laws, including the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, approved August 21, 1996 (Pub. L. No. 104-191; 110 Stat. 1936);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Record the patient's or authorized representative's designation of the lay caregiver, the relationship of the lay caregiver to the patient, and the name, telephone number, and address of the lay caregiver in the patient's medical record; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Notify the lay caregiver of the patient's discharge to the patient's residence as soon as practicable; provided, that if the hospital is unable to contact the lay caregiver, the hospital shall document that in the patient's medical record as soon as practicable.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a patient or authorized representative fails to authorize the release of medical information to the lay caregiver under paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection, the hospital is deemed to have met the requirements of the subchapter and no further action is needed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A patient or authorized representative may elect to change the designation of a  lay caregiver at any time before the patient's discharge; provided, that if a change is made, the hospital shall record that change in the patient's medical record as soon as practicable.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The designation of a lay caregiver by the patient or authorized representative does not obligate the lay caregiver to accept the designation or provide after-care.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A hospital is not obligated to determine the ability of a lay caregiver to understand or perform after-care tasks.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-07-01" doc="D.C. Law 21-132" eff="2016-07-01" path="ยง2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
