<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>21-2221.07</num>
  <heading>Compliance with a MOST Form.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If an EMS personnel or health care professional encounters a person who is in possession of a MOST Form, the EMS personnel or health care professional shall determine whether the person is the subject of the MOST Form and whether the MOST Form has been revoked.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If there is uncertainty as to whether the MOST Form has been revoked, the EMS personnel or health care professional shall act as if there were no MOST Form and resuscitate the patient.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If an EMS personnel or health care professional encounters a patient in an emergency medical circumstance with a MOST Form that is unreadable, the EMS personnel or health care professional shall proceed as if there were no MOST Form.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the EMS personnel does not resuscitate the patient on the basis of applicable treatment instructions on a MOST Form, EMS personnel shall record the do-not-resuscitate response in the run report and report the do-not-resuscitate response to DOH within 5 business days after the incident.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>On a biannual basis, DOH shall provide the Mayor with data on do-not-resuscitate responses.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-72" type="History">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-72, § 2(d), 63 DCR 208</annotation>
    <annotation type="Applicability">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-72">D.C. Law 21-72</cite>: Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-72">D.C. Law 21-72</cite> provided (a) that the act shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan; (b) that the Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification; and (c) that the Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register and that the date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of the act.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-02-27" doc="D.C. Law 21-72" eff="2016-02-27" path="§2|(d)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§7011" codified:display="Note" app="2017-07-20" eff="2017-07-20">For temporary (90 days) repeal of § 4 of D.C. Law 21-72, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§7011">§ 7011 of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104, July 20, 2017, 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-07-20" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" eff="2017-07-20" path="§7011" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§7011" codified:display="Note" app="2017-10-24" eff="2017-10-24">For temporary (90 days) repeal of § 4 of D.C. Law 21-72, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§7011">§ 7011 of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167, Oct. 24, 2017, 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-10-24" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" eff="2017-10-24" path="§7011" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§7011" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2017-12-13" eff="2017-12-13"><cite doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§7011">Section 7011 of D.C. Law 22-33</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-72" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 21-72</cite>. Therefore the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-72">D.C. Law 21-72</cite> has been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§7011" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
