<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>21-2510</num>
  <heading>Disclosure of other digital assets of principal.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise ordered by the Superior Court, directed by the principal, or provided by a power of attorney, a custodian shall disclose to an agent with specific authority over digital assets or general authority to act on behalf of a principal a catalogue of electronic communications sent or received by the principal and digital assets, other than the content of electronic communications, of the principal if the agent gives the custodian:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A written request for disclosure in physical or electronic form;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An original or a copy of the power of attorney that gives the agent specific authority over digital assets or general authority to act on behalf of the principal;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A certification by the agent, under penalty of perjury, that the power of attorney is in effect; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If requested by the custodian:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A number, username, address, or other unique subscriber or account identifier assigned by the custodian to identify the principal's account; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Evidence linking the account to the principal.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-189" eff="2021-03-16" path="ยง2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-189" eff="2021-03-16" path="ยง2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
