<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>21-2047.03</num>
  <heading>Duty of guardian to inform certain relatives about the health status and residence of a ward.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>During a period for which a public health emergency has been declared pursuant to <cite path="§7-2304.01">[§ 7-2304.01]</cite>, the guardian of a ward shall inform at least one relative of the ward, if one exists pursuant to subsection (d) of this section, as soon as practicable but no later than within 48 hours, of the following events:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The ward dies;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The ward is admitted to a medical facility;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The ward is transferred to acute care;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The ward is placed on a ventilator;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The residence of the ward or the location where the ward lives has changed; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The ward is staying at a location other than the residence of the ward for a period that exceeds 7 consecutive days.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In the case of the death of the ward, the guardian shall inform at least one relative of the ward, if one exists, pursuant to subsection (d) of this section, of any funeral arrangements and the location of the final resting place of the ward at least 72 hours before the funeral.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to exempt a guardian from complying with federal or District privacy laws to which they are otherwise subject.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This section shall apply only to the relative of a ward:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Against whom a protective order is not in effect to protect the ward;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Who has not been found by a court or other state agency to have abused, neglected, or exploited the ward; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Who has elected in writing to receive a notice about the ward.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Relative" means a spouse, parent, sibling, child, or domestic partner of the ward.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Domestic partner" shall have the same meaning as in <cite path="§32-701|(3)">[§ 32-701(3)]</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-405" eff="2020-08-19" path="§505|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
