<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1001.05a</num>
  <heading>Advisory opinions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>On its own initiative, or upon receiving a request from a person listed below and within a reasonable time after its receipt, the Board shall provide an advisory opinion regarding compliance with <cite path="1|10|I">this subchapter</cite>:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An elected official or a candidate to be an elected official;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Any person required to or who reasonably anticipates being required to submit filings to the Board under <cite path="1|10|I">this subchapter</cite> in connection with any election; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any other person under the jurisdiction of the Board.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Board shall publish a concise statement of each request for an advisory opinion, without identifying the person seeking the opinion, in the District of Columbia Register within 20 days after its receipt by the Board. Comments upon the requested opinion shall be received by the Board for a period of at least 15 days following publication of the concise statement.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Board may waive the requirements of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, following a finding that the issuance of the advisory opinion constitutes an emergency necessary for the immediate preservation of the public peace, health, safety, welfare, or trust.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Advisory opinions shall be published in the District of Columbia Register within 30 days after their issuance; provided, that the identity of a person requesting an advisory opinion shall not be disclosed in the District of Columbia Register without his or her prior consent in writing. When issued according to rules of the Board, an advisory opinion shall be deemed to be an order of the Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>There shall be a rebuttable presumption that a transaction or activity undertaken by a person in reliance on an advisory opinion from the Board is lawful if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The person requested the advisory opinion;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The facts on which the opinion is based are full and accurate, to the best knowledge of the person; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The person, in good faith, substantially complies with any recommendations in the advisory opinion.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 84-1-ch862" path="§5a">Aug. 12, 1955, 69 Stat. 700, ch. 862, § 5a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-03-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" eff="2019-03-13" path="§5|(d)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§5|(d)" codified:display="Note" app="2019-03-13" eff="2019-03-13">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="">D.C. Law 22-250</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§10">§ 10 of D.C. Law 22-250</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§5|(d)">§ 5(d) of D.C. Law 22-250</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-03-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" eff="2019-03-13" path="§5|(d)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§10|(a)" type="Applicability" history="false" display-template="" app="2019-03-13" eff="2019-03-13">
                Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§10">D.C. Law 22-250: § 10 of D.C. Law 22-250</cite>, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-404" path="§1104">§ 1104 of D.C. Act 23-404</cite>, repealed the requirement that <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§5|(d)">§ 5(d) of D.C. Law 22-250</cite> would be subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§5|(d)">§ 5(d) of D.C. Law 22-250</cite> has been implemented.
              </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-03-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" eff="2019-03-13" path="§10|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§1043|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§1104" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
