<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1163.12a</num>
  <heading>Non-contribution accounts.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A political action committee shall not make an independent expenditure unless it establishes a non-contribution account for the purpose of making such independent expenditures.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A political action committee must notify the Campaign Finance Board within 10 days after establishing a non-contribution account.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A political action committee that establishes a non-contribution account shall ensure that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The non-contribution account remains segregated from any accounts of the political action committee that are used to make contributions to candidates, political committees, political action committees, or political parties;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No contribution to the political action committee is deposited in the non-contribution account unless the contributor has specifically designated the contribution for the purpose of making an independent expenditure;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Contributions by the political action committee are not made from the non-contribution account; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The non-contribution account pays a proportional share, as determined by the Director of Campaign Finance, of the political action committee's administrative expenses.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a political action committee has established a non-contribution account, it must, in any reports it files pursuant to <cite path="§1-1163.09">§ 1-1163.09</cite>, identify any receipts that have been allocated to that account.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124" type="History" path="§312a">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 312a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-03-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" eff="2019-03-13" path="§6|(r)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§6|(r)" codified:display="Note" app="2019-03-13" eff="2019-03-13">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="">D.C. Law 22-250</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§10">§ 10 of D.C. Law 22-250</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§6|(r)">§ 6(r) of D.C. Law 22-250</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-03-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" eff="2019-03-13" path="§6|(r)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§1042|(d)" codified:display="Note" app="2019-07-22" eff="2019-07-22">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§1042|(d)">§ 1042(d) of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019, 66 DCR 8497)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§1042|(d)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§1042|(d)" codified:display="Note" app="2019-09-04" eff="2019-09-04">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§1042|(d)">§ 1042(d) of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019, 66 DCR 11964)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§1042|(d)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
