<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1163.15</num>
  <heading>Identification of political advertising.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A candidate, political committee, or political action committee shall identify its political advertising by the words "paid for by", followed by the name and address of the candidate or committee and the name of the committee's treasurer, as applicable.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An independent expenditure committee or person making an independent expenditure shall identify its political advertising by the words "paid for by", followed by the name and address of the independent expenditure committee and the name of the committee's treasurer, or the name and address of the person making the independent expenditure. The political advertising shall also include a written or oral statement of the words "Top Five Contributors", followed by a list of the 5 largest contributors over the amount of $5,000, whose contributions were made for the purpose of making an independent expenditure, to the independent expenditure committee or person making the independent expenditure, if applicable, during the 12-month period before the date of the political advertising.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A political committee, political action committee, independent expenditure committee, or person making an independent expenditure shall include a statement on the face or front page, if printed, or an oral statement, if audiovisual, of all political advertising soliciting contributions the following notice: "A copy of our report is filed with the Director of Campaign Finance."</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The identifications required by this section need not be included on items the size of which makes the inclusion of such identifications impractical.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "political advertising" includes newspaper and magazine advertising; posters; circulars and mailers; billboards; handbills; bumper stickers; sample ballots; initiative, referendum, or recall petitions; radio or television advertisements; paid telephone calls and text messaging; digital media advertisements; and other printed and digital materials produced by the persons in this subsection and intended to support or oppose:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A candidate or group of candidates; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any initiative, referendum, or recall measure.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124" type="History" path="§315">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 315, 59 DCR 1862</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-79" type="History">Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-79, § 2(l), 61 DCR 153</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-79">D.C. Law 20-79</cite> added (c).</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§7009" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="2016-10-08" eff="2016-10-08"><cite doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§7009">Section 7009 of D.C. Law 21-160</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-79" path="§3">§ 3 of D.C. Law 20-79</cite>. Therefore the changes made to this section by D.C. Law 20-79 have been given effect.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§7009" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-03-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" eff="2019-03-13" path="§10|(a)|(1)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-03-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" eff="2019-03-13" path="§6|(t)" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§6|(t)" codified:display="Note" app="2019-03-13" eff="2019-03-13">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="">D.C. Law 22-250</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§10">§ 10 of D.C. Law 22-250</cite> provided that the change made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§6|(t)">§ 6(t) of D.C. Law 22-250</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§1042|(f)" codified:display="Note" app="2019-07-22" eff="2019-07-22">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§1042|(f)">§ 1042(f) of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019, 66 DCR 8497)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§1042|(f)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§1042|(f)" codified:display="Note" app="2019-09-04" eff="2019-09-04">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§1042|(f)">§ 1042(f) of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019, 66 DCR 11964)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§1042|(f)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§1042|(f)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§1043|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
