<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-1162.06</num>
  <heading>Professional staff.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Ethics Board shall select, employ, and fix the compensation for a Director of Government Ethics and such staff as the Ethics Board considers necessary, subject to the pay limitations of <cite path="§1-611.16">§ 1-611.16</cite>. The Director of Government Ethics shall serve at the pleasure of the Ethics Board. The Ethics Board shall provide to the Director of Government Ethics employees to carry out the powers and duties of the Director of Government Ethics. Employees assigned to the Director of Government Ethics, while so assigned, shall be under the direction and control of the Director of Government Ethics and may not be reassigned without the concurrence of the Director of Government Ethics.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Director of Government Ethics shall be a District resident and failure to maintain District residency shall result in forfeiture of the position.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The staff of the Ethics Board shall be subject to the Code of Conduct, and the Ethics Board shall promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to ensure that all persons responsible for the proper administration of this subchapter maintain a position of strict impartiality and refrain from any activity that would imply support or opposition to an Ethics Board investigation.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124" type="History" path="§206">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 206, 59 DCR 1862</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§1-1161.01">§ 1-1161.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§1083|(g)" codified:display="Note" app="2018-07-30" eff="2018-07-30">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§1083|(g)">§ 1083(g) of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-434, July 30, 2018, 65 DCR 8200)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="§1083|(g)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§1083|(g)" codified:display="Note" app="2018-10-03" eff="2018-10-03">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§1083|(g)">§ 1083(g) of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-458, Oct. 3, 2018, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" eff="2018-10-03" path="§1083|(g)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
