<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-1162.06</num>
  <heading>Professional staff.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Board shall select, employ, and fix the compensation for a Director of Government Ethics, a Director of Open Government, and such staff as the Board considers necessary, subject to the pay limitations of <cite path="§1-611.16">§ 1-611.16</cite>.  The Director of Government Ethics and the Director of Open Government shall serve at the pleasure of the Board.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other law, an employee assigned to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Office of Government Ethics shall be under the Director of Government Ethics' direction and control and may not be transferred to the Office of Open Government without the concurrence of the Director of Government Ethics; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Office of Open Government shall be under the Director of Open Government's direction and control and may not be transferred to the Office of Government Ethics without the concurrence of the Director of Open Government.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Director of Government Ethics and the Director of Open Government shall be District residents throughout their term and failure to maintain District residency shall result in forfeiture of the position.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The staff of the Board shall be subject to the Code of Conduct, and the Board shall promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to ensure that all persons responsible for the proper administration of this subchapter maintain a position of strict impartiality and refrain from any activity that would imply support or opposition to a Board investigation.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124" type="History" path="§206">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 206, 59 DCR 1862</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§1-1161.01">§ 1-1161.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§1083|(g)" codified:display="Note" app="2018-07-30" eff="2018-07-30">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§1083|(g)">§ 1083(g) of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-434, July 30, 2018, 65 DCR 8200)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="§1083|(g)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§1083|(g)" codified:display="Note" app="2018-10-03" eff="2018-10-03">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§1083|(g)">§ 1083(g) of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-458, Oct. 3, 2018, 65 DCR 11212)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" eff="2018-10-03" path="§1083|(g)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§1083|(g)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§1083|(g)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§1083|(g)|(3)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§1083|(g)|(3)|(B)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
