<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1163.02a</num>
  <heading>Composition; term; qualifications; removal.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Campaign Finance Board shall consist of 5 members, no more than 3 of whom shall be of the same political party, appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Members shall be appointed to serve for terms of 6 years, except the members first appointed. Of the members first appointed, one member shall be appointed to serve for a 2-year term, 2 members shall be appointed to serve a 4-year term, and 2 members shall be appointed to serve a 6-year term, as designated by the Mayor. The terms of the 5 initial members shall begin on October 1, 2019.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall designate the Chairperson of the Campaign Finance Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Unless the unexpired term is less than 6 months, any person appointed to fill a vacancy on the Campaign Finance Board shall be appointed only for the unexpired term of the member whose vacancy he or she is filling.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A member may be reappointed, and, if not reappointed, notwithstanding <cite path="§1-523.01|(c)">§ 1-523.01(c)</cite>, the member may serve until the member's successor has been appointed and approved.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>When appointing a member of the Campaign Finance Board, the Mayor and Council shall consider whether the individual possesses particular knowledge, training, or experience in campaign finance law or administration.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A person shall not be a member of the Campaign Finance Board unless the person:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is a duly-registered District voter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has resided in the District continuously for the 3-year period preceding the day the person is appointed; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Holds no other office or employment in the District government.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>No person, while a member of the Campaign Finance Board, shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Campaign for any public office;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Serve in a leadership capacity or hold any office in a political party or political committee, political action committee, or independent expenditure committee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Participate in any political campaign in any District election, including by:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Making speeches for or publicly supporting or opposing a District candidate, political party, political committee, political action committee, independent expenditure committee, recall, initiative, or referendum;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Fundraising for or contributing to a District candidate, political party, political committee, political action committee, independent expenditure committee, recall, initiative, or referendum; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Attending or purchasing a ticket for a dinner or other event sponsored by or supporting or opposing a District candidate, political party, political committee, political action committee, independent expenditure committee, recall, initiative, or referendum;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Be a lobbyist;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Be an officer, director, or employee of an organization receiving District funds who has managerial or discretionary responsibilities with respect to those funds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Use their status as a member to directly or indirectly attempt to influence any decision of the District government relating to any action that is not within the Board's purview; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Be convicted of having committed an election- or campaign finance-related felony in the District of Columbia; or if the crime is committed elsewhere, conviction of such offense as would be an election- or campaign finance-related felony in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Members of the Campaign Finance Board, including the Chairperson, shall not receive compensation for their service on the Campaign Finance Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>A member may be removed for good cause, including engaging in any activity prohibited by subsection (f) or (g) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Campaign Finance Board shall hold regular monthly meetings in accordance with a schedule to be established by the Campaign Finance Board. Additional meetings may be called as needed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Campaign Finance Board shall provide notice of meetings and shall conduct its meetings in compliance with the <cite path="2|5|IV">Open Meetings Act</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-1163.02a" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§1-1163.02a">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="">D.C. Law 22-250</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§10">§ 10 of D.C. Law 22-250</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§6|(g)">§ 6(g) of D.C. Law 22-250</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-124" type="History" path="§302a">Apr. 27, 2012, D.C. Law 19-124, § 302a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-03-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" eff="2019-03-13" path="§6|(g)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§6|(g)" codified:display="Note" app="2019-03-13" eff="2019-03-13">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="">D.C. Law 22-250</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§10">§ 10 of D.C. Law 22-250</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§6|(g)">§ 6(g) of D.C. Law 22-250</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-03-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" eff="2019-03-13" path="§6|(g)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§10|(a)" type="Applicability" history="false" display-template="" app="2019-03-13" eff="2019-03-13">
                Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§10">D.C. Law 22-250: § 10 of D.C. Law 22-250</cite>, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-404" path="§1104">§ 1104 of D.C. Act 23-404</cite>, repealed the requirement that <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§6|(g)">§ 6(g) of D.C. Law 22-250</cite> would be subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§6|(g)">§ 6(g) of D.C. Law 22-250</cite> has been implemented.
                </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-03-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" eff="2019-03-13" path="§10|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§1043|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§1103|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§1104" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
