<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1231.13</num>
  <heading>Foreign notarial act.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a notarial act is performed under authority and in the jurisdiction of a foreign state or constituent unit of the foreign state or is performed under the authority of a multinational or international governmental organization, the notarial act shall have the same effect under the law of the District as if performed by a notarial officer of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the title of office and indication of authority to perform notarial acts in a foreign state appears in a digest of foreign law or in a list customarily used as a source for that information, the authority of an officer with that title to perform notarial acts shall be conclusively established.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The signature and official stamp of an individual holding an office described in subsection (b) shall be prima facie evidence that the signature is genuine and the individual holds the designated title.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An apostille in the form prescribed by the Hague Convention of October 5, 1961, and issued by a foreign state party to the Hague Convention conclusively shall establish that the signature of the notarial officer is genuine and that the officer holds the indicated office.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A consular authentication issued by an individual designated by the United States Department of State as a notarizing officer for performing notarial acts overseas and attached to the record with respect to which the notarial act is performed conclusively shall establish that the signature of the notarial officer is genuine and that the officer holds the indicated office.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-12-04" doc="D.C. Law 22-189" eff="2018-12-04" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-12-04" doc="D.C. Law 22-189" eff="2018-12-04" path="ยง14" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
