<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code" placeholder="Repealed">
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <num>1-1201</num>
  <heading>Appointment; representation of clients before government departments; license fee; rules.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 56-2-ch854" path="§558">Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1279, ch. 854, § 558</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 29, 1906, 34 Stat. 622, ch. 3616</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Feb. 10, 1925, 43 Stat. 821, ch. 198</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Dec. 16, 1944, 58 Stat. 810, ch. 597, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-14" type="History">June 22, 1983, D.C. Law 5-14, § 304, 30 DCR 2632</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 1072, 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21,§ 9020(b), 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 8003, 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(20) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.11">§ 1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.14|(a)">§ 1-207.14(a)</cite>), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="New Implementing Regulations">New implementing regulations: Section 302 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-14">D.C. Law 5-14</cite> also amended the Notaries Public Regulation (Reg. 73-13; 25 DCRR 3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Pursuant to the Office of the Chief Financial Officer’s “Notice of Public Interest” published in the April 18, 1997, issue of the District of Columbia Register ( 44 DCR 2345) the Office of Tax and Revenue assumed all of the duties and functions previously performed by the Department of Finance and Revenue, as set forth in Commissioner’s Order 69-96, dated March 7, 1969. This action was made effective January 22, 1997, nunc pro tunc.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 1071 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided that subtitle H of title I of the act may be cited as the “Notaries Public Authentications and License Fee Amendment Act of 2010”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 8003 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 8003 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1072 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> deleted the former last sentence of (b), which read: “All proceeds collected pursuant to this section shall be deposited into the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite>, in subsec. (b), inserted “All proceeds collected pursuant to this section shall be deposited into the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> rewrote subsec. (c), which had read as follows: “(c) The Council of the District of Columbia shall issue rules necessary to carry out the provisions of §§ <cite path="§1-1201">1-1201</cite> to <cite path="§1-1215">1-1215</cite>: Except, that the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall amend by rule from time to time the amount of any fee established pursuant to §§ <cite path="§1-1201">1-1201</cite> to <cite path="§1-1215">1-1215</cite>.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-501.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-801.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§47-2853.04">§ 47-2853.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Uniform Law: on Notarial Acts, see <cite path="§42-141">§ 42-141</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Licensing of non-health related occupations and professions, see <cite path="§47-2853.04">§ 47-2853.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-12-04" doc="D.C. Law 22-189" eff="2018-12-04" path="§34|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
