<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1231.06</num>
  <heading>Identification of individual.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A notarial officer has personal knowledge of the identity of an individual appearing before the officer if the individual is personally known to the officer through dealings sufficient to provide reasonable certainty that the individual has the identity claimed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A notarial officer has satisfactory evidence of the identity of an individual appearing before the officer if the officer can identify the individual by means of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Current government-issued identification that is:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A passport, driver's license, or government-issued nondriver identification card; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Another form of government identification issued to an individual, which contains the signature or a photograph of the individual and is satisfactory to the officer; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A verification on oath or affirmation of a credible witness personally appearing before the officer and known to the officer or whom the officer can identify based on a current passport, driver's license, or government-issued nondriver identification card.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A notarial officer may require an individual to provide additional information or identification credentials necessary to assure the officer of the identity of the individual.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-12-04" doc="D.C. Law 22-189" eff="2018-12-04" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-12-04" doc="D.C. Law 22-189" eff="2018-12-04" path="ยง7" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
