<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1231.19</num>
  <heading>Commission as notary public; endorsement as an electronic notary; qualifications; no immunity or benefit.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An individual qualified under subsection (c) of this section may apply to the Mayor for a commission as a notary public. An applicant shall comply with and provide the information required by the rules issued by the Mayor and pay the application fee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall issue rules setting an application fee; provided, that the application fee shall not be less than $75; provided further, that there is no application fee for a notary public in the service of the governments of the United States or District of Columbia whose notarial duties are confined solely to official government business.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An applicant for a commission as a notary public shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be at least 18 years of age;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be a citizen or permanent legal resident of the United States;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be a resident of or have a primary place of employment or practice in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Not be disqualified to receive a commission under <cite path="§1-1231.22">§ 1-1231.22</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Meet any other qualifications prescribed by rules issued by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Before issuance of a commission as a notary public, an applicant for the commission shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Take the oath prescribed for civil officers in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Complete a training class provided by the Mayor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>File the notary's signature and deposit an impression of the notary's official seal with the Mayor; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Indicate, on a form provided by the Mayor, the language(s) of records in which the applicant intends to perform notarial acts; provided, that the applicant shall be required to read and write in the language of any record on which the applicant performs a notarial act.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, before issuance of a commission as a notary public, the applicant shall submit to the Mayor an assurance in the form of a surety bond or its functional equivalent in the amount of $2,000, or other amount prescribed by rules issued by the Mayor. The assurance shall be issued by a surety or other entity licensed or authorized to do business in the District. The assurance shall cover acts performed during the term of the notary public's commission and shall be in the form prescribed by the Mayor. If a notary public violates law with respect to notaries public in the District, the surety or issuing entity is liable under the assurance. The surety or issuing entity shall give 30-days' notice to the Mayor before canceling the assurance. The surety or issuing entity shall notify the Mayor not later than 30 days after making a payment to a claimant under the assurance. A notary public may perform notarial acts in the District only during the period that a valid assurance is on file with the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A notary public commissioned on behalf of the government of the District of Columbia is exempt from the requirement of a surety bond under subsection (e) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Upon an applicant's compliance with this section, the Mayor shall issue a commission as a notary public to an applicant for a term of 5 years subject to removal pursuant to <cite path="§1-1231.22">§ 1-1231.22</cite>. A certificate issued by the Mayor granting this commission shall be signed by the Secretary of the District of Columbia or the Secretary's designee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>A commission to act as a notary public authorizes the notary public to perform notarial acts only within the District. The commission does not provide the notary public any immunity or benefit conferred by law of the District on public officials or employees.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>An individual who holds a commission as a notary public may apply to the Mayor for an endorsement as an electronic notary. The applicant shall comply with and provide the information required by rules issued by the Mayor and pay an application fee for such endorsement.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-1231.19" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§1-1231.19">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-189" path="">D.C. Law 22-189</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-189" path="§35">§ 35 of D.C. Law 22-189</cite> provided that the creation of subsection (i) of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-189" path="§20">§ 20 of D.C. Law 22-189</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-12-04" doc="D.C. Law 22-189" eff="2018-12-04" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-12-04" doc="D.C. Law 22-189" eff="2018-12-04" path="§20" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 22-189" path="§20" codified:display="Note" app="2018-12-04" eff="2018-12-04">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-189" path="">D.C. Law 22-189</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-189" path="§35">§ 35 of D.C. Law 22-189</cite> provided that the creation of subsection (i) of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-189" path="§20">§ 20 of D.C. Law 22-189</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§7153" codified:display="Note" app="2019-07-22" eff="2019-07-22">For temporary (90 days) repeal of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-189, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§7153">§ 7153 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019, 66 DCR 8497)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§7153" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§7153" codified:display="Note" app="2019-09-04" eff="2019-09-04">For temporary (90 days) repeal of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-189, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§7153">§ 7153 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019, 66 DCR 11964)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§7153" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-16" path="§7153" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-09-11">
        Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-189">D.C. Law 22-189</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-16" path="§7153">§ 7153 of D.C. Law 23-16</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-189" path="§35">§ 35 of D.C. Law 22-189</cite>. Therefore the creation of subsection (i) this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-189">D.C. Law 22-189</cite> has been implemented.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§7153" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
