<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1231.04</num>
  <heading>Requirements for certain notarial acts.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A notarial officer who takes an acknowledgment of a record shall determine, from personal knowledge or satisfactory evidence of the identity of the individual, that the individual appearing before the officer and making the acknowledgment has the identity claimed and that the signature on the record is the signature of the individual.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A notarial officer who takes a verification of a statement on oath or affirmation shall determine, from personal knowledge or satisfactory evidence of the identity of the individual, that the individual appearing before the officer and making the verification has the identity claimed and that the signature on the statement verified is the signature of the individual.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A notarial officer who witnesses or attests to a signature shall determine, from personal knowledge or satisfactory evidence of the identity of the individual, that the individual appearing before the officer and signing the record has the identity claimed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A notarial officer who certifies or attests a copy of a record or an item that was copied shall determine that the copy is a full, true, and accurate transcription or reproduction of the record or item.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A notarial officer who makes or notes a protest of a negotiable instrument shall determine the matters set forth in <cite path="ยง28:3-505|(b)">ยง 28:3-505(b)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-12-04" doc="D.C. Law 22-189" eff="2018-12-04" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-12-04" doc="D.C. Law 22-189" eff="2018-12-04" path="ยง5" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
