<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-1231.25</num>
  <heading>Prohibited acts.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A commission as a notary public shall not authorize an individual to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Assist persons in drafting legal records, give legal advice, or otherwise practice law;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Act as an immigration consultant or an expert on immigration matters;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Represent a person in a judicial or administrative proceeding relating to immigration to the United States, United States citizenship, or related matters; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Receive compensation for performing any of the activities listed in this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A notary public shall not engage in false or deceptive advertising.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A notary public, other than an attorney licensed to practice law in the District, shall not use the term "notario" or "notario publico".</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A notary public, other than an attorney licensed to practice law in the District, shall not advertise or represent that the notary may assist persons in drafting legal records, give legal advice, or otherwise practice law. If a notary public who is not an attorney licensed to practice law in the District in any manner advertises or represents that the notary offers notarial services, whether orally or in a record, including broadcast media, print media, and the Internet, then the notary shall include the following statement, or an alternate statement pursuant to rules issued by the Mayor, in the advertisement or representation, prominently and in each language used in the advertisement or representation: "I am not an attorney licensed to practice law in the District. I am not allowed to draft legal records, give advice on legal matters, including immigration, or charge a fee for those activities." If the form of advertisement or representation is not broadcast media, print media, or the Internet and does not permit inclusion of the statement required by this subsection because of size, it shall be displayed prominently or provided at the place of performance of the notarial act before the notarial act is performed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise allowed by law, a notary public shall not withhold access to or possession of an original record provided by a person that seeks performance of a notarial act by the notary public.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A notary public shall not charge a higher fee than permitted in rules issued by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-12-04" doc="D.C. Law 22-189" eff="2018-12-04" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-12-04" doc="D.C. Law 22-189" eff="2018-12-04" path="ยง26" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
