<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-301.115c</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on November 21, 2021.*
      </text>
  <heading>Office of the Inspector General Support Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Office of the Inspector General Support Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Office of the Inspector General ("OIG") in accordance with subsection (d) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The following funds shall be deposited into the Fund:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Twenty-five percent of the revenue received by the District from each restitution and recoupment resulting from a criminal action that was initiated based on a referral by the OIG of a criminal matter to the United States Attorney's Office or the Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia; provided, that such revenue is not due to another party or encumbered by federal or other legal restrictions; provided further, that before the deposit of such revenue into the Fund in each of Fiscal Years 2022 through 2025, there shall be deposited first into the General Fund of the District of Columbia $284,000 from such recoveries or from recaptured payments described in paragraph (2) of this subsection; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Twenty-five percent of the revenue received by the District resulting from recaptured overpayments identified by the OIG during the course of an audit, inspection, or evaluation; provided, that such revenue is not due to another party or encumbered by federal or other legal restrictions; provided further, that before the deposit of such revenue into the Fund in each of Fiscal Years 2022 through 2025, there shall be deposited first into the General Fund of the District of Columbia $284,000 from such recaptured overpayments or from recoveries described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>No more than $1 million may be deposited into the Fund in any fiscal year; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>No additional revenue shall be deposited into the Fund if the deposit of the additional revenue would result in the total amount in the Fund exceeding $2.5 million.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Revenue described in subsection (b) of this section that is not deposited into the Fund as a result of the restrictions set forth in this subsection instead shall be deposited in the General Fund.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used to support the OIG's statutory responsibilities as set forth in <cite path="§1-301.115a">§ 1-301.115a</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund but not expended in a fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "recaptured overpayments" means local funds disbursed by a District agency, a District contractor, a District grantee, or other entity administering a District program or activity in excess of statutory, contractual, or other applicable legal requirements, when such excess disbursements are identified by the OIG in an audit or investigation, and when such excess disbursements are recovered by the District based on the OIG audit or investigation.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-85" type="History" path="§208a">Feb. 21, 1986, D.C. Law 6-85, § 208a [209]</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§1002" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§1002" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§1002" codified:display="Note" app="2021-08-23" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§1002">§ 1002 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
