<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-301.86e</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on November 21, 2021.*
      </text>
  <heading>Tenant Receivership Abatement Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Tenant Receivership Abatement Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Attorney General in accordance with subsections (b) and (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Funds from the following sources shall be deposited into the Fund:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Funds from the Attorney General Restitution Fund, which the Attorney General may use to supply initial funding for, and to from time to time to replenish, the Fund; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>All funds recovered from owners under <cite path="§42-3651.06|(j)|(2)">§ 42-3651.06(j)(2)</cite>; except, that when the deposit of such funds into the Fund would cause the Fund balance to exceed $2 million, the excess of such funds instead shall be deposited into the Litigation Support Fund established by <cite path="§1-301.86b">§ 1-301.86b</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Amounts on deposit in the Fund shall not exceed $2 million.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used to comply with orders issued by the Superior Court under <cite path="§42-3651.06|(j)">§ 42-3651.06(j)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in subsection (b)(2) of this section, the money deposited into the Fund but not expended in a fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-160" type="History" path="§106e" display="false">May 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-160, § 106e</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-160" type="History" path="§106e">May 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-160, § 106e</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§1093|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§1093|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§1093|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-08-23" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§1093|(b)">§ 1093(b) of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
