<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-307.69</num>
  <heading>Emergency withdrawal.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An account holder may make an emergency withdrawal of his or her opportunity account funds in accordance with this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An account holder may make an emergency withdrawal for:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Paying the costs of medical care or the expenses necessary to obtain medical care for the account holder or a spouse, domestic partner, father, mother, child, or dependent of the account holder;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Making a payment necessary to prevent the eviction of the account holder from the primary residence of the account holder or to prevent foreclosure on a mortgage for the primary residence of the account holder;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Making payments necessary to enable the account holder to meet necessary living expenses following loss of employment; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Making payments necessary to enable the account holder to meet necessary living expenses in the event of a sudden, unexpected loss of income.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except during a period of time for which the Mayor has declared a public health emergency pursuant to <cite path="§7-2304.01">§ 7-2304.01</cite>, an account holder making an emergency withdrawal shall only withdraw funds deposited by the account holder and shall not withdraw matching funds;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-1)</num>
    <text>If an account holder makes an emergency withdrawal for the purposes set forth at subsection (b)(2) or (3) of this section, the account holder shall withdraw only funds deposited by the account holder and shall not withdraw matching funds.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-2)</num>
    <text>If an account holder makes an emergency withdrawal for the purposes set forth at subsection (b)(1) of this section, the account holder shall withdraw only funds deposited by the account holder and shall not withdraw matching funds, unless the withdrawal is for a medical emergency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-3)</num>
    <text>If an account holder makes an emergency withdrawal for the purposes set forth at subsection (b)(4) of this section, the account holder may withdraw funds deposited by the account holder and matching funds.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An emergency withdrawal shall not be made unless authorized by an administering organization on a case-by-case basis.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An account holder shall not be required to repay funds withdrawn from the opportunity account for an emergency withdrawal but shall be required to resume making deposits into the opportunity account no later than 90 days after the emergency withdrawal.  If the account holder fails to make a deposit no later than 90 days after the emergency withdrawal:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The account holder shall lose his or her matching funds and the matching funds shall be returned to the District of Columbia and administering organization in the same amounts as the matching funds were provided;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The account holder shall be removed from the opportunity account program; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>All funds deposited by the account holder into the opportunity account shall be returned to the account holder.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-266" type="History" path="§10">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-266, § 10, 48 DCR 1240</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-405" path="§301|(d)" codified:display="Note" app="2020-08-19" eff="2020-08-19">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-405" path="§301|(d)">§ 301(d) of Coronavirus Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2020 [Effective August 19, 2020 through October 8, 2020] (D.C. Act 23-405, Aug. 19, 2020, 67 DCR 10235)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-405" eff="2020-08-19" path="§301|(d)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-09" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" eff="2020-10-09" path="§301|(d)|(1)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-09" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" eff="2020-10-09" path="§301|(d)|(1)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-09" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" eff="2020-10-09" path="§301|(d)|(1)|(C)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-09" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" eff="2020-10-09" path="§301|(d)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-09" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" eff="2020-10-09" path="§301|(d)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-09" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" eff="2020-10-09" path="§301|(d)|(4)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
