<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-327.54a</num>
  <heading>Development of emergency medical application.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Office shall develop an emergency medical application to aid a trained user in providing cardiopulmonary resuscitation to an individual reported to be exhibiting signs of cardiac arrest while emergency medical service providers are dispatched to the individual's location.  At a minimum, the emergency medical application shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notify a trained user that he or she is within a certain distance from an individual that is experiencing a cardiac arrest in a public location;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Notify a trained user of the nearest location of a publicly accessible defibrillator;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Assist emergency medical service providers in monitoring patients or relaying information to hospital emergency rooms; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Allow a trained user to alert the Office if an individual is experiencing a health emergency.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Director shall ensure that staff are adequately trained to assist trained users in the use of the emergency medical application.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other law, a trained user shall have the same protections as provided in <cite path="ยง7-401">ยง 7-401</cite>, and shall not be subject to criminal or, in the absence of gross negligence, civil liability for administering cardiopulmonary resuscitation or using an automated external defibrillator pursuant to <cite path="1|3|XII|C">this part</cite>:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In good faith to treat a person who he or she reasonably believes is experiencing a cardiac arrest;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Outside of a hospital or medical office; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Without the expectation of receiving or intending to seek compensation for such service or acts.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Emergency medical application" means a website or mobile platform where trained users can interact with the Office during medical emergencies.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Trained user" means a District resident or visitor using an emergency medical application who has been trained by an organization recognized by the Department of Health to provide cardiopulmonary resuscitation to a victim of a cardiac arrest.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2004-12-07" doc="D.C. Law 15-205" eff="2004-12-07" path="ยง3205a" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="ยง3112" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
