<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-325.365</num>
  <heading>New hospital at St. Elizabeths Startup Reserve Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the New Hospital at St. Elizabeths Startup Reserve Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Department of Health Care Finance in accordance with subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>There shall be deposited into the Fund such amounts as shall be appropriated, consistent with the Hospital Operations Agreement between the Government of the District of Columbia and UHS East End Sub, LLC, for the operation of a hospital at St. Elizabeths and for other purposes ("Operations Agreement"), approved pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-138" path="I">Title I</cite> of D.C. Law 23-138.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used for the purposes set forth in the Operations Agreement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund but not expended in a fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-10-20" doc="D.C. Law 23-138" eff="2020-10-20" path="II" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-20" doc="D.C. Law 23-138" eff="2020-10-20" path="ยง202" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
