<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-325.421</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
      </text>
  <heading>SNAP Reinvestment Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the SNAP Reinvestment Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Mayor in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The unspent local fund dollars remaining in the operating budget of the Department of Human Services at the end of each fiscal year shall be deposited into the Fund; provided, that the amount of unspent local fund dollars deposited into the Fund at the end of a fiscal year shall not exceed the difference between the total of all amounts that remain to be invested by the Department of Human Services pursuant to active Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program excessive payment error rate liability settlement agreements ("Settlement Agreements") between the Department of Human Services and the United States Department of Agriculture minus the amount in the Fund at the end of the fiscal year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used to implement the Settlement Agreements.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund but not expended during a fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History" path="§5085">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 5085</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="V|G" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§5062" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§5062" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§5062" codified:display="Note" app="2021-08-23" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§5062">§ 5062 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
