<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-325.411</num>
  <heading>Audit Engagement Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Audit Engagement Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Office of the District of Columbia Auditor in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The following shall be deposited into the Fund:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All unspent local fund monies remaining in the operating budget for the Office of the District of Columbia Auditor at the end of each fiscal year; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any other funds received on behalf of the Fund or the Office of the District of Columbia Auditor for the purpose of performing audits.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used for operating expenses related to performing audits.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund but not expended in a fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" path="§1012" codified:display="Note" app="2020-12-03" eff="2020-08-19">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-404" path="§1012">§ 1012 of Fiscal Year 2021 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2020 (D.C. Act 23-404, Aug. 19, 2020, 67 DCR 10098)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§1012" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="I" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="§1012" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
