<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-515.02</num>
  <heading>District residency preference for applicants.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All District subordinate agencies, independent agencies, and instrumentalities shall use a ranking system based on a scale of 100 points for all employment decisions for positions in, or positions equivalent to positions in, the Career Service, Educational Service, Legal Service, and Management Supervisory Service.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Except for attorneys in the Senior Executive Service Attorney Service and attorneys in the Legal Service employed by the Council, for positions in the Career Service, Educational Service, Legal Service, and Management Supervisory Service, an individual who is a District resident at the time of application shall be awarded a 10-point hiring preference over a nonresident applicant; provided, that the individual claims the preference.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For employees of subordinate agencies, independent agencies, and instrumentalities, the 10-point preference shall be in addition to any points awarded on the 100-point scale.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At the time of appointment, an individual who claimed the 10-point residency preference provided in subsection (a) of this section shall agree, in writing, to remain a District resident for a period of 7 consecutive years from the effective date of appointment into the position for which the individual claimed the residency preference.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An individual who claimed the residency preference provided in subsection (a)(2) of this section and who fails to maintain District residency for 7 consecutive years from the individual's effective date of appointment shall forfeit the individual's District government employment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A personnel authority shall verify an individual's residency to ensure compliance with this section in accordance with <cite path="§1-515.04">§ 1-515.04</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Each applicant for a position covered by subsection (a) of this section shall be informed in writing of the provisions of this section at the time of application.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-108" type="History" path="§101">Feb. 6, 2008, D.C. Law 17-108, § 101, 54 DCR 10993</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 223(a), 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § 1-515.01.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 7094 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite> repealed section 301 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-108">D.C. Law 17-108</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in subsec. (a).</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§2" prefix="renumbered as § 102" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
