<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-551.06</num>
  <heading>Bonus pay and special awards pay; exceptions to prohibition.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the prohibition in <cite path="§1-551.02|(a)">§ 1-551.02(a)</cite>, funds may be used to pay:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Retirement awards;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Hiring bonuses for difficult-to-fill positions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Additional income allowances for difficult-to-fill positions; provided, that this is not a waiver of <cite path="§1-551.05">§ 1-551.05</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Agency awards or bonuses funded by private grants or donations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Employee awards pursuant to <cite path="§1-619.01">§ 1-619.01</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Safe-driving awards;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Gainsharing incentives in the Department of Public Works;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Suggestion or invention awards;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Quality steps;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Salary incentives negotiated through collective bargaining; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Any other award or bonus required by an existing contract or collective bargaining agreement that was entered into before October 8, 2016.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the prohibition in <cite path="§1-551.02|(a)">§ 1-551.02(a)</cite> or any other provision of law, no restrictions on the use of funds to support the categories of special awards pay (comptroller subcategory 0137) or bonus pay (comptroller subcategory 0138) shall apply to employees of the District of Columbia Public Schools who are based at a local school or who provide services directly to individual students.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the prohibition in <cite path="§1-551.02|(a)">§ 1-551.02(a)</cite> or any other provision of law, the Office of the Attorney General shall pay employees of the Office of the Attorney General all performance allowance payments to which they are entitled or may become entitled under any approved compensation agreement negotiated between and executed by the Mayor and Compensation Unit 33 of the American Federation of Government Employees, Local 1403, AFL-CIO for the period from October 1, 2013, through September 30, 2017.  These payments are necessary to satisfy the requirements of <cite path="§1-608.57">§ 1-608.57</cite>, which requires the Attorney General's performance-management system to link pay to performance.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="I" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§1006" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
