<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-555.05</num>
  <heading>Revised revenue contingency.</heading>
  <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a portion of the amount of local recurring revenues included in the Chief Financial Officer's revenue estimates issued prior to January 1, 2021, that exceeds the April 24, 2020, revenue estimate incorporated in the approved budget and financial plan for Fiscal Year 2021 shall be deposited in the Workforce Investment Account  to satisfy the Fiscal Year 2021 negotiated salary adjustments set aside by <cite path="ยง1-555.02">ยง 1-555.02</cite> for employees in the bargaining units covered by the collective bargaining agreements approved pursuant to the Interest Arbitration Award and Collective Bargaining Agreement between the District of Columbia Public Schools and the Office of the State Superintendent of Education and the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees, District Council 20, Local 2921, AFL-CIO Emergency Approval Resolution of 2020, effective March 3, 2020 (Res. 23-374; 67 DCR 2735), and the Compensation Collective Bargaining Agreement between the District of Columbia Government and Compensation Units 1 and 2, FY 2018-FY2021, Approval Resolution of 2018, deemed approved February 23, 2018 (P.R. 22-738); provided, that if amounts certified in a single revenue estimate are insufficient to satisfy the combined value of the negotiated salary adjustments under both agreements, the Mayor or appropriate personnel authority shall consult with the affected bargaining units as to how the available funds shall be allocated.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="I" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="ยง1026" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
