<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-551.02</num>
  <heading>Bonus pay and special awards pay; generally.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Unless authorized pursuant to <cite path="1|5|IX">this subchapter</cite>, no funds shall be used to support the categories of bonus pay or special awards pay.  The prohibition on the use of funds under <cite path="1|5|IX">this subchapter</cite> shall include funds appropriated to any agency, department, unit, or instrumentality of the District of Columbia government, and, unless specifically authorized in a grant agreement, any funds disbursed by the District through a grant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, an agency, department, unit, or instrumentality of the District of Columbia government may use funds to support the categories of bonus pay or special awards pay if the agency, department, unit, or instrumentality establishes a Performance Based Rewards Program pursuant to <cite path="§1-551.03">§ 1-551.03</cite> and meets the other requirements of <cite path="1|5|IX">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, each personnel authority of the Council, the Office of the District of Columbia Auditor, and the Office of Advisory Neighborhood Commissions may use funds to support bonus pay or special awards pay.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="I" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§1002" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§1072|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-07-20" eff="2017-07-20">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§1072|(a)">§ 1072(a) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104, July 20, 2017, 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-07-20" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" eff="2017-07-20" path="§1072|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§1072|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-10-24" eff="2017-10-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§1072|(a)">§ 1072(a) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167, Oct. 24, 2017, 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-10-24" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" eff="2017-10-24" path="§1072|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1072|(a)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
