<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-602.03</num>
  <heading>Educational employees of the District of Columbia Board of Education and the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Educational employees of the District of Columbia Board of Education and the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia shall be governed by the provisions of this chapter with the exception of subchapters VIII, IX (except to the extent provided therein), and X-A of this chapter. Subchapter VIII-A of this chapter shall only apply to such educational employees.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Educational employees of the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia shall not be governed by the provisions of <cite path="§1-609.01">§ 1-609.01</cite> relating to the development of job descriptions in consultation with the Mayor. The Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia shall develop policies on classification, appointment, promotion, retention, and tenure of employees consistent with the educational missions of their respective schools and in accordance with the sound policies and practices of the American Bar Association in the case of the School of Law, and of land-grant universities that meet the standards established by the College and Universities Personnel Association in the case of the University of the District of Columbia. Additionally, educational employees shall not be covered by subchapters VIII, X, XI (except as it provides for pay setting), XIII, XIII-A, XIX, and XXIV of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of <cite path="2|14|A">Unit A of Chapter 14 of Title 2</cite>, the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia ("Board") shall use a ranking system based on a scale of 100 points for all employment decisions for all non-educational positions within the Board.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An individual who is a District resident at the time of application shall be awarded a 10-point hiring preference over a nonresident applicant; provided, that the individual claims the preference. This 10-point preference shall be in addition to any points awarded on the 100-point scale.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>At the time of appointment, an individual who claimed the 10-point residency preference shall agree, in writing, to maintain District residency for a period of 7 consecutive years from the effective date of appointment into the position for which the individual claimed the residency preference.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>An individual who claimed the residency preference and who fails to maintain District residency for 7 consecutive years from the individual's effective date of appointment shall forfeit the individual's District government employment.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Each applicant for a position covered by this paragraph shall be informed in writing of the provisions of this paragraph at the time of application.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Board shall verify and enforce District residency requirements pursuant to <cite path="§1-515.04">§ 1-515.04</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>By November 1 of each year and pursuant to <cite path="§1-515.06">§ 1-515.06</cite>, the Board shall submit to the Mayor an annual report detailing, for the previous fiscal year, compliance with residency requirements.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Repeal of § 4(b) of Law 6-177: See Historical and Statutory Notes following <cite path="§1-602.02">§ 1-602.02</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Repeal of § 3 of Law 6-177: Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-177">D.C. Law 6-177</cite> provided that the provisions of § 3 are repealed on the 1st day following the 36-month period after February 24, 1987.</text>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History" path="§203">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 203, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-177" type="History">Feb. 24, 1987, D.C. Law 6-177, § 3(c), 33 DCR 7241</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-152" type="History">Aug. 1, 1996, D.C. Law 11-152, § 302(b), 43 DCR 2978</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81" type="History">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 2(a), 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-91" type="History">Apr. 12, 2000. D.C. Law 13-91, § 103(a), 47 DCR 520</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-108" type="History">Feb. 6, 2008, D.C. Law 17-108, § 203(a), 54 DCR 10993</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-108">D.C. Law 17-108</cite> added subsec. (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-91">D.C. Law 13-91</cite>, in subsec. (a), in the first sentence, substituted “XI-A” for “XI”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-332.3.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-602.3.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§1-602.02">§ 1-602.02</cite>, <cite path="§1-604.04">§ 1-604.04</cite>, <cite path="§1-604.06">§ 1-604.06</cite>, and <cite path="§1-608.01a">§ 1-608.01a</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§3|(a)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
