<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-607.62</num>
  <heading>Study of transgender and non-binary employment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall contract with an entity to conduct a study of employment data, hiring and recruitment practices, and workplace climate in District government agencies in relation to people who are transgender or non-binary. At a minimum, the study shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A census of employees who identify as transgender or non-binary, including information on the employees' race and ethnicity, gender identity, and age;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A review of District government agencies' transgender and non-binary inclusion policies, including policies developed under <cite path="2|14|A">Unit A of Chapter 14 of Title 2</cite> ("Human Rights Act"), and any regulations promulgated pursuant to the <cite path="2|14|A">Human Rights Act,</cite> and an evaluation of the extent to which District government agencies have implemented such polices and how transgender and non-binary employees experience such polices;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An evaluation of District government agencies' actual recruitment, hiring, retention, and promotion practices related to prospective and current transgender and non-binary employees;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>An analysis of any disparities in earnings, title, pay grade, length of time in position, and educational attainment between employees who identify as transgender or non-binary and employees who identify as cisgender;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>An assessment of transgender and non-binary employees' workplace experiences as employees of District government agencies, including experiences of discrimination, harassment, or mistreatment on the job;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>An evaluation of data, including participant demographics and program outcomes, for transgender or non-binary participants in the Department of Employment Services' job training programs; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Recommendations for District government agencies on improving employment and hiring practices as they relate to individuals who are transgender or non-binary.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The contractor may survey employees to gather data for the purposes of the study.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The contractor completing the study shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Have, or partner with another entity with, experience studying and knowledge of sexual orientation and gender identity;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Include a statement in requests for information and surveys sent to employees explaining that providing information is voluntary;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Ensure the privacy, dignity, and confidentiality of employees;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Not disclose, or retain after the study is complete, personally identifiable information gathered in the course of the study; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Consult with the Office of Human Rights in developing a detailed proposed plan of the study, surveys to be administered, and any resulting recommendations from the entity.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may use electronic communication tools, including e-mail, to facilitate the contractor's outreach to District government employees.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Review the contractor's proposals and recommendations to ensure they are consistent with the <cite path="2|14|A">Human Rights Act</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Review data, with personally identifiable information removed, on harassment and discrimination complaints filed by transgender and non-binary employees against District government agencies since January 1, 2015;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide the contractor with the information necessary to facilitate subsection (a) of this section; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Submit a final report with findings and recommendations to the Council no later than December 31, 2021. The final report submitted to the Council shall not contain any personally identifiable information.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History" path="ยง761">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, ยง 761 [762]</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="II" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="ยง2122" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
