<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-608.59</num>
  <heading>Residency.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The provisions of <cite path="§1-515.02">§ 1-515.02</cite> shall apply to employment in the Legal Service other than the Senior Executive Service Attorney Service and attorneys employed by the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of <cite path="2|14|A">Unit A of Chapter 14 of Title 2</cite>, and in accordance with <cite path="§1-515.03">§ 1-515.03</cite>, any attorney appointed to the Senior Executive Service Attorney Service and an attorney appointed to the Legal Service at the Council shall become a resident of the District within 180 days of the effective date of the appointment, and shall remain a District resident for the duration of the employment.  Failure to become a District resident or to maintain District residency shall result in forfeiture of the position to which the person has been appointed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Beginning on May 23, 2019, waivers for residency requirements applicable to employees in the Legal Service shall be governed by <cite path="§1-515.05">§ 1-515.05</cite>; provided, that a waiver of the residency requirement described in subsection (b) of this section issued before May 23, 2019, for an individual appointed to a hard-to-fill position in the Senior Executive Service Attorney Service, shall remain effective for the duration of the individual's appointment to the position for which the individual received the waiver.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History" path="§859">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 859</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-260" type="History">as added Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-260, § 2(j), 46 DCR 1318</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-91" type="History">Apr. 12, 2000. D.C. Law 13-91, § 110(e), 47 DCR 520</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3(d) of the Legal Services Clarification and Technical Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-293, March 7, 2000,  47 DCR 2063).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 3(d) of the Legal Services Clarification and Technical Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-203, December 8, 1999,  46 DCR 10456).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of subchapter, see note to <cite path="§1-608.51">§ 1-608.51</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-91">D.C. Law 13-91</cite>, in subsecs. (a) and (b), substituted “the Senior Executive Service Attorney Service and attorneys employed by the Council of the District of Columbia” for “the Senior Executive Attorney Service”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-609.59.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§2-1831.08">§ 2-1831.08</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§3|(f)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§3|(f)|(2)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§3|(f)|(2)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§3|(f)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§3|(f)|(4)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Verification and enforcement of District residency shall occur pursuant to <cite path="§1-515.04">§ 1-515.04</cite>.</text>
  </para>
</section>
