<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-609.06</num>
  <heading>Residency.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An appointee to the Excepted Service shall become a resident of the District within 180 days after the effective date of the individual's appointment and shall remain a resident of the District during the period of appointment, pursuant to <cite path="§1-515.03">§ 1-515.03</cite>. The failure to become a District resident or to maintain District residency shall result in the forfeiture of the position to which the person has been appointed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Residency shall be verified and enforced pursuant to <cite path="§1-515.04">§ 1-515.04</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A person hired in the Excepted Service prior to March 16, 1989, who was required to be or become a District of Columbia resident within 180 days of appointment and maintain that residency or forfeit employment, shall continue to be bound by this domicile requirement after March 16, 1989.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Beginning on May 23, 2019, waivers for residency requirements applicable to employees in the Excepted Service shall be governed by <cite path="§1-515.05">§ 1-515.05</cite>; provided, that a waiver of the residency requirement described in subsection (a) of this section issued before May 23, 2019, shall remain effective for the duration of the individual's appointment to the position for which the individual received the waiver.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Office of the Inspector General shall meet the definitions of “hard to fill” position or “exceptional circumstances” to receive a waiver of the District of Columbia’s residency and domicile laws for new hires.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>“Hard to fill position” means a position so designated by the personnel authority on the basis of demonstrated recruitment and retention problems inherent in the position due to the uniqueness of the duties and responsibilities and the unusual combination of highly specialized qualification requirements for the position.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>“Exceptional circumstances” means conditions or facts that are uncommon, deviate from or do not conform to the norm, or are beyond willful control, which are presented to the personnel authority by the Inspector General when hiring an individual to fill a position in the Excepted or Executive Services, and which shall be considered by the personnel authority in determining the reasonableness of granting a waiver of the domicile requirement pursuant to this section and <cite path="§1-610.59">§ 1-610.59</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>At the request of the Inspector General, the Mayor shall have the authority to grant the Office of the Inspector General waivers of the residency requirement for new positions or hires in the Office of the Inspector General when those positions or hires present exceptional circumstances or for appointees or hires in hard to fill positions.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <text type="Repeal of Law">Section 153 of Pub. L. 105-277 repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-138">D.C. Law 12-138</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Repeal of Law">Repeal of Law 12-138</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title of title XL of Law 14-190: Section 4001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-190">D.C. Law 14-190</cite> provided that title XL of the act may be cited as the Office of Inspector General Domiciliary Amendment Act of 2002.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">District of Columbia Inspector General Improvement Act of 1997: Section 1 of Pub. L. 105-7, 111 Stat. 14, provided that the act may be cited as the “District of Columbia Inspector General Improvement Act of 1997.”</text>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History" path="§906">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 906, 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-203" type="History">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-203, § 2(c), 36 DCR 450</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 101-518" type="History">Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 2237, Pub. L. 101-518, § 136(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 105-7" type="History">Mar. 27, 1997, 111 Stat. 14, Pub. L. 105-7, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-124" type="History">June 10, 1998, D.C. Law 12-124, § 101(i), 45 DCR 2464</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-138" type="History">July 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-138, § 2(d), 45 DCR 2972</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 105-277" type="History">Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681-146, Pub. L. 105-277, § 153</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-91" type="History">Apr. 12, 2000. D.C. Law 13-91, § 158(a), 47 DCR 520</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-185" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-185, § 2(b), 49 DCR 6073</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 4002, 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-213" type="History">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-213, § 43, 49 DCR 8140</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 314, 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-115" type="History">Mar. 14, 2012, D.C. Law 19-115, § 2(e), 59 DCR 461</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-185">D.C. Law 14-185</cite>, referred to in subsec. (h), is the Excepted and Executive Service Domicile Requirement Amendment Act of 2002, effective October 1, 2002 ( 49 DCR 6073).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">Section 136(b) of Public Law 101-518, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1991, provided that the amendments made by § 136(a) shall take effect as if included in the enactment of the Residency Preference Amendment Act of 1988 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 7-203">D.C. Law 7-203</cite>, March 16, 1989).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3902 of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-453, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8026).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(f) Subsections (a) through (e) of this section shall not apply to any person applying for, or accepting, a position in the Excepted Service as an attorney prior to March 25, 2009. The person shall be covered by the provisions of <cite path="§1-608.01|(e)">§ 1-608.01(e)</cite>.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-115">D.C. Law 19-115</cite> repealed subsec. (f), which formerly read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite>, in subsec. (f), inserted “prior to March 25, 2009” in the first sentence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-213">D.C. Law 14-213</cite>, in subsec. (c)(2), substituted “Office of Personnel or other appropriate personnel authority” for “Office of Personnel, or its designee”; in subsec. (g)(2), substituted “The Mayor shall transmit” for “The Office of Personnel shall transmit”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-190">D.C. Law 14-190</cite> added subsec. (i).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-185">D.C. Law 14-185</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-91">D.C. Law 13-91</cite>, in subsec. (a), in the first sentence, substituted “subsection (c), subsection (d), or subsection (e) of this section” for “subsection (c) or subsection (d)”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Pub. L. 105-277, Div. A, § 101(c) § 153, Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681-146, repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-138">D.C. Law 12-138</cite>, which had repealed subsec. (c) of this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-339.6.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-610.6.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§1-603.01">§ 1-603.01</cite>, <cite path="§1-610.59">§ 1-610.59</cite>, <cite path="§2-1831.08">§ 2-1831.08</cite>, and <cite path="§2-1831.12">§ 2-1831.12</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§3|(g)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§3|(g)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§3|(g)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§3|(g)|(4)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§3|(g)|(5)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§3|(g)|(6)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§3|(g)|(7)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
