<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-608.82</num>
  <heading>Certificate of Good Standing filing requirement for Council attorneys.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except for temporary waiver of this requirement pursuant to procedures established by the Council, each attorney who is required to be a member of the District of Columbia Bar as a prerequisite of employment, and who is employed by the Council, shall file annually with the Secretary to the Council a Certificate of Good Standing from the Committee on Admissions of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Secretary to the Council shall publish in the District of Columbia Register, on an annual basis, a list of all attorneys who have not met the filing requirements of subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Council may develop policies and procedures to implement this section including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Procedures addressing the timing for filing a Certificate of Good Standing pursuant to subsection (a) of this section and associated procedures;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The standards governing when a temporary waiver of the filing requirement established by subsection (a) of this section may be granted by the personnel authority for the attorney who is employed by the Council; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The procedures by which an attorney who is employed by the Council shall be notified of the filing requirement established by subsection (a) of this section and whether he or she is in compliance with the requirement.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2017-04-01" doc="D.C. Law 21-232" eff="2017-04-01" path="§2|(j)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-232" path="§2|(j)" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2017-04-01" eff="2017-04-01">
        For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-29" path="§2|(j)">§ 2(j) of Council Independent Authority Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-29, Mar. 27, 2017, 64 DCR 3077)</cite>.
      </annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-04-01" doc="D.C. Law 21-232" eff="2017-04-01" path="§2|(j)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-232" path="§2|(j)" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2017-04-01" eff="2017-04-01">
        For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 21-551" path="§2|(j)">§ 2(j) of Council Independent Authority Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 21-551, Dec. 6, 2016, 63 DCR 15022)</cite>.
      </annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
