<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-610.82</num>
  <heading>Establishment of District of Columbia Government Apprenticeship Initiative.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a District of Columbia Government Apprenticeship Initiative ("Initiative") to create apprenticeships in District agencies.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>DCHR and OAIT ("Administrators") shall develop and administer the Initiative in accordance with <cite path="1|6|X-C">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each Administrator shall designate one employee to serve as the agency's Initiative coordinator.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Administrators shall consult with potential host agencies and labor union representatives to identify at least 5 apprenticeable occupations in the District government in which the District will create apprenticeship programs.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Administrators shall identify apprenticeable occupations based on:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Review of apprenticeable occupations within District agencies;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Consideration of previously open positions in District agencies;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Upcoming position openings;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Current permanent, term, and temporary positions;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Positions filled by outside contractors; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Positions that could become apprenticeships if classified at a lower grade;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The business needs of potential host agencies; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The long-term employment opportunities and earning potential of workers in the occupation, including outside the District government.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>At least one of the identified apprenticeable occupations shall be in information technology and at least one shall be in healthcare.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Administrators shall submit a plan for creating and administering apprenticeship programs in the apprenticeable occupations identified pursuant to subsection (c) of this section to the Council within 180 days after October 1, 2019.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For each apprenticeship program, the plan shall include:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The occupation covered by the apprenticeship program and the number of anticipated apprentices that will be employed in years 1, 2, and 3 of the Initiative;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Which agency or agencies will serve as host agencies;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Whether the host agency, DCHR, or another entity will serve as the apprenticeship sponsor;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>The division of responsibilities between each of the Administrators, the apprenticeship sponsor, and host agencies for the development and administration of the apprenticeship program, including which entity or entities will be responsible for ensuring that apprentices receive life skills training and requesting that the University of the District of Columbia Community College provide apprentices with related technical instruction if it will not be provided directly by the host agency or apprenticeship sponsor; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>A breakdown of costs by entity, including related technical instruction and life skills training.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Within 2 years after October 1, 2019, the District government shall employ at least 2 apprentices in an apprenticeship program in each of the 5 apprenticeable occupations identified pursuant to subsection (c) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>DCHR shall develop a process by which labor union representatives and potential host agencies, including independent agencies, may request the creation of an apprenticeship program in a specific occupation or agency. This process shall include DCHR meeting with labor union representatives at least 2 times per year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>DOES shall post all open apprenticeship positions on its DC Networks website.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-610.82" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§1-610.82">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-211" path="">D.C. Law 22-211</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-211" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 22-211</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-211" path="§2|(d)">§ 2(d) of D.C. Law 22-211</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History" path="§1081">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 1081 [1082]</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-02-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-211" eff="2019-02-22" path="§2|(d)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-02-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-211" eff="2019-02-22" path="§2|(d)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 22-211" path="§2|(d)" codified:display="Note" app="2019-02-22" eff="2019-02-22">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-211" path="">D.C. Law 22-211</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-211" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 22-211</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-211" path="§2|(d)">§ 2(d) of D.C. Law 22-211</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-02-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-211" eff="2019-02-22" path="§2|(d)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§7156" codified:display="Note" app="2019-07-22" eff="2019-07-22">For temporary (90 days) repeal of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-211, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§7156">§ 7156 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019, 66 DCR 8497)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§7156" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§7156" codified:display="Note" app="2019-09-04" eff="2019-09-04">For temporary (90 days) repeal of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-211, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§7156">§ 7156 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019, 66 DCR 11964)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§7156" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-16" path="§7156" type="Applicability" history="false" display-template="" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-09-11">
          Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-211">D.C. Law 22-211</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-16" path="§7156">§ 7156 of D.C. Law 23-16</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-211" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 22-211</cite>. Therefore the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-211">D.C. Law 22-211</cite> has been implemented.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§7156" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
