<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-620.52</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by temporary legislation that will expire on April 4, 2021.*
      </text>
  <heading>Patient protections.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a public employer may not refuse to hire, terminate from employment, penalize, fail to promote, or otherwise take adverse employment action against an individual based upon the individual's status as a qualifying patient unless the individual used, possessed, or was impaired by marijuana at the individual's place of employment or during the hours of employment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A qualifying patient's failure to pass a public employer-administered drug test for marijuana components or metabolites may not be used as a basis for employment-related decisions unless reasonable suspicion exists that the qualifying patient was impaired by marijuana at the qualifying patient's place of employment or during the hours of employment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to safety sensitive positions or if compliance would cause the public employer to commit a violation of a federal law, regulation, contract, or funding agreement.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-08-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-128" eff="2020-08-27" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-128" eff="2020-08-27" path="ยง5|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-128" eff="2020-08-27" path="ยง2|(d)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
