<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-175.04</num>
  <text>
                *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
                </text>
  <text>
                *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
                </text>
  <heading>Grant uses.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Grantees may conduct activities:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Regarding a subset of employment laws; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>With workers in a single occupational group; provided, that the grant application demonstrates that such occupational group experiences significant, disproportionately high, or persistent violations of employment laws or that the occupational group requires targeted assistance in order to access programs under employment laws.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Grantees that provide worker education shall provide, to an eligible individual or group of eligible individuals, information on the rights and responsibilities of accessing benefits under employment laws, recognizing violations of and learning how to prevent or rectify violations of employment laws, or learning how to assist others to take steps to prevent or rectify violations of employment laws.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="IV" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§4152" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§5042|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§4152" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4152" codified:display="Note" app="2021-08-23" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4152">§ 4152 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
