<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-1621</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of <cite path="32|16|I-A">this subchapter</cite>, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Adult education program" means a program, other than a program that is part of the conventional kindergarten through grade 12 educational system funded by the Uniform Per Student Funding Formula, that offers services or instruction below the college level for adults who:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Lack mastery of basic educational skills;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Do not have a certificate of graduation from a school providing secondary education and who have not achieved an equivalent level of education; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Have limited ability in speaking, reading, writing, or understanding the English language.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Course of training" means the totality of services within a workforce development or adult education program designed to assist participants in obtaining a particular skill, scope of knowledge, or credential.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Funding vehicle" includes grants, contracts, and human care agreements.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Guide" means the Workforce Development Expenditure Guide.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Occupation" means the broad occupation code and associated title assigned to a particular category of work in the most recent edition of the Standard Occupational Classification Manual published by the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Participant" means a person who participates or participated in a program, as defined by program rules established by the program's administering or funding agency.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Personally identifiable information" means information that can be used to distinguish or trace an individual's identity, such as the individual's name, social security number, or biometric records, alone, or when combined with other personal or identifying information that is linked or linkable to a specific individual, such as date and place of birth or mother's maiden name.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Program" means each activity, sub-activity, pilot program, or project, including those funded through memoranda of understanding between agencies, that is managed, administered, overseen, or funded by a District agency. Where a District agency provides a service, a program is the most discrete unit of services in which an individual can participate.  Where a provider receives District funding to provide a service, a program is the most discrete level at which a provider can apply for such funding.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Provider" means an organization that provides any service as part of a workforce development or adult education program with funding obtained from a District agency, including federal funding managed, administered, or overseen by a District agency.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Public charter school program" means a program provided by a District public charter school with funds from the Uniform Per Student Funding Formula.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Sector" means the category of the occupation for which an individual trained or prepared and includes the high-demand sectors identified by the Workforce Investment Council.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>"Service" includes post-secondary education, credential preparation, workforce training, work-readiness or job-readiness training, workforce preparation, occupational skills training, subsidized work experience, unsubsidized work experience, job search and job placement, case management, and assistance to employers regarding hiring or training.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>"Target population" means the individuals that a program is designed to serve, identified by reference to shared demographic characteristics such as age range, gender, or race, or status as English-language-learners, hard-to-serve individuals, individuals with a physical disability, or individuals with an intellectual or developmental disability.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>"WIC" means the Workforce Investment Council.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>"Workforce development program" means a program that provides any service that supports and increases the capacity of individuals to enter and remain a part of the labor market, excluding programs that are:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Part of the conventional kindergarten through grade 12 educational system and funded by the Uniform Per Student Funding Formula;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Four-year college degree programs or post bachelor's degree programs; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Federally or locally funded scholarships for post-secondary, degree-granting, or credit-based programs.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-1621" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§32-1621">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-95" path="">D.C. Law 22-95</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-95" path="§301">§ 301 of D.C. Law 22-95</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-95" path="§101">§ 101 of D.C. Law 22-95</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-05-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-95" eff="2018-05-05" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-05-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-95" eff="2018-05-05" path="§101" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 22-95" path="§101" codified:display="Note" app="2018-05-05" eff="2018-05-05">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-95" path="">D.C. Law 22-95</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-95" path="§301">§ 301 of D.C. Law 22-95</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-95" path="§101">§ 101 of D.C. Law 22-95</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-168" path="§7030" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2018-10-30" eff="2018-10-30"><cite doc="D.C. Law 22-168" path="§7030">Section 7030 of D.C. Law 22-168</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-95" path="§301">section 301 of D.C. Law 22-95</cite> amending the applicability restriction impacting this section. Therefore the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-95">D.C. Law 22-95</cite> has been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§7030" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
