<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-141.03</num>
  <heading>Retaliation prohibited.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No employer or agent thereof may take an adverse employment action against an employee for the employee's refusal to serve a customer or client, or to work within 6 feet of an individual, who is not complying with the workplace protections established pursuant to <cite path="ยง32-141.02">ยง 32-141.02</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No employer or agent thereof may take an adverse employment action against an employee because:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The employee tested positive for COVID-19; provided, that the employee did not physically report to the workplace after receiving a positive test result;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The employee was exposed to someone with COVID-19 and needs to quarantine;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The employee is sick and is waiting for a COVID-19 test result; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The employee is caring for or seeks to provide care for someone who is sick with COVID-19 symptoms or who is quarantined.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Nothing in <cite path="32|1A-i">this chapter</cite> prohibits an employer from requiring an employee who has tested positive for COVID-19 to refrain from entering the workplace until a medical professional has cleared the employee to return to the workplace or until a period of quarantine recommended by the Department of Health or U.S. Centers for Disease Control has elapsed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No employer or agent thereof may take an adverse employment action against an employee because of actions the employee takes to secure any right or protection contained in <cite path="32|1A-i">this chapter</cite> or to prevent or stop a violation of <cite path="32|1A-i">this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-08-13" doc="D.C. Act 23-384" eff="2020-08-13" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-13" doc="D.C. Act 23-384" eff="2020-08-13" path="ยง103" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
