<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-175.03</num>
  <text>
                *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
                </text>
  <heading>Grantee eligibility requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To be eligible for a grant authorized under <cite path="32|1D-ii">this chapter</cite>, a community-based organization shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Demonstrate in its application that it is well qualified to engage in the types of activities which will be funded, in whole or in part, by the grant;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Specify in its grant application the planned staff, schedule, format, and intended audience of the activities it plans to provide and provide a summary of the content of any worker education that will be carried out during the grant period;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Have the capacity to provide free legal services if applying to be a legal services provider; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Include other information as required by OAG.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In addition to the criteria specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection, to be eligible for Program grant funds, a community-based organization that is not a legal services provider shall demonstrate that it possesses at least 3 years' experience:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Conducting outreach to and establishing working relationships with significant numbers of eligible individuals; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Working on or assisting workers to secure rights under employment laws.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A community-based organization that does not satisfy the criteria in subparagraph (A)(i) of this paragraph may receive a Program grant if it applies in partnership with a community-based organization that meets the requirements of subparagraph (A)(i) and (ii) of this paragraph.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="IV" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§4152" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§4152" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4152" codified:display="Note" app="2021-08-23" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4152">§ 4152 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
