<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-1051.15</num>
  <heading>Civil action.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A covered employee aggrieved by a violation of  <cite path="32|10A">this chapter</cite> may bring a civil action in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia and may be awarded such legal or equitable relief as may be appropriate to effectuate the purposes of  <cite path="32|10A">this chapter</cite>, including without limitation:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Reinstatement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Payment of lost wages totaling not less than the hourly rate of pay due to the covered employee but for the violation multiplied by the number of hours below the minimum work week that the covered employee was provided each work week during which a violation occurred;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Actual medical costs incurred by the covered employee as a result of the violation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Liquidated damages in the amount of $100 per day for each day the violation continued; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Reasonable attorney's fees and costs of the action to be paid by the defendant to a prevailing plaintiff.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An action to recover damages under  <cite path="32|10A">this chapter</cite> may be maintained in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia by one or more covered employees aggrieved by a violation of  <cite path="32|10A">this chapter</cite> or on behalf of a covered employee or covered employees who are similarly situated as long as at least one of the covered employees has exhausted all administrative remedies.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>For the purposes of this subsection, 2 or more covered employees are similarly situated if they:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Are or were employed by the same covered employer, whether concurrently or otherwise, at some point during the applicable statute of limitations period;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Allege one or more violations that raise similar questions as to liability; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Seek similar forms of relief.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Covered employees alleging violations of  <cite path="32|10A">this chapter</cite> shall not be considered dissimilar under this subsection solely because their claims seek damages that differ in amount or their job titles, or other means of classifying them differ in ways that are unrelated to their claims.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an action commenced for a violation of  <cite path="32|10A">this chapter</cite> on or after the applicability of  <cite path="32|10A">this chapter</cite> shall be commenced within 3 years after the cause of action accrued or of the last occurrence if the cause of action is continuous, whichever is later, or the cause of action shall be forever barred.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The 3-year statute of limitations shall be tolled:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>From the date the covered employee files an administrative complaint with the Mayor until the Mayor notifies the covered employee in writing that the administrative complaint has been resolved or the administrative complaint is withdrawn by the covered employee;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>During any period that the covered employer has failed to provide the covered employee with actual or constructive notice of the covered employee's rights; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>On other equitable grounds.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§16" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" codified:display="Note" app="2016-10-08" eff="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" path="§16">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-157" path="">D.C. Law 21-157</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-157" path="§18">§ 18 of D.C. Law 21-157</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-157" path="§16">§ 16 of D.C. Law 21-157</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§7016" codified:display="Note" app="2017-07-20" eff="2017-07-20">For temporary (90 days) repeal of § 18 of D.C. Law 21-157, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§7016">§ 7016 of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104, July 20, 2017, 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-07-20" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" eff="2017-07-20" path="§7016" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§7016" codified:display="Note" app="2017-10-24" eff="2017-10-24">For temporary (90 days) repeal of § 18 of D.C. Law 21-157, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§7016">§ 7016 of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167, Oct. 24, 2017, 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-10-24" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" eff="2017-10-24" path="§7016" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§7016" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2017-12-13" eff="2017-12-13"><cite doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§7016">Section 7016 of D.C. Law 22-33</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-157" path="§18">§ 18 of D.C. Law 21-157</cite>. Therefore the changes made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-157">D.C. Law 21-157</cite> have been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§7016" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
