<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-181.02</num>
  <heading>CertainiInformation to be available when American Job Centers are closed.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning no later than 15 days after the effective date of this subtitle, on any day when American Job Centers are closed (excluding weekends, holidays, and staff training days), the Department of Employment Services ("DOES") shall provide the following materials at its headquarters from 8:30 a.m. to 5:00 p.m.:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Hard copies of unemployment insurance benefits applications, with hard copies of all instructions that are available online for completing the application;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Hard copies of DOES complaint forms for violations of District labor laws, including wage and hour, accrued paid sick time, and workers' compensation laws, with hard copies of all instructions that are available online for completing each form;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Envelopes individuals may use in submitting their applications and complaint forms, with space on the outside to identify the form being submitted; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A locked box with a slot into which individuals may deposit their completed applications and complaint forms.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The DOES shall make the materials identified in subsection (a) of this section available in a location at its headquarters that is publicly and handicap accessible.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="II" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="ยง2113" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
