<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-1051.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of <cite path="32|10A">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Covered employee" or "building services employee" means an individual performing janitorial services, building maintenance services, or other services in or around a covered location to maintain the repair, cleanliness, and overall quality of the covered location.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Covered employer" means an individual, group of individuals, partnership, association, corporation, business trust, society, firm, company, joint stock company, or other entity that at a covered location:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Directly employs a covered employee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Contracts for the services of a covered employee; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Subcontracts for the services of a covered employee.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Covered leave" means paid or unpaid temporary leave from work taken by a covered employee pursuant to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Federal or District law;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>An employee handbook; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>A written request voluntarily initiated by the covered employee.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Covered location" means an office building, commonly owned office park, or a commonly owned and managed group of buildings, with over 350,000 square feet of net rentable commercial office space.  The term "covered location" excludes property owned or leased by a health-care facility licensed under the Health-Care and Community Residence Facility, Hospice and Home Care Licensure Act of 1983, effective February 24, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-48; D.C. Official Code ยง 44-501 <em>et seq.</em>), and affiliated subsidiaries.
          </text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Minimum work week" means the minimum number of compensated hours provided to a covered employee in any work week, including weeks in which the covered employee is taking covered leave.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>"Office park" means an area where a number of office buildings are together on landscaped grounds, which may include parking lots, parklike surroundings, and restaurants.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>"Work week" means a fixed regularly recurring period of 168 hours or 7 consecutive 24-hour periods.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="ยง2" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
