<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-141.04</num>
  <heading>Enforcement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may enforce and administer <cite path="32|1A-i">this chapter</cite> by conducting investigations (of the Mayor's own volition or after receiving a complaint), holding hearings, and assessing penalties. The Mayor shall have the power to administer oaths and examine witnesses under oath, issue subpoenas, compel the attendance of witnesses, compel the production of papers, books, accounts, records, payrolls, documents, and testimony, and to take depositions and affidavits in any proceedings before the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may assess administrative penalties in the following amounts:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>For violations of <cite path="§32-141.02">§ 32-141.02</cite>, up to $50 per violation per employee per day for a repeated or willful violation.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For violations of <cite path="§32-141.03">§ 32-141.03</cite>, up to $500 per violation.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General may enforce <cite path="32|1A-i">this chapter</cite> by conducting investigations (of the Attorney General's own volition or after receiving a complaint) and instituting actions. The Attorney General shall have the power to administer oaths and examine witnesses under oath, issue subpoenas, compel the attendance of witnesses, compel the production of papers, books, accounts, records, payrolls, documents, and testimony, and to take depositions and affidavits in any investigation or proceeding conducted to enforce <cite path="32|1A-i">this chapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General, acting in the public interest, including the need to deter future violations, may enforce <cite path="32|1A-i">this chapter</cite> by commencing a civil action in the name of the District of Columbia in a court of competent jurisdiction on behalf of the District or one or more aggrieved employees.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Upon prevailing in court after commencing a civil action as permitted by this subsection, the Attorney General shall be entitled to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Reasonable attorneys' fees and costs;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Statutory penalties in amount not greater than the maximum administrative penalties provided under subsection (b) of this section;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>On behalf of an aggrieved employee, the payment of lost wages; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Equitable relief as may be appropriate.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-08-13" doc="D.C. Act 23-384" eff="2020-08-13" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-13" doc="D.C. Act 23-384" eff="2020-08-13" path="§104" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
