<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-175.02</num>
  <text>
                *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
                </text>
  <heading>Establishment of Program and issuance of grants.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the Workplace Rights Grant Program for the purpose of authorizing OAG to provide grants to community-based organizations to conduct activities with eligible individuals related to employment laws and to inform the OAG's work related to employment laws.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>OAG shall administer the Program by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Issuing Program grants to community-based organizations to provide:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Outreach and worker education;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Outreach and legal services; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A combination of outreach, worker education, and legal services.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Awarding Program grants at least annually, which may include the continuation or renewal of multi-year grants, to at least 2 qualified community-based organizations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Adopting policies, procedures, guidelines, and requirements for the grants, including performance measures and target outcomes; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Issuing all grants pursuant to the requirements set forth in t<cite path="1|3|XII-A">subchapter XII-A of Chapter 3 of Title 1</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>OAG may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Require that at least 95% of the individuals served by a Program grant in a grant year be low- or moderate-income eligible individuals or reasonably believed to be low- or moderate-income eligible individuals; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Pay grants on a performance basis or a reimbursable basis.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Program grants shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Have a duration of at least one year and up to 3 years, subject to the availability of appropriations and contingent on satisfactory performance by a grantee during the grant's first year or, if applicable, the grant's second year; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be for not less than $100,000 per year per grant.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="IV" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§4152" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§4152" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4152" codified:display="Note" app="2021-08-23" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4152">§ 4152 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
