<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-1131.02</num>
  <heading>Prohibition against assisting certain employment of perpetrator of child sexual abuse offenses.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A covered employee is prohibited from assisting an employee, contractor, or agent of a school or a child development facility in obtaining a new job involving direct interaction with minors if the covered employee knows, or has probable cause to believe, that such employee, contractor, or agent engaged in sexual misconduct or sexual abuse regarding a child or student in violation of District or federal law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The prohibition in subsection (a) of this section shall not apply if the information giving rise to probable cause:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Has been properly reported to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A law enforcement agency with jurisdiction over the alleged sexual misconduct or sexual abuse; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Any other appropriate authorities as required by federal or District law, including any authorities identified under Title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972, approved June 23, 1972 (86 Stat. 373; 20 U.S.C. 1681 <em>et seq.</em>), and 34 C.F.R. Part 106; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The matter has been officially closed or the United States Attorney's Office for the District of Columbia or the Metropolitan Police Department has investigated the allegations and notified school or child development facility officials that there is insufficient information to establish probable cause that the employee, contractor, or agent engaged in sexual misconduct or sexual abuse regarding a minor or student in violation of District or federal law;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The employee, contractor, or agent has been charged with, and acquitted or otherwise exonerated of the alleged misconduct or abuse; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The case or investigation remains open and there have been no charges filed against, or indictment of, the employee, contractor, or agent within 4 years of the date on which the information was reported to the United States Attorney's Office for the District of Columbia or the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-294" eff="2019-04-11" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-294" eff="2019-04-11" path="ยง202" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
