<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-141.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of <cite path="32|1A-i">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Adverse employment action" means an action that an employer takes against an employee, including a threat, verbal warning, written warning, reduction of work hours, suspension, termination, discharge, demotion, harassment, material change in the terms or conditions of the employee's employment, or any action that is reasonably likely to deter the employee from attempting to secure any right or protection contained in <cite path="32|1A-i">this chapter</cite> or to prevent or stop a violation of <cite path="32|1A-i">this chapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Active COVID-19 infection" means an infection confirmed by a diagnostic test for COVID-19 and not an antibody test.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"COVID-19" means the disease caused by the novel coronavirus SARS-CoV-2.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Employee" includes any person suffered or permitted to work by an employer.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Employer" includes every individual, partnership, firm, general contractor, subcontractor, association, corporation, the legal representative of a deceased individual, or the receiver, trustee, or successor of an individual, firm, partnership, general contractor, subcontractor, association, or corporation employing any person in the District of Columbia. The term "employer" shall include the District government or a quasi-governmental agency. The term "employer" shall not include the United States government or its agencies.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Personal protective equipment" includes face coverings, disposable gloves, eye protection, face shields, disposable gowns or aprons, and plexiglass barriers.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"PPE" means personal protective equipment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Public health emergency" means the Coronavirus (COVID-19) public health emergency declared pursuant to Mayor's Order 2020-045, on March 11, 2020, and all subsequent extensions.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Workplace" means any physical structure or space over which an employer maintains control wherein an employee performs work for an employer; workplace does not include the home of an employee who teleworks.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-08-13" doc="D.C. Act 23-384" eff="2020-08-13" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-13" doc="D.C. Act 23-384" eff="2020-08-13" path="ยง101" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
