<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-171.04</num>
  <heading>Grant requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each grantee must hold at least 10 workshops aimed at informing District-based employees who are or expect to become part of the private-sector workforce about their rights under 2 or more of the following laws:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Accrued Sick and Safe Leave Act of 2008 [<cite path="32|5|III">subchapter III of Chapter 5 of this title</cite>];</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Minimum Wage Act Revision Act of 1992 [<cite path="32|10">Chapter 10 of this title</cite>];</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An Act To provide for the payment and collection of wages in the District of Columbia [<cite path="32|13">Chapter 13 of this title</cite>];</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Wage Theft Prevention Amendment Act of 2014, effective October 1, 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>; 61 DCR 10157); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text><cite path="32|13|II">Subchapter II of Chapter 13 of this title</cite> and <cite path="§2-359.07|(c)|(6A)">§ 2-359.07(c)(6A)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Workshops may be of any duration and in any format that the grantee determines is most effective at helping employees understand their rights; provided, that all other requirements of this section are satisfied.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Workshops may be directed to a general audience of District-based employees or may be tailored to a particular demographic group or industry subset of employees.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For each workshop held, the grantee must obtain the following information from each attendee:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Gender;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Racial or ethnic group;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Whether employed full-time, part-time, or unemployed;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Industry; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Occupation.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The grantee may permit attendees to decline to answer individual questions but shall record that the attendee declined.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>At the conclusion of the grant period, each grantee shall demonstrate to DOES that it presented workshops to at least 500 people over the grant period.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Grantees may fulfill the requirements of the grant by contracting with or subgranting funds to another community-based organization to perform any portion of the grant requirements; provided, that the contractor or subgrantee agrees to comply with the terms of this subtitle and the grant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>DOES may specify additional requirements for grantees consistent with the purpose of the Program.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation codify:doc="D.C. Code" path="§2095" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91">
          For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="2095">§ 2095 of the Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019</cite>, 66 DCR 8497).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§2095" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation codify:doc="D.C. Code" path="§2095" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112">
          For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="2095">§ 2095 of the Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019</cite>, 66 DCR 11964).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§2095" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="II" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§2095" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
