<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-175.05</num>
  <text>
                *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
                </text>
  <heading>Transparency and reporting.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>OAG annually shall collect the following information from grantees:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The number of eligible individuals served by gender, race, ethnicity, primary language, and age;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The number of eligible individuals served by state of residence, and for District residents, by election ward;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The occupational groups of eligible individuals served and the number of individuals served in each occupational group;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A list of the activities provided, with a descriptive summary of each activity;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The number of eligible individuals served in relation to each employment law or set of employment laws;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Performance outcomes; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>An evaluation of implementation challenges and recommendations for future improvements.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>OAG annually shall provide to the Council a report that includes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A list of grantees and the amount of grant funding provided to each;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For each grantee, the information provided to OAG pursuant to subsection (a) of this section; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An overall evaluation of the Program, including implementation challenges and recommendations for future improvements.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>OAG may not require grantees to release to OAG any personally identifying information in connection with the preparation or provision of the reports described in this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="IV" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§4152" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§4152" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4152" codified:display="Note" app="2021-08-23" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4152">§ 4152 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
