<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>32-1051.07</num>
  <heading>Penalties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a covered employer who willfully violates the posting requirements of section 5 shall be assessed a civil penalty not to exceed $100 for each day that the covered employer fails to post the notice; provided, that the total penalty shall not exceed $500.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No liability for failure to post the notice shall arise under this section if the Mayor has failed to provide the notice required by section 5 to the covered employer.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A covered employer who fails to comply with any of the requirements of this act, other than the posting requirements of section 5, shall be subject to a fine of not more than $5,000 for each violation for each day that the violation continues.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, each violation of a covered employee's right provided by this act shall constitute a separate violation of this act.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Mayor shall assess an administrative penalty against a covered employer for a violation of this act. In assessing the amount of the fine to be imposed pursuant to the following authorized penalties, the Mayor may consider factors the Mayor determines appropriate, including a covered employer's past history of violations of this act:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>For the first violation, a maximum fine of up to $500; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For any subsequent violation, a maximum fine of up to $1,000.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No administrative penalty may be collected unless the Mayor provided a covered employer alleged to have violated this act:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Notification of the violation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The amount of the administrative penalty that may be imposed; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>An opportunity to request a hearing.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="ยง8" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
