<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-111.05</num>
  <heading>Enforcement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>An eligible employee or retained employee may, on their own behalf or on behalf of other eligible employees or retained employees similarly situated, bring an action to enforce <cite path="32|1|II">this subchapter</cite> in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia and upon prevailing shall be awarded:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Back pay for each day the violation continues at a rate of compensation not less than the higher of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The average regular rate of pay received by the eligible employee or retained employee during the last 3 years of the eligible employee or retained employee's employment in the same occupation classification, or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The final regular rate received by the eligible employee or retained employee;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The costs of benefits the employer would have incurred for the eligible employee or retained employee under the employer's benefit plan;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If it is established that a contractor or employer violated <cite path="32|1|II">this subchapter</cite> with malice or with reckless indifference, an affected eligible employee or retained employee treble damages, and, in addition, may be awarded compensatory or punitive damages; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Reasonable attorney fees and costs of the suit, including expert witness fees.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-105" type="History" path="§2">Apr. 26, 1994, D.C. Law 10-105, § 205</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-605" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-04-27" eff="2021-01-13">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-605" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of Displaced Workers Right to Reinstatement and Retention Emergency Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Act 23-605, Jan. 13, 2021, 68 DCR 001213)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Act 23-605" eff="2021-01-13" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-281" eff="2021-04-27" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-281" eff="2021-04-27" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-281" eff="2021-04-27" path="§2|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-69" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2021-05-03" eff="2021-05-03">For temporary (90 days) creation of, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-69" path="§2">§ 2 of Displaced Workers Right to Reinstatement and Retention Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-69, May 3, 2021, 68 DCR 004914)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-05-03" doc="D.C. Act 24-69" eff="2021-05-03" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
