<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-1007</num>
  <heading>Investigatory powers of Mayor.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor and the Attorney General shall each have the power to administer oaths and require by subpoena the attendance and testimony of witnesses, the production of all books, registers, and other evidence relative to any matters under investigation, at any public hearing, or at any meeting of any committee or for the use of the Mayor or the Attorney General in securing compliance with <cite path="32|10">this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In case of disobedience to a subpoena, the Mayor or the Attorney General may invoke the aid of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to require the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of documentary evidence.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In case of contumacy or refusal to obey a subpoena, the Court may issue an order to require an appearance before the Mayor or the Attorney General, the production of documentary evidence, and the giving of evidence.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person or an entity to whom a subpoena has been issued may move to quash or modify the subpoena.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Any failure to obey the order of the Court may be punished by the Court as contempt.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-248" type="History" path="§8">Mar. 25, 1993, D.C. Law 9-248, § 8, 40 DCR 761</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 36-220.6.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 21-583" path="§3|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2016-12-21" eff="2016-12-21">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 21-583" path="§3|(b)">§ 3(b) of Wage Theft Prevention Clarification and Overtime Fairness Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-583, Dec. 21, 2016, 63 DCR 16031)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-12-21" doc="D.C. Act 21-583" eff="2016-12-21" path="§3|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-33" path="§3|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-03-28" eff="2017-03-28">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-33" path="§3|(b)">§ 3(b) of Wage Theft Prevention Clarification and Overtime Fairness Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-33, Mar. 28, 2017, 64 DCR 3089)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-03-28" doc="D.C. Act 22-33" eff="2017-03-28" path="§3|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-04-07" doc="D.C. Law 21-266" eff="2017-04-07" path="§3|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
