<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-247</num>
  <heading>Industry advisory committees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director shall establish industry advisory committees to advise DCIA on occupational skills training offerings with the goal of aligning DCIA's trainings with industry hiring needs.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>There shall be one committee per industry sector in which DCIA offers occupational skills training pursuant to <cite path="§32-246|(a)|(1)">§ 32-246(a)(1)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Each committee shall consist of representatives of at least 2 employers from the relevant industry sector, whom the Director shall appoint.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Director shall make initial appointments to the committees within 30 days of December 20, 2020.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Committee members shall disclose all existing and potential conflicts of interest to the Director. No committee member may, in any manner, directly or indirectly, participate in a deliberation upon, or the determination of, any question affecting the financial interest of any corporation, partnership, or association in which the member or a member of the member's family is directly or indirectly interested. Committee members shall disclose the nature of any financial or personal relationships with any training providers by completing a conflict of interest form.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No later than December 15, 2020, and annually thereafter in advance of the start of a new fiscal year, each Committee shall submit written recommendations to DCIA, which shall contain the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Recommendations of 2 to 4 specific occupational skills trainings DCIA should offer;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The number of District residents DCIA should train in the occupations identified pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Occupational skills required to obtain employment in the occupations identified pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A description of tools, equipment, and services necessary to conduct trainings to acquire the skills identified in paragraph (3) of this subsection;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Industry-recognized credentials required for obtaining employment in the occupations identified pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, when appropriate; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The feasibility of providing virtual training or distance learning and recommendations to implement virtual training.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>After receiving a proposed training curriculum from the DCIA pursuant to <cite path="§32-246|(a)|(2)|(B)|(i)">§ 32-246(a)(2)(B)(i)</cite>, a Committee shall provide the DCIA with a written explanation of recommended modifications, if any.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Within 30 calendar days after receiving a proposed scope of work for a grant or contract from DCIA pursuant to <cite path="§32-246|(a)|(2)|(C)|(i)">§ 32-246(a)(2)(C)(i)</cite>, the Committee shall provide DCIA with a written explanation of recommended modifications, if any.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-46" type="History" path="§2f">Jan. 5, 1980, D.C. Law 3-46, § 2f</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="§2082|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
