<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-246</num>
  <heading>DC Infrastructure Academy.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In addition to duties the Mayor prescribes, the DCIA shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Provide occupational skills training ("skills training") annually in industries for which there is significant demand regionally or by a major employer, including construction, infrastructure, and information technology;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide occupational skills training designed to meet the needs of employers by:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Aligning skills training, where appropriate, with the annual recommendations the committees submit to the DCIA pursuant to <cite path="§32-247|(c)">§ 32-247(c)</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Submitting a proposed curriculum, at least 30 calendar days prior to the start of any skills training taught by DCIA staff, to the relevant committee for its feedback; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Taking into consideration any feedback from a committee when implementing any skills trainings taught by DCIA staff;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Submitting to the relevant committee, at least 30 calendar days before soliciting applications or bids on a grant or contract to provide skills training, a request that the committee review a grant or contract solicitation's proposed scope of work; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Considering any feedback received from a committee when preparing statements of work for grants and contracts to provide skills training; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>For any customized skills training provided specifically for a particular employer, seeking input from the employer consistent with the requirements outlined in subparagraphs (B) and (C) of this paragraph;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide test preparation sessions and practice exams to ready participants to obtain the occupational credentials the committees identify in their annual reports pursuant to <cite path="§32-247|(c)">§ 32-247(c)</cite>(4) [§ 32-247(b)]; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Provide job referrals, as defined in 20 C.F.R. § 651.10, to employers in the industry sectors in which training is offered pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection for all qualified graduates of DCIA training programs.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>DCIA skills training may include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Training services enumerated in section 134(c)(3)(D) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, approved July 22, 2014 (128 Stat. 1529; 29 U.S.C. § 3174(c)(3)(D));</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Supportive services, as defined in 20 C.F.R. § 651.10;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Integrated education and training, as defined in 34 C.F.R. § 463.35;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Workforce preparation activities, as defined in 34 C.F.R. § 463.34; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Job development, as defined in 20 C.F.R. § 651.10.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At least 66% of the participants receiving skills training through the DCIA each fiscal year shall be trained in occupations that pay an average wage that is at least 150% of the minimum wage specified in <cite path="§32-1003">§ 32-1003</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>At least 25% of the value of each grant or contract with a skills training provider shall be contingent on the provider achieving at least one of the following results:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>At least 75% of the provider's participants receive an industry-recognized credential; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>At least 80% of the provider's participants enter permanent, unsubsidized employment in the occupation of training.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-46" type="History" path="§2e">Jan. 5, 1980, D.C. Law 3-46, § 2e</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="§2082|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
