<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-551.02</num>
  <heading>Universal Paid Leave Administration Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Universal Paid Leave Administration Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Department of Employment Services ("DOES") in accordance with subsections (c), (d), (e), and (f) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Pursuant to <cite path="§32-551.01|(b)|(2)">§ 32-551.01(b)(2)</cite>, amounts appropriated from the Universal Paid Leave Fund annually for the purposes described in subsection (c) of this section shall be deposited in the Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used for the following purposes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Administration of the Act by DOES, including public education pursuant to <cite path="§32-541.06|(j)">§ 32-541.06(j)</cite>; provided, that no more than 6% of the money appropriated annually for administration may be used for public education and of those public education funds, at least $500,000 shall be used to fund the Workplace Leave Navigators Program established pursuant to <cite path="§32-561.02">§ 32-561.02</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Enforcement of <cite path="§32-541.08|(e)">§ 32-541.08(e)</cite> and <cite path="§32-541.10|(a)">§ 32-541.10(a)</cite> and <cite path="§32-541.10|(b)"> (b)</cite> by the Office of Human Rights, which may include education and outreach on individuals' rights under <cite path="32|5|IV">subchapter IV of this chapter</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Hearing of appeals of claim determinations by the Office of Administrative Hearings, pursuant to <cite path="§32-541.08|(a)">§ 32-541.08(a)</cite>, and <cite path="§32-541.08|(b)"> (b)</cite>, and <cite path="§32-541.08|(c)">and (c)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Beginning no later than October 1, 2020, and by October 1 annually thereafter, DOES shall execute a Memorandum of Understanding with the Office of Human Rights for the intradistrict transfer of funds appropriated, pursuant to subsection (c)(2) of this section, for enforcement; provided, that DOES shall transfer funds appropriated for enforcement to the Office of Human Rights no later than October 2 of any year even if the agencies fail to execute a Memorandum of Understanding by October 1 of that year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Beginning no later than October 1, 2020 and by October 1 annually thereafter, DOES shall execute a Memorandum of Understanding with the Office of Administrative Hearings for the intradistrict transfer of funds appropriated, pursuant to subsection (c)(3) of this section, for hearing of appeals of claim determinations; provided, that DOES shall transfer funds appropriated for hearing of appeals of claim determinations to the Office of Administrative Hearings no later than October 2 of any year even if the agencies fail to execute a Memorandum of Understanding by October 1 of that year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Money deposited into the Fund but not expended in a fiscal year shall revert to the Universal Paid Leave Fund, established pursuant to <cite path="§32-551.02">this section</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="I|P" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§2142|(c)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
