<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>32-772</num>
  <heading>Department of Employment Services annual report on year-round youth programs.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Starting December 15, 2020, and annually thereafter, the Department of Employment Services ("Department") shall publish on its website and submit to the Council a report on the operations of its year-round youth programs, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The In-School Youth Program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Out-of-School Youth Program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Marion Barry Youth Leadership Institute;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Pathways for Young Adults Program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Youth Earn and Learn Program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The High School Internship Program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>In-School Youth Innovation Grants; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>In-school DCHR internship program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The report shall include the following information for each program from the previous fiscal year:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The number of participants newly enrolled;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The total number of participants, disaggregated by ward, grade, school, age, and, if known, at-risk status;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Each program's total expenditures, disaggregated by fund type (federal, local, intra-District, or special purpose revenue funds); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The names of any vendors, grantees, host employers (including public schools and public charter schools for the High School Internship Program), host sites, or other organizations providing services to youth.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Department may withhold from the report required pursuant to subsection (b) of this section any information precluded from release by federal law, rule, or policy; provided, that, if at a later time, such information may be released, the Department shall supplement the next annual report following the date on which the information may be shared with the withheld information.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "at-risk" means a public school, public charter school, private school, or homeschool student who is identified as one or more of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Homeless;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In the District's foster care system;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Qualifies for the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families program or the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A high school student that is one year older, or more, than the expected age for the grade in which the student is enrolled.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History" path="§2083">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 2083</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="§2103" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
