<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>11-1748</num>
  <heading>Authority of courts to accept certain types of payments.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <heading>Definitions.--In this section, the term `electronic funds transfer'--</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>means a transfer of funds, other than a transaction by check, draft, or similar paper instrument, that is initiated through an electronic terminal, telephone, or computer or magnetic tape for the purpose of ordering, instructing, or authorizing a financial institution to debit or credit an account; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>includes point of sale transfers, automated teller machine transfers, direct deposit or withdrawal of funds, transfers initiated by telephone, and transfers resulting from debit card transactions.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <heading>Authority To Accept Credit Card Payments and Electronic Funds Transfers.--</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <heading>In general.--</heading>
      <text>The District of Columbia courts may accept payment of fines, fees, escrow payments, restitution, bonds, and other payments to the courts by credit card or electronic funds transfer.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <heading>Use of vendors and third party providers.--</heading>
      <text>The Executive officer--</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>may contract with a bank or credit card vendor, or other third party provider, for purposes of accepting payments by credit card or electronic funds transfer; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>shall make every effort to find the lowest cost vendor for purposes of accepting such payments.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <heading>Responsibility for paying fees.--</heading>
      <text>Under any contract entered into under paragraph (2), the person making the payment shall be responsible for covering any fee or charge associated or imposed with respect to the method of payment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <heading>Completion of payment.--</heading>
      <text>Completion of payment.--If a person elects to make a payment to the District of Columbia courts by a method authorized under paragraph (1), the payment shall not be deemed to be made until the courts receive the funds.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <heading>Authority To Accept Checks.--</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <heading>In general.--</heading>
      <text>The District of Columbia courts may accept payment of fines, fees, escrow payments, restitution, bonds, and other payments to the courts by check.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <heading>Use of check guarantee vendor.--</heading>
      <text>The Executive Officer--</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>may contract with a check guarantee vendor for purposes of accepting payments by check; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>shall make every effort to find the lowest cost vendor for purposes of accepting such payments.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <heading>Responsibility for paying fees.--</heading>
      <text>Under any contract entered into under paragraph (2), the person making the payment by check shall be responsible for covering any fee or charge associated or imposed with respect to the method of payment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <heading>Liability for Non-Payment.--</heading>
    <text>If a check or other method of payment, including payment by credit card, debit card, or charge card, so received is not duly paid, or is paid and subsequently charged back to the District of Columbia courts, the person by whom such check or other method of payment has been tendered shall remain liable for the payment, to the same extent as if such check or other method of payment had not been tendered.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-12-14" doc="Pub. L. 114-257" eff="2016-12-14" path="ยง4|(a)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
