<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>36-641.07</num>
  <heading>Distributor licensure.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person may not buy, sell, distribute, lease, maintain, market, or service a game of skill machine or a major component or part of a game of skill machine for distribution in the District unless the person has a valid distributor's license issued by the Office.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A licensed distributor may buy, sell, distribute, lease, maintain, market, or service a game of skill machine or any major component or part of a game of skill machine for distribution in the District to a licensed establishment that possesses a retailer's license from the Office and a game of skill machine endorsement from the ABC Board pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 25-113.01(e).  No distributor may give anything of value, including a loan or financing agreement, to a licensed establishment as an incentive or inducement to locate a game of skill machine in the establishment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person applying for a distributor's license shall do so on a form prescribed by the Office.  The form shall require:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the applicant;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The mailing address of the applicant and, if the applicant is a corporation, the name of the state in which it is incorporated, the location of its principal place of business, and the names and addresses of its directors;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A report of the applicant's financial activities, including evidence of financial stability, such as bank statements, business and personal income and disbursement schedules, and tax returns; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any other information the Office considers necessary.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In considering whether to approve an application for a distributor's license, the Office may consider evidence the distributor submitted to the Office of an existing license as a distributor from another jurisdiction that the Office has determined has licensing requirements similar to those required by the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An applicant for a distributor's license shall demonstrate that the equipment, system, or device that the applicant plans to offer to retailers conforms to standards established pursuant to this title, rules issued pursuant to this title, and other applicable law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>An applicant for a distributor's license shall pay a nonrefundable application fee of $10,000 with the application.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A distributor's license shall be renewed annually; provided, that the licensee has continued to comply with all statutory and regulatory requirements and pays upon submission of its renewal application a $5,000 renewal fee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>A distributor shall submit to the Office, at such times as are established by the Office by rule, a list of all game of skill machines sold, delivered, or offered to a retailer.  All such equipment shall be tested and approved by an independent testing laboratory approved by the Office.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-05-03" doc="D.C. Law 22-312" eff="2019-05-03" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" codified:display="Note" app="2019-07-22" eff="2019-07-22" path="§7177" display="false">For temporary (90 days) amendment of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-312, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§7177">§ 7177 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019, 66 DCR 8497)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§7177" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" codified:display="Note" app="2019-09-04" eff="2019-09-04" path="§7177" display="false">For temporary (90 days) amendment of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-312, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§7177">§ 7177 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019, 66 DCR 11964)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§7177" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§6022|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§6022|(e)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
