<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>36-641.17</num>
  <heading>Authority of the Office.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Office may enforce the provisions of this title with respect to licensees and any individual or entity not holding a license and offering a game of skill machine in violation of the provisions of this title or rules issued pursuant to this title.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (c) of this section, the Office and the Metropolitan Police Department may issue citations for civil violations of this title as set forth in rules issued pursuant to this title.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A citation for a violation for which the penalty includes the suspension or revocation of a license shall be issued by the Office as a result of an investigation carried out by the Office.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Office may request and check the identification of a person who has played, is playing, or is attempting to play a game of skill machine. The Office may seize evidence that substantiates a violation under this title, which may include seizing the tickets, vouchers, or cash awards issued to a person under the age of 18 and fake identification documents used by a person under the age of 18.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Office may seize a game of skill machine license from an establishment if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The game of skill machine license has been suspended, revoked, or canceled by the Office;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The business is no longer in existence; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The business has been closed by another District government agency.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-05-03" doc="D.C. Law 22-312" eff="2019-05-03" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" codified:display="Note" app="2019-07-22" eff="2019-07-22" path="§7177" display="false">For temporary (90 days) amendment of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-312, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§7177">§ 7177 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019, 66 DCR 8497)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§7177" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" codified:display="Note" app="2019-09-04" eff="2019-09-04" path="§7177" display="false">For temporary (90 days) amendment of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-312, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§7177">§ 7177 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019, 66 DCR 11964)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§7177" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§6022|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§6022|(e)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
