<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>36-641.10</num>
  <heading>Minimum requirements of game of skill machines.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Every game of skill machine offered for play shall first be tested and approved pursuant to this title and rules issued pursuant to this title.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Office shall utilize the services of an accredited independent outside testing laboratory to test and assess each game of skill machine.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The applicant shall be responsible for paying the fees associated with testing the game of skill machines.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Every game of skill machine offered in the District shall meet the minimum standards approved by the Office, including that a game of skill machine:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Conform to all requirements of federal law and regulations, including the Federal Communications Commission's Class A emissions standards;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Pay out a mathematically demonstrable percentage during the expected lifetime of the machine of all amounts played, which shall not be less than 80%;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Display an accurate representation of the game outcome;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Not automatically alter pay tables or any function of the game of skill machine based on an internal computation of a hold percentage or have a means of manipulation that affects the random selection process or probabilities of winning a game;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Not be negatively affected by static discharge or other electromagnetic interference;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Be capable of displaying the following during idle status: "power reset"; "door open"; or "door closed";</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Be able to detect and display the game's complete play history and winnings for the previous 10 games;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Not have a theoretical payback percentage capable of being changed without making a hardware or software change in the machine itself;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Be designed so that the replacement of parts or modules required for normal maintenance does not necessitate replacement of the electromechanical meters;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Contain a non-resettable meter that shall be located in a locked area of the machine that is accessible only by a key;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Be capable of storing the meter information required by paragraph (10) of this subsection for a minimum of 180 days after a power loss to the machine;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>Have accounting software that keeps an electronic record that includes:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Total cash inserted into the game of skill machine;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The value of winning tickets awarded to players by the game of skill machine;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The total credits played on the game of skill machine;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The total credits awarded by the game of skill machine; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The payback percentage credited to players of the game of skill machine;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>Be linked to a centralized accounting system that will allow the Office to activate or deactivate the game of skill machine from the centralized system remotely; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>Be linked to a centralized accounting system in accordance with section 414 by which all approved game of skill machines shall be connected for the purposes set forth in section 414.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The CFO may issue rules to establish additional licensing and registration requirements.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-05-03" doc="D.C. Law 22-312" eff="2019-05-03" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" codified:display="Note" app="2019-07-22" eff="2019-07-22" path="§7177" display="false">For temporary (90 days) amendment of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-312, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§7177">§ 7177 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019, 66 DCR 8497)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§7177" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" codified:display="Note" app="2019-09-04" eff="2019-09-04" path="§7177" display="false">For temporary (90 days) amendment of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-312, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§7177">§ 7177 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019, 66 DCR 11964)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§7177" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§6022|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§6022|(e)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
