<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>36-641.09</num>
  <heading>Retailer licensure; registration of game of skill machines.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person may not own, lease, maintain, install, make available, or offer or allow another to play a game of skill machine in the District unless the person:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is a licensed establishment;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Possesses a retailer's license from the Office and a game of skill machine endorsement from ABRA in accordance with D.C. Official Code § 25-113.01(e); and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Has entered into a written use agreement with a licensed distributor for the placement or installation of a game of skill machine on the licensed premises.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A person convicted of violating this subsection shall be subject to a fine not to exceed $5,000 or imprisonment not to exceed 6 months, or revocation of the retailer's license, or all of the foregoing.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Each game of skill machine located on a retailer's licensed premises shall be registered with the Office by the retailer before the game of skill machine is installed on the licensed premises.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A retailer may register and operate up to 5 game of skill machines on the licensed premises at any time. The registration fee for each game of skill machine shall be $100.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Office shall issue to the retailer a registration sticker for placement on each registered game of skill machine.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person shall apply for a retailer's license on a form prescribed by the Office. The form shall require:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the applicant;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The mailing address of the applicant and, if the applicant is a corporation, the name of the state in which it is incorporated, the location of its principal place of business, and the names and addresses of its directors;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A report of the applicant's financial activities, including evidence of financial stability, such as bank statements, business and personal income and disbursement schedules, and tax returns; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any other information the Office considers necessary.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An applicant for a retailer's license shall pay a nonrefundable application fee of $300 with the application.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A retailer's license shall be renewed annually; provided, that the licensee continued to comply with the statutory and regulatory requirements and pays upon submission of its renewal application a $300 renewal fee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Office shall require a retailer to be bonded, in such amounts and in such manner as determined by the Office, and to agree, in writing, to indemnify and hold harmless the District government against any actions, claims, and demands of whatever kind or nature that the District may incur by reason of or in consequence of issuing the retailer's license to the retailer.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-05-03" doc="D.C. Law 22-312" eff="2019-05-03" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" codified:display="Note" app="2019-07-22" eff="2019-07-22" path="§7177" display="false">For temporary (90 days) amendment of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-312, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§7177">§ 7177 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019, 66 DCR 8497)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§7177" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" codified:display="Note" app="2019-09-04" eff="2019-09-04" path="§7177" display="false">For temporary (90 days) amendment of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-312, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§7177">§ 7177 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019, 66 DCR 11964)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§7177" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§6022|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§6022|(e)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
