<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>36-641.03</num>
  <heading>Game of skill machine license requirements; prohibition.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, no person may offer or allow a game of skill machine in the District unless all the licenses required by this title, or by a rule issued pursuant to this title, have been duly obtained.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Office shall issue the following categories of game of skill machine licenses:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Manufacturer;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Distributor;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Supplier; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Retailer.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Office shall not grant a license listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection until it has determined that each person that possesses 10% or greater beneficial or proprietary interest in the applicant has been approved for licensure in accordance with this title and rules issued pursuant to this title.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An applicant for an initial manufacturer, distributor, or supplier license shall be subject to District and national criminal history background checks.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The applicant shall submit an application to the Office, in a form determined by the Office, for fingerprints for a national criminal records check by the Metropolitan Police Department and the Federal Bureau of Investigation of all individuals required to be named in the application and a signed authorization of each individual submitting fingerprints for the release of information by the Metropolitan Police Department and the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In the case of an application for license renewal, the Office may require additional background checks.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Office shall require proof of good standing pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 29-102.08 of an applicant for a license pursuant to this title and may, in addition, require certification that the Citywide Clean Hands Database indicates that the proposed licensee is current with its District taxes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Proprietary information, trade secrets, financial information, and personal information about a person in an application submitted to the Office pursuant to this title shall not be a public record and shall not be made available under the Freedom of Information Act of 1976, effective March 29, 1977 (D.C. Law 1-96; D.C. Official Code § 2-531 <em>et seq</em>.), or any other law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A retailer shall display its license as required by section 411(d) and shall make the license immediately available for inspection upon request by an employee of the Office, the Metropolitan Police Department, or ABRA.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>When present at a licensed establishment, an employee of a distributor shall carry a copy of its license and make it readily available for inspection by an employee of the Office, the Metropolitan Police Department, or ABRA.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A licensed establishment that applied for and obtained a game of skill machine endorsement from the ABC Board pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 25-113.01(e) prior to the effective date of the Game of Skill Machines Consumer Protection Act of 2020, passed on 2nd reading on July 28, 2020 (Enrolled version of Bill 23-760) ("permanent legislation"), shall have 180 calendar days after the effective date of the permanent legislation to come into compliance with this title or rules issued pursuant to this title.  Failure to do so may result in the Office taking action against the licensed establishment in accordance with section 417.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-05-03" doc="D.C. Law 22-312" eff="2019-05-03" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" codified:display="Note" app="2019-07-22" eff="2019-07-22" path="§7177" display="false">For temporary (90 days) amendment of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-312, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§7177">§ 7177 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019, 66 DCR 8497)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§7177" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" codified:display="Note" app="2019-09-04" eff="2019-09-04" path="§7177" display="false">For temporary (90 days) amendment of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-312, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§7177">§ 7177 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019, 66 DCR 11964)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§7177" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§6022|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§6022|(e)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
