<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>36-641.04</num>
  <heading>License prohibitions; suspensions and revocation of licenses.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An applicant convicted of a disqualifying offense shall not be licensed. The Office shall define disqualifying offenses by a rule issued pursuant to <cite path="36|6|III">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No employee of the Office or ABRA or member of the ABC Board, or immediate family member of an employee of the Office or ABRA or member of the ABC Board, may be an applicant for, have an interest in, or obtain a license issued pursuant to <cite path="36|6|III">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Failure of an applicant or licensee to notify the Office of a change to the information provided in its application for license or renewal within 10 days after the change may result in the Office suspending or revoking the licensee's license, denying the applicant's license, and issuing a fine.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Office shall not grant a license pursuant to <cite path="36|6|III">this subchapter</cite>, and shall revoke a license previously granted, if evidence satisfactory to the Office exists that the applicant or licensee has:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Knowingly made a false statement of a material fact to the Office;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Had a license revoked by a governmental authority responsible for regulation of games of skill;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Been convicted of a felony and has not received a pardon or been released from parole or probation for at least 5 years; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Been convicted of a gambling-related offense or a theft or fraud offense.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Office may deny a license to an applicant or suspend or revoke a license of a licensee if the applicant or licensee:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Has not demonstrated, to the satisfaction of the Office, financial responsibility sufficient to adequately meet the requirement of the proposed activity;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Is not the true owner of the licensed business or has not disclosed the existence or identity of another individual or entity that has an ownership interest in the business; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Is an entity that sells more than 10% of a licensee's voting interests, more than 10% of the voting interests of an entity that controls the licensee, or sells a licensee's assets to an individual or entity not already determined by the Office to have met the qualifications of a licensee pursuant to <cite path="36|6|III">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-172" type="History" path="§404">Mar. 10, 1981, D.C. Law 3-172, § 404</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-05-03" doc="D.C. Law 22-312" eff="2019-05-03" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" codified:display="Note" app="2019-07-22" eff="2019-07-22" path="§7177" display="false">For temporary (90 days) amendment of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-312, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§7177">§ 7177 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019, 66 DCR 8497)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§7177" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" codified:display="Note" app="2019-09-04" eff="2019-09-04" path="§7177" display="false">For temporary (90 days) amendment of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-312, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§7177">§ 7177 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019, 66 DCR 11964)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§7177" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-479" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-04-27" eff="2020-10-01">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-479" path="§2|(b)">§ 2(b) of Revised Game of Skill Machines Consumer Protections Emergency Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Act 23-479, Oct. 1, 2020, 67 DCR 13284)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Act 23-479" eff="2020-10-01" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-16" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-04-27" eff="2021-02-26">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-16" path="§2|(b)">§ 2(b) of Revised Game of Skill Machines Consumer Protections Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-16, Feb. 26, 2021, 68 DCR 002559)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Act 24-16" eff="2021-02-26" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 23-257" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-04-27" eff="2021-03-16">For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-257" path="§2|(b)">§ 2(b) of Revised Game of Skill Machines Consumer Protections Temporary Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Law 23-257, Mar. 16, 2021, 67 DCR 13932)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-257" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-280" eff="2021-04-27" path="§7|(a)|(3)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-280" eff="2021-04-27" path="§7|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
