<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>36-641.14</num>
  <heading>Centralized accounting system.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 6 months after the effective date of the Game of Skill Machines Consumer Protection Act of 2020, passed on 2nd reading on July 28, 2020 (Enrolled version of Bill 23-760) ("permanent legislation"), the Office shall issue a solicitation to procure a centralized accounting system, which shall be administered by the Office and designed and operated to allow the monitoring and reading of all game of skill machines for the purpose of compliance with this title and rules issued pursuant to this title.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>When the Office is satisfied with the operation of the CAS, it shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Certify the effective status of the system; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Notify all retailers of the date by which the retailer's game of skill machines must be linked to the CAS.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A game of skill machine approved prior to the effective date of the permanent legislation shall be connected to the CAS within one year after notification pursuant to subsection (a)(2) of this section.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A game of skill machine approved on or after the effective date of the permanent legislation but prior to the deployment of the CAS shall be connected within 6 months after notification pursuant subsection (a)(2) of this section.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A game of skill machine approved after the effective date of the permanent legislation and after deployment of the CAS shall be connected to the CAS prior to operation of the game of skill machine.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>After a game of skill machine has been connected to the CAS, it shall remain connected as required by the Office.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All game of skill machines registered in the District shall be linked to the CAS for purposes of accounting, reporting, monitoring, and reading machine activities as provided for in this title or rules issued pursuant to this title.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The CAS shall not provide for the monitoring or reading of personal or financial information concerning patrons of game of skill machines.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Employees and agents of a contractor or subcontractor of the Office that is engaged in building, operating, maintaining, or contracting to build, operate, or maintain the CAS, and the immediate family members of such employees and agents, shall be prohibited from obtaining a license under this title.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Unless a retailer's license is canceled, suspended, or revoked, nothing in this section shall authorize the Office to limit or eliminate a registered game of skill from the CAS.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-05-03" doc="D.C. Law 22-312" eff="2019-05-03" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" codified:display="Note" app="2019-07-22" eff="2019-07-22" path="§7177" display="false">For temporary (90 days) amendment of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-312, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§7177">§ 7177 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019, 66 DCR 8497)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§7177" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" codified:display="Note" app="2019-09-04" eff="2019-09-04" path="§7177" display="false">For temporary (90 days) amendment of applicability provision of D.C. Law 22-312, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§7177">§ 7177 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019, 66 DCR 11964)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§7177" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§6022|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§6022|(e)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
