<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>34-3411.01</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on October 22, 2021.*
      </text>
  <heading>STAY DC Improvements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No later than August 9, 2021, the Stronger Together by Assisting You ("STAY DC") Program application portal shall allow housing providers to submit an application for emergency rental assistance on behalf of tenants with an electronic signature from the tenant for funding allocated to the District through section 501 of Division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2021, approved December 27, 2020 (134 Stat. 2069; 15 U.S.C. § 9058a ).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Applications submitted by housing providers under paragraph (1) shall meet all the requirements of section 501(f)(2) of Division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021, approved December 27, 2020 (134 Stat. 2069; 15 U.S.C. § 9058a(f)(2)), and applicable guidance issued by the United States Department of Treasury.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No later than August 9, 2021, the Mayor shall issue guidance outlining the circumstances in which STAY DC will cover arrearages for internet services provided to the rental unit and security deposits, consistent with U.S. Department of Treasury guidance. This guidance shall be posted on the STAY DC website.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Should additional time be necessary to implement the changes in this section, the Mayor shall notify the Council. For each specific improvement required by this section, the notice to Council shall include the reason more time is needed, and an estimate of the additional time needed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No later than August 9, 2021, the Mayor shall provide information related to the STAY DC program, including eligibility, instructions for application, benefits of enrolling, and any programmatic deadlines, via e-mail or another form of communication, to all individuals who have received benefits during the emergencies declared in the Declaration of Public Emergency (Mayor's Order 2020-045) together with the Declaration of Public Health Emergency (Mayor's Order 2020-046), declared on March 11, 2020, including any extension of those declared emergencies, from the following programs:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Unemployment insurance;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Emergency rental assistance;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Medicaid;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Program; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>DC Healthcare Alliance.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-3411.01" action="creation of this section" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§34-3411.01" codified:display="Note"/>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-3411.01" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§34-3411.01">
    <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on October 22, 2021.*
      </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-07-24" doc="D.C. Act 24-125" eff="2021-07-24" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-07-24" doc="D.C. Act 24-125" eff="2021-07-24" path="§4" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-07-24" doc="D.C. Act 24-125" eff="2021-07-24" path="§4" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-125" path="§4" codified:display="Note" app="2021-07-24" eff="2021-07-24">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-125" path="§4">§ 4 of Public Emergency Extension and Eviction and Utility Moratorium Phasing Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-125, July 24, 2021, 68 DCR 007342)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
