<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-2232</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
      </text>
  <heading>Reentry Housing and Services Program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Department of Housing and Community Development ("DHCD") shall establish a Reentry Housing and Services Program ("Program"), subject to available funding, to provide project-based assistance to a Community Housing Development for qualifying housing projects.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Program shall allocate project-based funds to produce and maintain new affordable housing units and subsidize the cost of monthly rent and on-site services for the target population at a qualifying housing project.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In Fiscal Year 2022 only, DHCD may use up to $174,000 of funds allocated for this project for administrative costs associated with implementing the Program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To be eligible, a qualifying housing project shall provide:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No fewer than 60 units of housing, which may include single room occupancy units;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>On-site services for the target population; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A preference for returning citizens as tenants.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The agency shall issue a request for proposals no later than January 31, 2022, and issue awards no later than July 1, 2022.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, pursuant to <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>, shall issue rules to implement the provisions of <cite path="42|22A">this chapter</cite>, including rules addressing:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The distribution of funds under this program; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The allocation of project-based funds pursuant to this section, including by combining funds under this program with other sources of funds for housing production and development.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, by resolution, within the 45-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง42-2232" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="ยง42-2232">
    <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
      </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="II" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="ยง2093" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="ยง2093" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
