<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-2071</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of <cite path="42|20B">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Board" means the executive and administrative entity, by whatever name denominated, designated in the organizing instruments of a common interest community to act for the unit owners' association in governing and maintaining the common interest community.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Common elements" means all portions of the common interest community other than the units and as defined in the organizing instruments of the common interest community.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Common interest community" means a residential condominium, residential cooperative, or other residential real property with respect to which a person, by virtue of the person's ownership of a parcel of real property, is obligated to pay property taxes or insurance premiums, or for maintenance, or improvement of other real property described in a recorded covenant that creates the common interest community.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"DHCD" means the Department of Housing and Community Development.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Green Communities standard" means criteria for the sustainable design, construction, and operation of healthy, energy-efficient, and environmentally responsible affordable housing established and published by Enterprise Community Partners.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"MFI" means the median family income for a household in the Washington Metropolitan Statistical Area as set forth in the periodic calculation provided by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development ("HUD"), adjusted for family size, without regard to any adjustments made by HUD for the purposes of the programs it administers.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="II" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="§2232" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§2232" codified:display="Note" app="2018-07-30" eff="2018-07-30">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§2232">§ 2232 of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-434, July 30, 2018, 65 DCR 8200)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" eff="2018-10-03" path="§2232" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§2232" codified:display="Note" app="2018-10-03" eff="2018-10-03">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§2232">§ 2232 of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-458, Oct. 3, 2018, 65 DCR 11212)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§2232" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
