<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-3502.01a</num>
  <heading>Powers and duties of the Chairperson of the Rental Housing Commission.</heading>
  <text>The Rental Housing Commission shall be headed by a Chairperson who shall be accountable and responsible for the fairness, impartiality, effectiveness, and efficiency of the Rental Housing Commission.</text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Chairperson shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Be the administrative head and personnel authority for the Rental Housing Commission;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Develop and implement a code of professional responsibility for members of the Rental Housing Commission;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Monitor the quality of administrative adjudication;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Issue and implement procedures, practices, and guidelines relating to the operations or responsibilities of the Rental Housing Commission;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Issue and transmit to the Mayor and the Council an annual report, not later than 90 days after the close of the first complete fiscal year of the Commission's operation as an independent agency, and each fiscal year thereafter, on the operations of the Rental Housing Commission; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Establish necessary or desirable standards and specialized training programs for members of the Rental Housing Commission;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Chairperson may:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Provide for, or require completion of, continuing education programs for members of the Rental Housing Commission and other employees of the Rental Housing Commission considered to be necessary or desirable;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Appoint, in accordance with applicable law and available funding, promote, discipline, and remove staff employed by the Rental Housing Commission, other than members of the Rental Housing Commission;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Develop and maintain a program for student interns and law clerks to gain experience at the Rental Housing Commission; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Exercise any other lawful authority to effectuate the purposes of <cite path="42|35">this chapter</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-10" type="History" path="ยง201a">July 17, 1985, D.C. Law 6-10, ยง 201a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-02-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-200" eff="2019-02-22" path="ยง2|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
