<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-3505.09</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by temporary legislation that will expire on October 27, 2021.*
      </text>
  <heading>Sealing of eviction court records.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court shall seal all court records relating to an eviction proceeding if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The eviction proceeding does not result in a judgment for possession in favor of the housing provider, 30 days after the final resolution of the eviction proceeding; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The eviction proceeding results in a judgement for possession in favor of the housing provider, 3 years after the final resolution of the eviction proceeding; except, that, if the tenant was the defendant in any additional eviction proceedings that resulted in judgment for possession in favor of the housing provider during the 3-year period after the final resolution of the first eviction proceeding, the court shall seal the court records of all such proceedings at the completion of a 3-year period in which the tenant is not a defendant in another eviction proceeding that resulted in judgment for possession in favor of the housing provider.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For court records relating to an eviction proceeding filed before March 11, 2020, the requirement of subsection (a) of this section shall apply as of January 1, 2021.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Superior Court may seal court records relating to an eviction proceeding at any time, upon motion by a tenant, if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The tenant demonstrates by a preponderance of the evidence that:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The housing provider brought the eviction proceeding because the tenant failed to pay an amount of $600 or less;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The tenant was evicted from a unit under a federal or District site-based housing assistance program or a federal or District tenant-based housing assistance program;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>The housing provider's initiation of eviction proceedings against the tenant was in violation of:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>Section <cite path="§42-3505.02">42-3505.02</cite>; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>Section <cite path="§2-1402.61">2-1402.61</cite>;</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>The housing provider failed to timely abate a violation of 14 DCMR § 100 <em>et seq.</em> or 12G DCMR § 100 <em>et seq.</em> in relation to the defendant tenant's rental unit;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>The housing provider initiated the eviction proceedings because of an incident that would constitute a defense to an action for possession under <cite path="§42-3505.01|(c-1)">§ 42-3505.01(c-1)</cite> or federal law pertaining to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>The parties entered into a settlement agreement that did not result in the housing provider recovering possession of the rental unit; or</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Superior Court determines that there are other grounds justifying such relief.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An order dismissing, granting, or denying a motion filed under this subsection shall be a final order for purposes of appeal.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A copy of an order issued under this subsection shall be provided to the tenant or his or her counsel.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A tenant may obtain a copy of an order issued under this subsection at any time from the Clerk of the Superior Court, upon proper identification, without a showing of need.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Records sealed under this section shall be opened only:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Upon written request of the tenant; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>On order of the Superior Court upon a showing of compelling need.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Superior Court shall not order the redaction of the tenant's name from any published opinion of the trial or appellate courts that refer to a record sealed under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-497" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2020-11-10">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-497" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of Fairness in Renting Emergency Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Act 23-497, Nov. 10, 2020, 67 DCR 13949)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Act 23-497" eff="2020-11-10" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-3" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-17" eff="2021-01-25">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-3" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of Fairness in Renting Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-3, Jan. 25, 2021, 68 DCR 001529)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-17" doc="D.C. Act 24-3" eff="2021-01-25" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-255" eff="2021-03-16" path="§4" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-255" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(c)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 23-255" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2021-03-16">For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-255" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of Fairness in Renting Temporary Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Law 23-255, Mar. 16, 2021, 67 DCR 13959)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-255" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
