<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>51-178</num>
  <heading>Payment of shared work benefits.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the weekly benefit for a participating employee shall be the product of the regular weekly unemployment compensation amount for a week of total unemployment multiplied by the percentage of reduction in the participating employee's usual weekly hours of work.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The shared work benefit for a participating employee who performs work for another employer during weeks covered by a shared work plan shall be calculated as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>If the combined hours of work in a week for both employers results in a reduction of less than 10% of the usual weekly hours of work the participating employee works for the shared work employer, the participating employee is not eligible for shared work benefits;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If the combined hours of work for both employers results in a reduction equal to or greater than 10% of the usual weekly hours worked for the shared work employer, the shared work benefit payable to the participating employee is determined by multiplying the weekly unemployment benefit amount for a week of total unemployment by the percentage by which the combined hours of work have been reduced. A week for which benefits are paid under this subparagraph shall be reported as a week of shared work benefits.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>If an individual worked the reduced percentage of the usual weekly hours of work for the shared work employer and is available for all the participating employee's usual hours of work with the shared work employer, and the participating employee did not work any hours for the other employer, either because of the lack of work with that employer or because the participating employee is excused from work with the other employer, the participating employee shall be eligible for the full value of the shared work benefit for that week.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-238" type="History" path="§9">Oct. 15, 2010, D.C. Law 18-238, § 9, 57 DCR 7181</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-10-09" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" eff="2020-10-09" path="§103|(g)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-09" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" eff="2020-10-09" path="§103|(g)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-09" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" eff="2020-10-09" path="§103|(g)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" path="§103|(g)" codified:display="Note" app="2020-10-09" eff="2020-10-09">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-130" path="§103|(g)">§ 103(g) of Coronavirus Support Temporary Amendment Act of 2020 [Effective from October 9, 2020] (D.C. Law 23-130, Oct. 9, 2020, 67 DCR 8622)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-10-09" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" eff="2020-10-09" path="§103|(g)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A participating employee who is not provided any work during a week by the shared work employer or any other employer and who is otherwise eligible for unemployment compensation shall be eligible for the amount of regular unemployment compensation to which the individual would otherwise be eligible.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A participating employee who is not provided any work by the shared work employer during a week, but who works for another employer and is otherwise eligible for unemployment compensation may be paid unemployment compensation for that week subject to the disqualifying income provision and other provisions applicable to claims for regular unemployment compensation.</text>
  </para>
</section>
