<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-1108.03</num>
  <heading>Notice requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Immediately after the application is filed for a permit for demolition pursuant to <cite path="§6-1104">§ 6-1104</cite>, alteration pursuant to <cite path="§6-1105">§ 6-1105</cite>, subdivision pursuant to <cite path="§6-1106">§ 6-1106</cite>, new construction pursuant to <cite path="§6-1107">§ 6-1107</cite>, preliminary review pursuant to <cite path="§6-1108|(a)">§ 6-1108(a)</cite>, or conceptual review pursuant to <cite path="§6-1108|(b)">§ 6-1108(b)</cite>, that will be submitted to the Historic Preservation Review Board or the Commission of Fine Arts for a public hearing, the applicant shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Post notice of the application on a form provided by the Mayor, in plain view of the public, at each street frontage on the property that is subject to review and on the front of each building located on the property that is subject to review; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Provide, by hand delivery with a delivery receipt or via the United States Postal Service with a certificate of mailing, to the owners of record of all confronting or abutting properties, excluding streets and alleys, and to all affected Advisory Neighborhood Commissions, the following:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Notice of the application;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Information regarding how to obtain the schedule for review by the Historic Preservation Review Board or the Commission of Fine Arts; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>A copy of the plans for the demolition, alteration, new construction on, or subdivision of, the property that is subject to review, or instructions on how to access the plans on a publicly available website or, upon request, for in-person viewing.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In the case of a residential condominium or cooperative with 25 or more dwelling units, notice by hand delivery with a delivery receipt or via the United States Postal Service with a certificate of mailing as required by subparagraph (A) of this paragraph may be provided to the board of directors or to the association of the condominium or cooperative that represents all of the owners of all of the dwelling units.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Before the Mayor approves a permit based on an application submitted to the Historic Preservation Review Board or the Commission of Fine Arts for a public hearing pursuant to <cite path="§6-1104">§ 6-1104</cite>, <cite path="§6-1105">§ 6-1105</cite>, <cite path="§6-1106">§ 6-1106</cite>, <cite path="§6-1107">§ 6-1107</cite>, or <cite path="§6-1108|(a)">§ 6-1108(a)</cite>, or before the Historic Preservation Review Board gives conceptual design approval pursuant to <cite path="§6-1108|(b)">§ 6-1108(b)</cite> for such an application, the Mayor shall require a certification by the owner that the requirements of subsection (a) of this section have been met.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall not approve a permit, and the Historic Preservation Review Board shall not grant conceptual design approval, pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection until 21 days have elapsed for citizen review of applications prior to the scheduling of a hearing, and following the date the Mayor receives the certification by the owner pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-144" type="History" path="§9c">March 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-144, §  9c</annotation>
    <annotation app="2015-04-30" doc="D.C. Law 20-249" eff="2015-04-30" path="§2|(f)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" path="§2|(f)" codified:display="Note" app="2015-04-30" eff="2015-04-30" doc="D.C. Law 20-249">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-249" path="">D.C. Law 20-249</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-249" path="§3">§ 3 of D.C. Law 20-249</cite> provided that the change made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-249" path="§2|(f)">§ 2(f) of D.C. Law 20-249</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2015-04-30" doc="D.C. Law 20-249" eff="2015-04-30" path="§2|(f)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§7005" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2016-10-08" eff="2016-10-08"><cite doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§7005">Section 7005 of D.C. Law 21-160</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-249" path="§3">§ 3 of D.C. Law 20-249</cite>. Therefore the changes made to this section by D.C. Law 20-249 have been given effect.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§7005" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
