<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-1331</num>
  <heading>Foreign-Government-Owned Real Property Task Force.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the Foreign-Government-Owned Real Property Task Force ("Task Force") with the purpose of serving as a collaborative body to address matters relating to real property, including all buildings located on such real property, owned by foreign governments or their instrumentalities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall meet on a quarterly basis to review and identify issues with real property owned by foreign governments or their instrumentalities to include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The tax status of such property;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The condition of such property; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Whether such property is in substantial compliance with District laws and regulations.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall consist of the following members:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Three Advisory Neighborhood Commissioners, each of whom shall be appointed by the Mayor from Advisory Neighborhood Commission ("ANC") 2B, ANC 2D, ANC 3C, or ANC 3F; provided, that no more than one Advisory Neighborhood Commissioner may be appointed from a single ANC;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, or the Director's designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Deputy Chief Financial Officer for the Office of Tax and Revenue, or the Deputy Chief Financial Officer's designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Department of Public Works, or the Director's designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Secretary of the District of Columbia, or the Secretary's designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The Chairman of the Council, or the Chairman's designee; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The Director of the United States Department of State's Office of Foreign Missions ("OFM"), or the Director's designee.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall designate one member of the Task Force to serve as its chairperson.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>On or before October 1 of each year, the Task Force shall submit to the Mayor, the Council, and OFM a report of its findings and recommendations to address the issues outlined in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall convene its first meeting no later than 90 days after March 22, 2019.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-254" eff="2019-03-22" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-254" eff="2019-03-22" path="ยง4" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
