<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-1431</num>
  <heading>DCRA housing and building infractions fine; periodic adjustments.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning on January 1, 2018, a fine amount listed in section 3201.1 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (16 DCMR § 3201.1), when assessed for an infraction listed in sections 3301 through 3313 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (16 DCMR § 3301 through 16 DCMR § 3313), shall be adjusted according to the most recent Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers in the Washington Metropolitan Statistical area, as published by the United States Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Beginning on or after January 1, 2018, and on or after January 1 of every year thereafter, there shall be published in the District of Columbia Register a schedule of the fine amounts for each infraction listed in sections 3301 through 3313 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (16 DCMR § 3301 through 16 DCMR § 3313), as adjusted according to the most recent Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers in the Washington Metropolitan Statistical area, as published by the United States Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-216" type="History" path="§11">Mar. 21, 1987, D.C. Law 6-216, § 11 [11a]</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="II" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§2222|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§2222|(b)" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2017-12-13" eff="2017-12-13">
          For temporary (90-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§2222|(b)">§ 2222(b) of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017, effective July 20, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104; 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§2222|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§2222|(b)" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2017-12-13" eff="2017-12-13">
          For temporary (90-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§2222|(b)">§ 2222(b) of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017, effective October 24, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167; 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.
        </annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
