<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-1451.07</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section has been amended by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
      </text>
  <heading>Green Building Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Green Building Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Mayor in accordance with subsection (c) of this section. The purpose of the Fund is to streamline administrative green building processes, improve sustainability performance outcomes, build capacity of development and administrative oversight professionals in green building skills and knowledge, institutionalize innovation, overcome barriers to achieving high-performance buildings, and continuously promote the sustainability of green building practices in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Monies obtained pursuant to sections 6 and 9 shall be deposited into the Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used for the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The following amounts shall be transferred to the Sustainable Energy Trust Fund ("SETF") established by <cite path="§8-1774.10">§ 8-1774.10</cite>:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>For each of Fiscal Years 2022, 2023, 2024, and 2025, a minimum of $900,000; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For each fiscal year thereafter, 50% of monies in the Fund; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Costs for at least 3 full-time employees at DCRA, or elsewhere as assigned by the Mayor, whose primary job duties are devoted to technical assistance, plan review, and inspections and monitoring of green buildings;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Additional staff and operating costs to provide training, technical assistance, plan review, inspections and monitoring of green buildings, and green codes development;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Research and development of green building practices;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Education, training, outreach, and other market transformation initiatives;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Seed support for demonstration projects, their evaluation, and when successful, their institutionalization; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Costs incurred to make green building materials accessible to low-income residents.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund but not expended in a fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may receive and administer grants for the purpose of carrying out the goals of <cite path="6|14A">this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-234" type="History" path="§8">Mar. 8, 2007, D.C. Law 16-234, § 8, 54 DCR 377</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-139" type="History">June 5, 2012, D.C. Law 19-139, § 2(f), 59 DCR 2555</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(3) Incentive funding for private buildings as provided for in <cite path="§6-1451.06">§ 6-1451.06</cite>.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) Education, training and outreach to the public and private sectors on green building practices; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(1) Staffing and operating costs to provide technical assistance, plan review, and inspections and monitoring of green buildings;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(c) The Fund shall be used as follows:”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-139">D.C. Law 19-139</cite> rewrote subsec. (c), which formerly read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§6-1451.01">§ 6-1451.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="§6012|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="§6012|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="§6012|(c)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§6122" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§6122" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§6122" codified:display="Note" app="2021-08-23" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§6122">§ 6122 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
