<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-229.02</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
      </text>
  <heading>Rent Supplement Program Project-Based Allocation Fund quarterly reporting.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Department of Housing and Community Development shall submit to the Council, within 30 days after the end of each fiscal quarter, a Project-Based Rent Supplement Program report.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each report shall include the following information with respect to the Rent Supplement Program Project-Based Allocation Fund:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The total amount of money in the fund at the beginning and end of the reporting period;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The amount of money in the fund transferred to the Authority for project-based voucher assistance during the reporting period, listed separately by the project for which the funds were awarded;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The amount of money in the fund awarded to projects that do not yet have a certificate of occupancy, listed separately by project;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>For each project that has been awarded project-based voucher assistance, the developer, address, planned number of total housing units, planned number of units subsidized by project-based voucher assistance, planned period of project-based voucher assistance, date of award, expected completion date, and whether the project is new construction or existing housing rehabilitation or preservation; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The amount of money expended from the fund during the reporting period on administrative costs, which shall contain a breakdown by category of expense.</text>
    </para>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§6-229.02" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§6-229.02">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-105" type="History" path="§26d-2" display="false">May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-105, § 26d-2</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-105" type="History" path="§26d-2">May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-105, § 26d-2</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§2042|(f)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§2042|(f)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
