<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-271</num>
  <heading>Expenditures from the Public Housing and Structural Transformation capital account.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Capital project DHA21C ("DHA21C") shall be administered by the Office of the Chief Financial Officer ("OCFO"), with available project allotments advanced to the District of Columbia Housing Authority ("Authority") on a quarterly basis for the encumbrances and expenditures planned for that quarter; provided, that the requirements of subsection (b) of this section are met.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>DHA21C funds shall be used by the Authority to fund capital-eligible construction, renovation, or rehabilitation subprojects that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Increase the longevity of public housing units;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Prevent existing tenants from being displaced; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Increase the availability of public housing units for existing District of Columbia residents listed on the Authority's waitlist.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>DHA21C funds shall not be used to fund the Authority's operating costs, renovation, or rehabilitation of any unit set to be demolished, sold, or otherwise removed from the Authority inventory, or any administrative or overhead costs not specifically attributable to a subproject.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Each fiscal year that DHA21C funds are available, the Authority shall submit to the Mayor, the Council, and the OCFO a proposed spending plan, which shall include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Documentation that planned encumbrances and expenditures are capital eligible; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Information on each subproject for which the Authority proposes to use DHA21C funds, including, at a minimum:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The proposed location of the subproject;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>A detailed proposed scope of the subproject;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>A detailed proposed line-item budget for the subproject;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>A detailed proposed timeline for the subproject; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>A statement of whether the implementation of the proposed subproject will require the relocation of tenants and, if relocation is required, a detailed proposed relocation plan.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In the event of significant delays or changes in planned encumbrances and expenditures for any subproject during the fiscal year, the Authority shall update its spending plan and provide additional documentation as needed to minimize unencumbered and unexpended transfers, avoid causing the District to incur unnecessary debt service costs, and ensure that all subproject encumbrances and expenditures are capital eligible.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For each solicitation of a contract valued at $100,000 or more that is funded with money from capital project DHA21C, the Authority shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Award preferences to certified business enterprises as provided in <cite path="§2-218.43">§ 2-218.43</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Exercise its contracting and procurement authority for contracts funded by capital project DHA21C so as to meet, on an annual basis, the goals of procuring and contracting at least 50% of the dollar volume of such contracts ("CBE dollar volume") with certified business enterprises and at least 50% of the CBE dollar volume with small business enterprises.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>"Certified business enterprise" shall have the meaning set forth in <cite path="§2-218.02|(1D)">§ 2-218.02(1D)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>"Small business enterprise" shall have the meaning set forth in <cite path="§2-218.02|(16)">§ 2-218.02(16)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-416" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2020-12-05" eff="2020-10-01">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-416" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Fiscal Year 2021 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Act 23-416, Oct. 1, 2020, 67 DCR 12245)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-05" doc="D.C. Act 23-416" eff="2020-10-01" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="II" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="§2192" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-554" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2020-12-22" eff="2020-12-22">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-554" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Fiscal Year 2021 Budget Support Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Act 23-554, Dec. 22, 2020, 68 DCR 00130)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-554" eff="2020-12-22" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 23-176" path="§2|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2020-12-23" eff="2020-12-23">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-176" path="§2|(a)">§ 2(a) of Fiscal Year 2021 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Law 23-176, Dec. 23, 2020, 67 DCR 13036)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-23" doc="D.C. Law 23-176" eff="2020-12-23" path="§2|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 23-264" path="§3|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2021-03-16">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-264" path="§3|(b)">§ 3(b) of Fiscal Year 2021 Budget Support Additional Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Law 23-264, Mar. 16, 2021, 68 DCR 00005)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-264" eff="2021-03-16" path="§3|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 23-264" path="§4|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2021-03-16">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-264" path="§4|(b)">§ 4(b) of Fiscal Year 2021 Budget Support Additional Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Law 23-264, Mar. 16, 2021, 68 DCR 00005)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-264" eff="2021-03-16" path="§4|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-280" eff="2021-04-27" path="§2|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-280" eff="2021-04-27" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
