<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>6-623.02</num>
  <heading>Office of Zoning — Director and staff; appointment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Office of Zoning shall consist of a Director and other staff as the Zoning Commission considers necessary.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Director of the Office of Zoning shall be appointed by the District members of the Zoning Commission and shall serve as an excepted service employee in accordance with <cite path="§1-609.01">§ 1-609.01</cite>. The Director shall be a District resident throughout his or her term and failure to maintain District residency shall result in a forfeiture of the position.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of <cite path="2|14|A">Unit A of Chapter 14 of Title 2</cite>, the Director shall use a ranking system based on a scale of 100 points for all employment decisions for all positions within the Office.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An individual who is a District resident at the time of application shall be awarded a 10-point hiring preference over a nonresident applicant; provided, that the individual claims the preference. This 10-point preference shall be in addition to any points awarded on the 100-point scale.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>At the time of appointment, an individual who claimed the 10-point residency preference shall agree, in writing, to maintain District residency for a period of 7 consecutive years from the effective date of appointment into the position for which the individual claimed the residency preference.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>An individual who claimed the residency preference and who fails to maintain District residency for 7 consecutive years from the individual's effective date of appointment shall forfeit the individual's District government employment.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Each applicant for a position covered by this paragraph shall be informed in writing of the provisions of this paragraph at the time of application.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>The Director shall verify and enforce District residency requirements pursuant to <cite path="§1-515.04">§ 1-515.04</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The District members of the Zoning Commission shall verify and enforce residency requirements applicable to the Director pursuant to <cite path="§1-515.04">§ 1-515.04</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>By November 1 of each year and pursuant to <cite path="§1-515.06">§ 1-515.06</cite>, the Director shall submit to the Mayor an annual report detailing, for the previous fiscal year, compliance with residency requirements.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>By November 1 of each year and pursuant to <cite path="§1-515.06">§ 1-515.06</cite>, the District members of the Zoning Commission shall submit to the Mayor an annual report detailing for the previous fiscal year the Director's compliance with residency requirements.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-163" type="History" path="§3">Sept. 20, 1990, D.C. Law 8-163, § 3, 37 DCR 4676</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-108" type="History">Feb. 6, 2008, D.C. Law 17-108, § 209, 54 DCR 10993</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section effective October 1, 1991: Section 7(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-163">D.C. Law 8-163</cite> provided that the provisions of the act shall not apply until October 1, 1991.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-108">D.C. Law 17-108</cite> rewrote the section which had read as follows: “The Office of Zoning shall consist of a Director and other staff as the Zoning Commission deems necessary, subject to appropriations. The Director of the Office of Zoning shall be appointed by the District members of the Zoning Commission and shall serve as an excepted service employee in accordance with <cite path="§1-609.01">§ 1-609.01</cite>.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-412.2.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§8" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
