<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-751.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of 
            <cite path="6|7|IV">this subchapter</cite>, the term:
          </text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Construction Codes" means the most recent edition of the codes published by the International Code Council, or by a comparable nationally recognized and accepted code development organization, as adopted and amended by the Construction Codes Supplement by the District of Columbia pursuant to the procedures set forth in <cite path="§6-1409">§ 6-1409</cite>, and in Title 12 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, or any successor regulations.
            </text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Construction Codes Supplement" means the additions, insertions, deletions, and changes to the Model Codes adopted by the District pursuant to 
              <cite path="§6-1409">§ 6-1409</cite>.
            </text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Dwelling unit" means a structure, building, area, room, or combination of rooms occupied by a person for sleeping or living.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>"Owner" means any person, who alone or jointly or severally with other persons, has legal title to a premises, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>An agent, officer, fiduciary, or employee of the owner;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>The committee, conservator, or legal guardian of an owner who is non compos mentis or otherwise under a disability or who is a minor;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>A trustee, elected or appointed, or a person required by law to execute a trust, other than a trustee under a deed of trust, to secure the payment of money; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>An executor, administrator, receiver, fiduciary, or an officer appointed by a court, or other similar representative of the owner or the owner’s estate.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The term "owner" does not include a lessee, sublessee, or other person who merely has the right to occupy or possess a premises.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-81" type="History" path="§2">June 20, 1978, D.C. Law 2-81, § 2, 24 DCR 9050</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-84" type="History">Mar. 9, 1988, D.C. Law 7-84, § 2(a), 34 DCR 8122</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305" type="History">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 20, 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-169" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-169, § 14, 59 DCR 5567</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 35 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> provided that no provision of the act shall impair any right or obligation existing under law.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-169">D.C. Law 19-169</cite> substituted “intellectual disabilities” for “mental retardation” in (5)(B).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite>, in par. (5)(B), substituted “persons with mental retardation” for “the mentally retarded”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-328.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-529.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-05-18" doc="D.C. Law 21-118" eff="2016-05-18" path="§2|(a)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
