<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-803</num>
  <heading>Unsafe structure or excavation -- Failure of owner to make safe.</heading>
  <text>Whenever a responsible party to whom notice has been provided pursuant to 
            <cite path="§6-801|(d)">§ 6-801(d)</cite> refuses or neglects to abate the unsafe structure or excavation within the time period specified by the notice, upon expiration of that time period, the Mayor shall proceed to make the structure or excavation safe as authorized by 
            <cite path="§6-801|(d)|(2)">§ 6-801(d)(2)</cite>, and the responsible party shall not enter, or send anyone to enter, the premises to:
          </text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Make repairs;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Remove or take down the structure; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Interfere in any way with the authorized agents of the District taking action to make the structure or excavation safe, including by removing or taking down the structure, without first having obtained the written consent of the Mayor to enter the premises.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 55-3-ch323" path="§3">Mar. 1, 1899, 30 Stat. 923, ch. 323, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Apr. 5, 1935, 49 Stat. 106, ch. 41</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-486" type="History">Aug. 22, 1964, 78 Stat. 599, Pub. L. 88-486, §§ 1, 3</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-281" type="History">Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-281, § 102(c), 48 DCR 1888</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-114" type="History">Apr. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-114, § 102, 49 DCR 1468</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-213" type="History">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-213, § 12(2), 49 DCR 8140</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.11">§ 1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.14|(a)">§ 1-207.14(a)</cite>), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-213">D.C. Law 14-213</cite> validated previously made technical corrections.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-114">D.C. Law 14-114</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “structure, except for a deteriorated structure under <cite path="42|31C|II">subchapter II of Chapter 31C of Title 42</cite>, or excavation,” for “structure or excavation,”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-281">D.C. Law 13-281</cite> designated subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 5-503.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 5-603.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§6-806">§ 6-806</cite> and <cite path="§47-1205">§ 47-1205</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-05-18" doc="D.C. Law 21-118" eff="2016-05-18" path="§3|(c)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
