<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="D.C. Law 14-309" doc-type="dclaw" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify">
  <num type="law">14-309</num>
  <heading type="short">Urban Forest Preservation Act of 2002</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2003-06-12</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-309.pdf">D.C. Law 14-309</citation>
      <citation type="register">50 DCR 888</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B14-0307">
      <narrative>Law 14-309, the “Urban Forest Preservation Act of 2002”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-307, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works and the Environment. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 3, 2002, and December 17, 2002, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 22, 2003, it was assigned Act No. 14-614 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-309 became effective on June 12, 2003.</narrative>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>I</num>
    <heading>Urban Forest Preservation.</heading>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="8|6B" />
    <section>
      <num>101</num>
      <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-651.01" />
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>102</num>
      <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-651.02" />
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>103</num>
      <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-651.03" />
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>104</num>
      <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-651.04" />
    </section>
    <section>
      <codify:organic after="§8-651.04" num-value="8-651.04a" />
      <reason>Not Funded</reason>
      <num>104a</num>
      <heading>Protection of Heritage Trees.</heading>
      <text>[Not Funded].</text>
      <annotation app="notfunded" doc="D.C. Law 21-133" eff="2016-07-01" path="§2|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History" />
      <annotation type="Editor's Notes" path="§104a" app="2016-07-01" eff="2016-07-01">
       Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-133" path="">D.C. Law 21-133</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-133" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 21-133</cite> provided that the change made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-133" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of D.C. Law 21-133</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been given effect.
      </annotation>
      <annotation app="2016-07-01" doc="D.C. Law 21-133" eff="2016-07-01" path="§2|(c)" type="History" />
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>105</num>
      <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-651.05" />
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>106</num>
      <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-651.06" />
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>107</num>
      <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-651.07" />
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>108</num>
      <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-651.08" />
    </section>
    <section>
      <codify:organic num-value="8-651.09" />
      <num>109</num>
      <heading>Urban Forestry Advisory Council.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>There is established an Urban Forestry Advisory Council ("UFAC").</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>The UFAC shall be composed of 12 members, as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The Director of the District Department of Transportation, or the Director's designee;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The Director of the District Department of the Environment, or the Director's designee;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>The Director of the Department of Parks and Recreation, or the Director's designee;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>The Director of the Department of General Services, or the Director's designee;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>The General Manager of District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority, or the General Manager's designee;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>A representative of the U.S. National Park Service;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>A representative of the U.S. General Services Administration;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>A representative of the District's electric utility;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>Three community representatives appointed by the Mayor knowledgeable in the fields of urban forestry, public policy, environmental protection, public administration, or environmental justice and equity; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>One community representative appointed by the Chairperson of the Council committee with oversight of the District Department of the Environment.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The community representatives shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, with initial staggered appointments of one community representative appointed for one year, 2 community representatives appointed for 2 years, and one community representative appointed for 3 years. The community representative to serve the one-year term, the community representatives to serve the 2-year term, and the community representative to serve the 3-year term shall be determined by lot at the first meeting of the UFAC.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment to the position that became vacant. Community representatives who are appointed to fill vacancies that occur before the expiration of a community representative's full term shall serve only the unexpired portion of the community representative's term.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>The UFAC shall be co-chaired by the Director of the District Department of Transportation and the Director of the District Department of the Environment, or their designees. The UFAC may designate other officers and create temporary, ad-hoc committees as necessary.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The UFAC shall hold at least 3 meetings per year.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The UFAC shall conduct its meetings in compliance with <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 90-614" path="IV">the Open Meetings Amendment Act of 2010, effective March 31, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-350; D.C. Official Code § 2-571 <em>et seq.</em>)</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(f)</num>
        <text>The purpose of the UFAC shall be to:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Ensure coordination between the District agencies responsible for achieving the District's tree canopy goals and partners engaged in programs and activities geared toward achieving those goals.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Advise District agencies responsible for achieving the District's tree canopy goals regarding policies, programs, and partnerships for the purpose of maintaining, protecting, and increasing the District's tree canopy; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Provide input on the 5-year urban forest report and master plan required by <code-cite path="§103|(c)" doc="D.C. Law 14-309">section 103(c)</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(g)</num>
        <text>The District Department of Transportation and the District Department of the Environment shall provide the UFAC with an annual operating budget, which shall include funds to maintain a website where the UFAC shall provide a public listing of members, meeting notices, and meeting minutes.</text>
      </para>
      <annotation app="2016-07-01" doc="D.C. Law 21-133" eff="2016-07-01" path="§2|(e)" prefix="as added" type="History" />
    </section>
  </container>
</document>