<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-2351.10</num>
  <heading>Enforcement provisions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may conduct examinations of providers, administrators, insurers, or other persons to enforce the provisions of <cite path="31|23M">this chapter</cite> and protect service contract holders in the District. Upon request of the Commissioner, the provider shall make all accounts, books, and records concerning a service contract sold by the provider available to the Commissioner that the Commissioner considers necessary to enable the Commissioner to reasonably determine compliance or noncompliance with <cite path="31|23M">this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Commissioner may take action that is necessary or appropriate to enforce the provisions of <cite path="31|23M">this chapter</cite> and regulations and orders issued pursuant to <cite path="31|23M">this chapter</cite>, and to protect service contract holders in the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a provider has violated <cite path="31|23M">this chapter</cite> or a regulation or order issued pursuant to <cite path="31|23M">this chapter</cite>, the Commissioner may issue an order, or any combination of the following, that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Orders the provider to cease and desist from committing the violation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Prohibits the provider from selling or offering for sale service contracts in violation of <cite path="31|23M">this chapter</cite> or a regulation or order issued pursuant to <cite path="31|23M">this chapter</cite>; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Imposes a civil penalty on the provider.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person aggrieved by a Commissioner's order issued pursuant to this subsection may request a hearing before the Commissioner; provided, that the request for a hearing shall be filed with the Commissioner within 20 days after the effective date of the Commissioner's order.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a hearing is timely requested, the order at issue shall be suspended until completion of the hearing and a final decision of the Commissioner.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>At the hearing, the burden shall be on the Commissioner to show why the order issued pursuant to this subsection is justified.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The hearing shall be conducted according to the rules established in Subtitle A of Chapter 38 of Title 26 of the District of Columbia Municipal Rules (26 DCMR A3800 <em>et seq.</em>).</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may bring an action in any court of competent jurisdiction for an injunction or other appropriate relief for a violation of <cite path="31|23M">this chapter</cite> or a regulation or order issued pursuant to <cite path="31|23M">this chapter</cite>. An action filed under this section may also seek restitution on behalf of a person aggrieved by a violation of <cite path="31|23M">this chapter</cite> or a regulation or order issued pursuant to <cite path="31|23M">this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person who is found to have violated <cite path="31|23M">this chapter</cite> or a regulation or order issued pursuant to <cite path="31|23M">this chapter</cite> may be assessed a civil penalty in an amount determined by the Commissioner of not more than $500 per violation and no more than $10,000 in the aggregate for all violations of a similar nature.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For purposes of this subsection, violations are of a similar nature if the violation consists of the same or similar course of conduct, action, or practice.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-02-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-216" eff="2019-02-22" path="ยง11" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
