<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-2361.09</num>
  <heading>Payment to appraisers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An appraisal management company shall, except in bona fide cases of breach of contract or substandard performance of services, make payment to an independent appraiser for the completion of an appraisal or valuation assignment no later than 45 days after the date on which the appraiser transmits or otherwise provides the completed appraisal or valuation assignment to the company or its assignee unless a mutually agreed-upon alternate arrangement previously has been established.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An appraisal management company seeking to be registered or to renew an existing registration in the District shall certify that the company will require appraisals to be conducted independently as required by the appraisal independence standards under section 129E of the Truth in Lending Act, approved July 21, 2010 (124 Stat. 2187; 15 U.S.C. § 1639e), including the requirement that a customary and reasonable fee be paid to an independent appraiser who completes an appraisal in connection with a consumer credit transaction secured by a principal dwelling.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-110" path="§109" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2019-07-31">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-110" path="§109">§ 109 of Appraisal Management Company Regulation Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-110, July 31, 2019, 66 DCR 178)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Act 23-110" eff="2019-07-31" path="§109" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-20" doc="D.C. Law 23-135" eff="2020-10-20" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 23-140" path="§109" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2020-10-20">For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-140" path="§109">§ 109 of Appraisal Management Company Regulation Temporary Act of 2020 (D.C. Law 23-140, Oct. 20, 2020, 67 DCR 9891)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-140" eff="2020-10-20" path="§109" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-206" eff="2021-03-16" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-206" eff="2021-03-16" path="§109" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
