<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-2361.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For purposes of <cite path="31|23R">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Affiliate" means any company that controls, is controlled by, or is under common control of another company.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"AMC National Registry" means the registry of state-registered appraisal management companies and federally regulated appraisal management companies maintained by the Appraisal Subcommittee.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Appraisal Foundation" means the Appraisal Foundation established on November 30, 1987, as a not-for-profit corporation under the laws of Illinois.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Appraisal management company" means a person, not including a department or division of an entity that provides appraisal management services only to that entity, that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Provides appraisal management services to creditors or to secondary mortgage market participants, including affiliates; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Provides appraisal management services in connection with valuing a consumer's principal dwelling as security for a consumer credit transaction or incorporating such transactions into securitizations; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>At any time in a 12-calendar month period oversees an appraiser panel of more than 15 state-certified or state-licensed appraisers in a state or 25 or more state-certified or state-licensed appraisers in 2 or more states, as described in <cite path="§31-2361.03">§ 31-2361.03</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Appraisal management services" means one or more of the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Recruiting, selecting, and retaining appraisers;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Contracting with state-certified or state-licensed appraisers to perform appraisal assignments;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Managing the process of having an appraisal performed, including providing administrative services such as receiving appraisal orders and appraisal reports, submitting completed appraisal reports to creditors and secondary market participants, collecting fees from creditors and secondary market participants for services provided, and paying appraisers for services performed; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Reviewing and verifying the work of appraisers.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>"Appraisal panel" means a network, list, or roster of licensed or certified appraisers approved by an appraisal management company to perform appraisals as independent contractors for the appraisal management company.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Appraisers on an appraiser panel include both appraisers accepted by the appraisal management company for consideration for future appraisal assignments in covered transactions or for secondary mortgage market participants in connection with covered transactions, and appraisers engaged by the appraisal management company to perform one or more appraisals in covered transactions or for secondary mortgage market participants in connection with covered transactions.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>An appraiser is an independent contractor or if the appraiser is treated as an independent contractor by the appraisal management company for purposes of federal income taxation.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Appraisal review" means the act or process of developing and communicating an opinion about the quality of another appraiser's work that was performed as part of an appraisal assignment and is related to the appraiser's data collection, analysis, opinions, conclusions, estimate of value, or compliance with the uniform standards of professional appraisal practice.  This term does not include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A general examination for grammatical, typographical, or other similar errors; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A general examination for completeness, including regulatory or client requirements as specified in the agreement process that does not communicate an opinion of value.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Appraisal Subcommittee" means the Appraisal Subcommittee of the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Consumer credit" means credit offered or extended to a consumer primarily for personal, family, or household purposes.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Controlling person" means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An officer, director, or owner of greater than a 10% interest of a corporation, partnership, or other business entity seeking to act as an appraisal management company;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An individual employed, appointed, or authorized by an appraisal management company that has the authority to enter a contractual relationship with other persons for the performance of services requiring registration as an appraisal management company and has the authority to enter agreements with appraisers for the performance of appraisals; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>An individual who possesses, directly or indirectly, the power to direct or cause the direction of the management of policies of an appraisal management company.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Covered transaction" means any consumer credit transaction secured by the consumer's principal dwelling.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>"Creditor" means a person who regularly extends consumer credit that is subject to a finance charge or is payable by written agreement in more than 4 installments (not including a down payment), and to whom the obligation is initially payable, either on the face of the note or contract, or by agreement when there is no note or contract.  A person regularly extends consumer credit if, in any 12-month period, the person originates more than one credit extension for transactions secured by a dwelling.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>"Department" means the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>"Dwelling" means a residential structure that contains one to 4 units, regardless of whether that structure is attached to real property.  The term includes an individual condominium unit, cooperative unit, mobile home, and trailer, if it is used as a residence.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>"Federal financial institutions regulatory agency" includes the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, and the National Credit Union Administration.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>"Federally regulated appraisal management company" means an appraisal management company that is owned and controlled by an insured depository institution, as defined in section 3(c)(2) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, approved September 21, 1950 (64 Stat. 873; 12 U.S.C. § 1813(c)(2)), and regulated by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, or the National Credit Union Administration.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(17)</num>
      <text>"Federally regulated transaction regulations" means regulations established by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, or the National Credit Union Administration, pursuant to sections 1112, 1113, and 1114 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989, approved August 9, 1989 (103 Stat. 183; 12 U.S.C. §§ 3341-3343).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(18)</num>
      <text>"Federally related transaction" means any real-estate-related financial transaction that involves an insured depository institution regulated by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, or National Credit Union Administration and that requires the services of an appraiser under the interagency appraisal rules.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(19)</num>
      <text>"Person" means a natural person or an organization, including a corporation, partnership, proprietorship, association, cooperative, estate, trust, or government unit.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(20)</num>
      <text>"Principal dwelling" means the primary residence of a consumer.  For purposes of <cite path="31|23R">this chapter</cite>, a consumer may only have one principal dwelling.  A vacation or other second home shall not be considered a principal dwelling.  However, if a consumer buys or builds a new dwelling that will become the consumer's primary residence within one year or upon completion of the construction, the new residence shall be considered the principal dwelling for purposes of <cite path="31|23R">this chapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(21)</num>
      <text>"Real-estate-related financial transaction" means any transaction involving the sale, lease, purchase, investment in, or exchange of real property, including interests in property or the financing thereof, the refinancing of real property or interests in real property, or the use of real property or interests in property as security for a loan or investment, including mortgage-backed securities.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(22)</num>
      <text>"Secondary mortgage market participant" means a guarantor or insurer of mortgage-backed securities, or an underwriter or issuer of mortgage-backed securities.  The term includes an individual investor in a mortgage-backed security only if that investor also serves in the capacity of a guarantor, insurer, underwriter, or issuer for the mortgage-backed security.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(23)</num>
      <text>"State" includes the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>[(24)]</num>
      <text>"Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice" or "USPAP" means the appraisal standards as promulgated by the Appraisal Standards Board of the Appraisal Foundation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-110" path="§101" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2019-07-31">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-110" path="§101">§ 101 of Appraisal Management Company Regulation Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-110, July 31, 2019, 66 DCR 178)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Act 23-110" eff="2019-07-31" path="§101" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-20" doc="D.C. Law 23-135" eff="2020-10-20" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 23-140" path="§101" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2020-10-20">For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-140" path="§101">§ 101 of Appraisal Management Company Regulation Temporary Act of 2020 (D.C. Law 23-140, Oct. 20, 2020, 67 DCR 9891)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-140" eff="2020-10-20" path="§101" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-206" eff="2021-03-16" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-206" eff="2021-03-16" path="§101" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
