<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-2802</num>
  <heading>Covered services.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All health insurers, hospitals or medical services corporations, and health maintenance organizations shall reimburse for emergency services that are due to a medical emergency.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Reimbursement for pre-hospital medical care and transport delivered pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection by the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department ("Department") or a third party contracted by the District to provide such services pursuant to <cite path="§5-401|(b)">§ 5-401(b)</cite>, shall be at the fee rate authorized by the Council pursuant to <cite path="§5-416|(a)">§ 5-416(a)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>This subsection shall not apply to any group health plan or multiple employer welfare arrangement to the extent the plan or arrangement is not subject to state insurance regulation under section 514 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, approved September 2, 1974 (88 Stat. 897; 29 U.S.C. § 1144).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A hospital emergency department or emergency medical service transporter shall provide a health insurer, hospital or medical services corporation, or health maintenance organization with any claim for reimbursement of services, and information on the presenting symptoms of the insured as well as the services provided.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A health insurer, hospital or medical services corporation, or health maintenance organization shall consider both the presenting symptoms and the services provided in processing a claim for reimbursement of emergency services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A health insurer, hospital or medical services corporation, or health maintenance organization may not deny reimbursement, except for co-payments, deductibles, and co-insurance, for the provision of emergency services that are due to a medical emergency solely because the member failed to obtain pre-authorization for emergency services from the health insurer, hospital or medical services corporation, or health maintenance organization.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-145" type="History" path="§3">Sept. 11, 1998, D.C. Law 12-145, § 3, 45 DCR 3785</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-4802.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§3022" codified:display="Note" app="2017-07-20" eff="2017-07-20">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§3022">§ 3022 of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104, July 20, 2017, 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-07-20" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" eff="2017-07-20" path="§3022" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§3022" codified:display="Note" app="2017-10-24" eff="2017-10-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§3022">§ 3022 of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167, Oct. 24, 2017, 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-10-24" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" eff="2017-10-24" path="§3022" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§3022|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§3022|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation codify:doc="D.C. Code" path="§3022" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2017-12-13" eff="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33"><cite doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§3024">Section 3024 of D.C. Law 22-33</cite> provided that the amendments made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§3022">section 3022 of D.C. Law 22-33</cite> shall apply to all health benefit plans issued or renewed in the District 90 or more days after December 13, 2017.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§3022" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-20" doc="D.C. Law 23-135" eff="2020-10-20" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
