<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-2361.05</num>
  <heading>Reporting requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Department shall collect from each appraisal management company registered or seeking to be registered in the District the information and fees that the Department requires to be submitted to it pursuant to regulations or guidance promulgated by the Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A federally regulated appraisal management company operating in the District must report to the Department the information required to be submitted by the District to the Appraisal Subcommittee, pursuant to the Appraisal Subcommittee's policies regarding the determination of the appraisal management company AMC National Registry fee.  These reporting requirements will be set forth by the Department by rule, and shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A report to the Department on a form prescribed by the Department of intent to operate in the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Information related to whether the appraisal management company is owned in whole or in part, directly or indirectly, by any person who has had an appraiser license or certificate refused, denied, canceled, surrendered in lieu of revocation, or revoked in any state for a substantive cause, as determined by the Appraisal Subcommittee; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If a person has had such action taken on his or her appraisal license, information related to whether the license was revoked for a substantive cause and whether it has been reinstated by the state or states in which the appraiser was licensed or certified.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-110" path="§105" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2019-07-31">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-110" path="§105">§ 105 of Appraisal Management Company Regulation Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-110, July 31, 2019, 66 DCR 178)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Act 23-110" eff="2019-07-31" path="§105" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-20" doc="D.C. Law 23-135" eff="2020-10-20" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 23-140" path="§105" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2020-10-20">For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-140" path="§105">§ 105 of Appraisal Management Company Regulation Temporary Act of 2020 (D.C. Law 23-140, Oct. 20, 2020, 67 DCR 9891)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-140" eff="2020-10-20" path="§105" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-206" eff="2021-03-16" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-206" eff="2021-03-16" path="§105" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
