<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-311.01a</num>
  <heading>Internal audit function requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An insurer shall be exempt from the requirements of this section if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The insurer has annual direct written and unaffiliated assumed premium, including international direct and assumed premium but excluding premium reinsured with the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation and Federal Flood Program, less than $500 million; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the insurer is a member of a group of insurers, the group has annual direct written and unaffiliated assumed premium including international direct and assumed premium, but excluding premium reinsured with the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation and Federal Flood Program, less than $1 billion.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The insurer or group of insurers shall establish an internal audit function providing independent, objective, and reasonable assurance to the audit committee and insurer management regarding the insurer's governance, risk management, and internal controls.  This assurance shall be provided by performing general and specific audits, reviews, and tests and by employing other techniques considered necessary to protect assets, evaluate control effectiveness and efficiency, and evaluate compliance with policies and regulations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To ensure that internal auditors remain objective, the internal audit function shall be organizationally independent.  The internal audit function will not defer ultimate judgment on audit matters to others and shall appoint an individual to head the Internal audit function who will have direct and unrestricted access to the board of directors.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Organizational independence shall not preclude dual-reporting relationships.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The head of the internal audit function shall report to the audit committee regularly, but no less than annually, on the periodic audit plan, factors that may adversely impact the Internal audit function's independence or effectiveness, material findings from completed audits, and the appropriateness of corrective actions implemented by management as a result of audit findings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If an insurer is a member of an insurance holding company system or included in a group of insurers, the insurer may satisfy the Internal audit function requirements set forth in this section at the ultimate controlling parent level, an intermediate holding company level, or the individual legal entity level.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-48" type="History" path="§12a-1">Oct. 21, 1993, D.C. Law 10-48, § 12a-1</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-292" eff="2019-04-11" path="§301|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-292" path="§401" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2019-04-11" eff="2019-04-11">
        Section 401 of D.C. Law 22-292 provided that this section, as created by D.C. Law 22-292, shall apply to all insurance policies issued or renewed in the District 90 days after April 11, 2019.
      </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-292" eff="2019-04-11" path="§401" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-20" doc="D.C. Law 23-135" eff="2020-10-20" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
