<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-3303.13c</num>
  <heading>Licensing requirement for certain multiple employer welfare arrangements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A multiple employer welfare arrangement that is not fully insured, as described in subsection (c) of this section, shall not operate in the District or market, offer, or issue a health benefit plan to any individual or employer in the District without first meeting the requirements for, and becoming licensed as, an insurer, a hospital and medical services corporation, a fraternal benefit society, or a health maintenance organization.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The existence of contracts of reinsurance shall not be considered in determining whether a multiple employer welfare arrangement is fully insured.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, a multiple employer welfare arrangement is not fully insured unless the covered benefits it provides are:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Insured on a direct basis by an insurance company licensed to transact the business of insurance in District; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Arranged for or provided on a direct basis by</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A hospital and medical services corporation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A fraternal benefit society;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A health maintenance organization licensed in the District; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Any combination of these entities.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-209" type="History" path="ยง313c">Apr. 13, 1999, D.C. Law 12-209, ยง 313c</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-266" eff="2019-03-22" path="ยง2|(e)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-20" doc="D.C. Law 23-135" eff="2020-10-20" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
