<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-3303.13d</num>
  <heading>Short-term, limited-duration health insurance.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An insurer shall not provide short-term, limited-duration health insurance policies, certificates of coverage, or contracts unless the insurer obtains a certificate of authority from the Commissioner to offer health insurance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An insurer offering for sale a short-term, limited-duration health insurance policy, certificate of coverage, or contract shall apply the same underwriting standards to all applicants for such coverage regardless of whether the applicant has previously been covered by a short-term, limited-duration health insurance policy, certificate of coverage, or contract.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A short-term, limited-duration health insurance policy, certificate of coverage, or contract shall not exclude from coverage as a pre-existing condition any medical or behavioral health condition for which an applicant sought treatment in the prior 12 months or for which an applicant is currently in an active course of treatment. An insurer shall not use underwriting related to such a condition to deny enrollment in short-term, limited-duration coverage to an applicant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A short-term, limited-duration insurance policy, certificate of coverage, or contract shall terminate not more than 3 months after its effective date.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A short-term, limited-duration health insurance policy, certificate of coverage, or contract shall not be extended or renewed. The insurer shall not issue, directly or indirectly through an affiliate, a new short-term, limited-duration health insurance policy, certificate of coverage, or contract to an individual who had such a policy, certificate of coverage, or contract from the insurer within the preceding 9 months.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>An insurer shall ensure that each policy, certificate of coverage, or contract for short-term, limited-duration health insurance and all application materials for enrollment in that coverage displays prominently, in at least 14-point type, a statement that the coverage does not constitute minimum essential coverage for the purposes of satisfying the individual responsibility requirement of <cite path="§47-5102">§ 47-5102</cite>, and any other disclosures the Commissioner may require through rulemaking, including the types of benefits and consumer protections that are and are not included in the coverage.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A company offering for sale a short-term, limited-duration health insurance policy, certificate of coverage, or contract shall provide to the Commissioner any information the Commissioner requires by rulemaking.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-209" type="History" path="§313d">Apr. 13, 1999, D.C. Law 12-209, § 313d</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-266" eff="2019-03-22" path="§2|(e)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
