<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>31-3302.07</num>
  <heading>Regulations establishing standards.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may adopt regulations to enable him or her to establish and administer such standards relating to the provisions of this chapter as may be necessary to (i) implement the requirements of this chapter, and (ii) assure that the District of Columbia’s regulation of health insurers is not preempted pursuant to the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, approved August 21, 1996 (P.L. 104-191; 110 Stat. 1936).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may revise or amend such regulations and may increase the scope of the regulations to the extent necessary to maintain federal approval of the District of Columbia’s program for regulation of health insurers pursuant to the requirements established by the United States Department of Health and Human Services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may issue rules to establish and administer such standards relating to the provisions of <cite path="31|33">this chapter</cite> as may be necessary to improve access and affordability of health insurance in the District and to maintain the requirements of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, approved March 23, 2010 (124 Stat. 111; 42 U.S.C. § 18001, note).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner shall annually advise the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, or such other Council committee or committees having subject matter jurisdiction over health insurance, of revisions and amendments made pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-209" type="History" path="§207">Apr. 13, 1999, D.C. Law 12-209, § 207, 45 DCR 8433</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">See notes to <cite path="§31-3301.01">§ 31-3301.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">See Historical and Statutory Notes following <cite path="§31-3301.01">§ 31-3301.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 35-1028.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-526" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2018-12-10" eff="2018-12-10">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-526" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of Health Insurance Marketplace Improvement Emergency Amendment Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-526, Dec. 10, 2018, 65 DCR 13424)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-12-10" doc="D.C. Act 22-526" eff="2018-12-10" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 22-251" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2019-03-15" eff="2019-03-15">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-251" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of Health Insurance Marketplace Improvement Temporary Amendment Act of 2018 (D.C. Law 22-251, Mar. 15, 2019, 66 DCR 975)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-03-15" doc="D.C. Law 22-251" eff="2019-03-15" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-266" eff="2019-03-22" path="§2|(c)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-20" doc="D.C. Law 23-135" eff="2020-10-20" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
