<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>31-706.01</num>
  <heading>Group-wide supervision of internationally active insurance groups.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Commissioner shall be the group-wide supervisor for any internationally active insurance group in accordance with the provisions of this section; provided, that the Commissioner may acknowledge another regulatory official as the group-wide supervisor where the internationally active insurance group:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Does not have substantial insurance operations in the United States;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Has substantial insurance operations in the United States, but not in the District; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Has substantial insurance operations in the United States and the District, but the Commissioner has determined pursuant to the factors set forth in subsections (b) and (f) of this section that the other regulatory official is the appropriate group-wide supervisor.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An insurance holding company system that does not otherwise qualify as an internationally active insurance group may request that the Commissioner make a determination or acknowledgment as to the appropriate group-wide supervisor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In cooperation with other state, federal, and international regulatory agencies, the Commissioner shall identify a single group-wide supervisor for an internationally active insurance group.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Commissioner may determine that the Commissioner is the appropriate group-wide supervisor for an internationally active insurance group that conducts substantial insurance operations concentrated in the District; provided, that the Commissioner may acknowledge that a regulatory official from another jurisdiction is the appropriate group-wide supervisor for the internationally active insurance group.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Commissioner shall consider the following factors when making a determination or acknowledgment of who is appropriate as group-wide supervisor:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The place of domicile of the insurers within the internationally active insurance group that holds the largest share of the group's written premiums, assets, or liabilities;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The place of domicile of the top-tiered insurers in the insurance holding company system of the internationally active insurance group;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The location of the executive offices or largest operational offices of the internationally active insurance group;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Whether another regulatory official is acting or seeking to act as the group-wide supervisor under a regulatory system that the Commissioner determines to be:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Substantially similar to the system of regulation provided under the laws of the District; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Otherwise sufficient in terms of providing for group-wide supervision, enterprise risk analysis, and cooperation with other regulatory officials; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Whether another regulatory official acting or seeking to act as the group-wide supervisor provides the Commissioner with reasonably reciprocal recognition and cooperation.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A regulatory official identified under this section as the group-wide supervisor may determine that it is appropriate to acknowledge another supervisor to serve as the group-wide supervisor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The acknowledgment of the group-wide supervisor shall be made after consideration of the factors listed in this subsection (b) of this section and in cooperation with and subject to the acknowledgment of other regulatory officials involved with supervision of members of the internationally active insurance group, and in consultation with the internationally active insurance group.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, when another regulatory official is acting as the group-wide supervisor of an internationally active insurance group, the Commissioner shall acknowledge that regulatory official as the group-wide supervisor; provided, that, in the event of a material change in the internationally active insurance group that results in the internationally active insurance group's insurers domiciled in the District holding the largest share of the group's premiums, assets, or liabilities or the District being the place of domicile of the top-tiered insurers in the insurance holding company system of the internationally active insurance group, the Commissioner shall make a determination or acknowledgment as to the appropriate group-wide supervisor for such an internationally active insurance group pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Pursuant to <cite path="§31-706">§ 31-706</cite>, the Commissioner is authorized to collect from any insurer registered pursuant to <cite path="§31-705">§ 31-705</cite> all information necessary to determine whether the Commissioner may act as the group-wide supervisor of an internationally active insurance group or if the Commissioner may acknowledge another regulatory official to act as the group-wide supervisor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Before issuing a determination that an internationally active insurance group is subject to group-wide supervision by the Commissioner, the Commissioner shall notify the insurer registered pursuant to <cite path="§31-705">§ 31-705</cite> and the ultimate controlling person within the internationally active insurance group.  The internationally active insurance group shall have, at a minimum, 30 days to provide the Commissioner with additional information pertinent to the pending determination.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Commissioner shall publish in the District of Columbia Register and on the website for the Department of Insurance, Securities and Banking the identity of internationally active insurance groups that the Commissioner has determined are subject to group-wide supervision by the Commissioner.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If the Commissioner is the group-wide supervisor for an internationally active insurance group, the Commissioner shall be authorized to engage in any of the following group-wide supervision activities:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Assess the enterprise risks within the internationally active insurance group to ensure that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The material financial condition and liquidity risks to the members of the internationally active insurance group that are engaged in the business of insurance are identified by management; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Reasonable and effective mitigation measures are in place; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Request from any member of an internationally active insurance group subject to the Commissioner's supervision information necessary and appropriate to assess enterprise risk, including information about the members of the internationally active insurance group regarding:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Governance, risk assessment, and management;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Capital adequacy; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Material intercompany transactions;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Coordinate, and, through the authority of the regulatory officials of the jurisdictions where members of the internationally active insurance group are domiciled, compel development and implementation of reasonable measures designed to ensure that the internationally active insurance group is able to timely recognize and mitigate enterprise risks to members of such internationally active insurance group that are engaged in the business of insurance;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Communicate with other state, federal, and international regulatory agencies for members within the internationally active insurance group and share relevant information, subject to the confidentiality provisions of <cite path="§31-708">§ 31-708</cite>, through supervisory colleges as set forth in <cite path="§31-707.01">§ 31-707.01</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Enter into agreements with or obtain documentation from any insurer registered under <cite path="§31-705">§ 31-705</cite>, any member of the internationally active insurance group, and any other state, federal, and international regulatory agencies for members of the internationally active insurance group, providing the basis for or otherwise clarifying the Commissioner's role as group-wide supervisor, including provisions for resolving disputes with other regulatory officials; provided, that such agreements or documentation shall not serve as evidence in any proceeding that any insurer or person within an insurance holding company system not domiciled or incorporated in the District, doing business in the District, or otherwise subject to jurisdiction in the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Other group-wide supervision activities, consistent with the authorities and purposes enumerated above, as considered necessary by the Commissioner.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>If the Commissioner acknowledges that another regulatory official from a jurisdiction that is not accredited by the NAIC is the group-wide supervisor, the Commissioner is authorized to reasonably cooperate, through supervisory colleges or otherwise, with group-wide supervision undertaken by the group-wide supervisor; provided, that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Commissioner's cooperation is in compliance with the laws of the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The regulatory official acknowledged as the group-wide supervisor also recognizes and cooperates with the Commissioner's activities as a group-wide supervisor for other internationally active insurance groups where applicable; provided, that where such recognition and cooperation is not reasonably reciprocal, the Commissioner is authorized to refuse recognition and cooperation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner is authorized to enter into agreements with or obtain documentation from any insurer registered under <cite path="§31-705">§ 31-705</cite>, any affiliate of the insurer, and other state, federal, and international regulatory agencies for members of the internationally active insurance group that provide the basis for or otherwise clarify a regulatory official's role as group-wide supervisor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i )</num>
    <text>A registered insurer subject to this section shall pay the reasonable expenses of the Commissioner's participation in the administration of this section, including the engagement of attorneys, actuaries, and any other professionals and all reasonable travel expenses.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner is authorized to promulgate rules and regulations necessary to implement the provisions of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-44" type="History" path="§7a">Oct. 21, 1993, D.C. Law 10-44, § 7a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-292" eff="2019-04-11" path="§101|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-292" path="§401" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2019-04-11" eff="2019-04-11">
        Section 401 of D.C. Law 22-292 provided that this section, as created by D.C. Law 22-292, shall apply to all insurance policies issued or renewed in the District 90 days after April 11, 2019.
      </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-292" eff="2019-04-11" path="§401" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
