<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>16-1062</num>
  <heading>Petition for anti-stalking order; representation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person 16 years of age or older may petition the court for an anti-stalking order against another person who has allegedly stalked the petitioner, with at least one occasion of the course of conduct occurring within the 90 days prior to the date of petitioning.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A minor who is less than 16 years of age may not petition the court for an anti-stalking order on their own behalf.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The parent, legal guardian, or legal custodian of a minor may file a petition for an anti-stalking order on the minor's behalf.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A person 18 years of age or older to whom the minor is related by blood, adoption, legal custody, marriage, or domestic partnership may, at the request of a minor 13 years of age or older, petition for an anti-stalking order on the minor's behalf:</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Office of Attorney General may:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>If the petitioner is unable to petition on the petitioner's own behalf, intervene in a case and represent the interests of the District of Columbia at the request of the petitioner, a person petitioning on the petitioner's behalf, or a government agency; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>At the request of the petitioner or a person petitioning on the petitioner's behalf, provide individual legal representation to the petitioner in proceedings under <cite path="16|10A"> this chapter</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the Office of the Attorney General intervenes in a case under paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection, the intervention shall continue until:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The court denies the petition for an anti-stalking order;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Office of the Attorney General withdraws from the intervention.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The court may appoint attorneys to represent a party if the party:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is a minor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is not represented by an attorney; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The appointment would not unreasonably delay a determination on the issuance or denial of a temporary anti-stalking order or anti-stalking order.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>When computing a time period specified in <cite path="16|10A"> this chapter</cite> or in an order issued under <cite path="16|10A"> this chapter</cite> that is stated in days or a longer unit of time:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Exclude the day of the event that triggers the time period;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Count every day, including intermediate Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Include the last day of the time period, but if the last day of the time period specified falls on a Saturday, Sunday, a legal holiday, or a day on which weather or other conditions cause the court to be closed, the time period specified shall continue to run until the end of the next day that is not a Saturday, Sunday, legal holiday, or a day on which weather or other conditions cause the court to be closed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-275" eff="2021-04-27" path="ยง3|(j)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-275" eff="2021-04-27" path="ยง3|(j)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
