<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>16-1065</num>
  <heading>Notice to the parties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Pursuant to the Rules of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, the respondent shall be served with notice of the hearing, an order to appear, a copy of the petition, and a temporary anti-stalking order, if issued.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a minor has petitioned for an anti-stalking order without a parent, guardian, or custodian, and if the minor is residing with a parent, guardian, or custodian, the court shall send a copy of any order issued pursuant to <cite path="§16-1063|(d)">§ 16-1063(d)</cite> and notice of the hearing to that parent, guardian, or custodian, unless, in the discretion of the court, notification of that parent, guardian, or custodian would be contrary to the best interests of the minor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the court does not send notice to the parent, guardian, or custodian with whom the minor resides, the court may, in its discretion, send notice to any other parent, guardian, custodian, or other appropriate adult.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The notice of hearing shall notify the respondent that if the respondent does not attend the hearing, the court may issue an order against the respondent that may last up to 2 years.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A respondent is deemed to have been personally served and no additional proof of service is required for enforcement of an order if the respondent is present before the court when the order is issued or if the respondent is served with the order in open court.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>At the request of the petitioner, the Metropolitan Police Department may attempt to serve civil process in any case filed under <cite path="16|10A">this chapter</cite> that has an address for service in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-275" eff="2021-04-27" path="§3|(j)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-275" eff="2021-04-27" path="§3|(j)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
