<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>16-405</num>
  <heading>Requirements of surrogates and intended parents.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An individual seeking to serve as a surrogate shall enter into a written surrogacy agreement and, at the time that the surrogacy agreement is executed, shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be at least 21 years of age;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Have given birth to at least one live child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Have undergone a medical evaluation in which the individual was approved to serve as a surrogate;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Have completed a mental health evaluation by a mental health professional in which the individual was approved to serve as a surrogate; provided, that the mental health professional has received specialized training in, or has a practice that includes a specialty in, collaborative reproduction; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Have completed, with the intended parent or parents, a joint consultation with a mental health professional regarding issues that could arise during the surrogacy.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An individual or individuals seeking to become an intended parent or parents shall enter into a written surrogacy agreement and, at the time the surrogacy agreement is executed, shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Be at least 21 years of age; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Have completed with the surrogate a joint consultation with a mental health professional regarding issues that could arise during the surrogacy.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If an individual is married or in a domestic partnership, both parties to the marriage or domestic partnership must satisfy the requirements of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2017-04-07" doc="D.C. Law 21-255" eff="2017-04-07" path="ยง2|(e)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
