<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-1303.10</num>
  <heading>Grants.</heading>
  <text>In Fiscal Year 2020, the Agency shall award, on a competitive basis, grants to:</text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Support a program that provides targeted legal intervention services in matters involving child custody, child support, domestic violence, landlord-tenant issues, housing conditions, federally subsidized housing defense, and access to public benefits, for the purpose of preventing families from unnecessarily entering the child welfare system, in the amount of $200,000; provided, that the selected program shall have contracted with the Agency in Fiscal Year 2019 for the provision of such services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Support a program that helps fathers gain the knowledge and skills necessary to improve their involvement and connection to their children through voluntary home visits, parenting support, child-development information and activities, health education and support, family goal planning, adult literacy, legal advocacy, access to community resources, and activities that promote bonding and healthy habits, in the amount of $150,000; provided, that the selected program shall have received Community-Based Child Abuse Prevention grant funding from the Agency in Fiscal Year 2018;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Support a program that provides services to youth between 11 and 24 years of age that have been, or are at risk of, becoming victims of sex trafficking, as that term is defined in section 103(12) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000, approved October 28, 2000 (114 Stat. 1469; 22 U.S.C. § 7102(12)), that are not in the Agency's care and custody, in the amount of $150,000; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Support a program that provides parenting group sessions and home visitation services to families, with an emphasis on services that assist mothers who are homeless, victims of domestic violence, and reuniting with their children following a period of incarceration, in the amount of $160,000; provided, that the selected program shall have received Community-Based Child Abuse Prevention grant funding from the Agency in Fiscal Years 2018 and 2019.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-22" type="History" path="§310">Sept. 23, 1977, D.C. Law 2-22, title III, § 310</annotation>
    <annotation codify:doc="D.C. Code" path="§5062" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91">
          For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§5062">§ 5062 of the Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019</cite>, 66 DCR 8497).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§5062" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation codify:doc="D.C. Code" path="§5062" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112">
          For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§5062">§ 5062 of the Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019</cite>, 66 DCR 11964).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§5062" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§5062" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
