<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-251.23</num>
  <heading>Eligibility.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A close relative may be eligible to receive subsidy payments under this section if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The close relative has been the child's primary caregiver for at least the previous 6 months;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The child has resided in the close relative's home for at least the previous 6 months;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The child's parent has not resided in the close relative's home for at least the previous 6 months; provided, that a parent may reside in the home without disqualifying the close relative from receiving a subsidy if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The parent has designated the close relative to be the child's standby guardian pursuant to <cite path="16|48">Chapter 48 of Title 16</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The parent is a minor enrolled in school; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The parent is a minor with a medically verifiable disability under criteria that shall be prescribed by the Mayor pursuant to <cite path="§4-251.26">§ 4-251.26</cite>;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The close relative, and all adults residing in the close relative's home, has submitted to a criminal background check;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The close relative's household income is under 200% of the federally defined poverty level;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The close relative is a resident of the District as defined by <cite path="§4-205.03">§ 4-205.03</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The close relative has applied for Temporary Assistance for Needy Families benefits for the child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The close relative has entered into a subsidy agreement that includes a provision that no payments received under the agreement shall inure to the benefit of the child's parent but shall be solely for the benefit of the child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The close relative is not currently receiving a guardianship or adoption subsidy for the child;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The close relative has provided a signed statement, sworn under penalty of perjury, that the information provided to establish eligibility pursuant to this section, or any rules promulgated pursuant to <cite path="§4-251.26">§ 4-251.26</cite>, is true and accurate to the best belief of the close relative applicant; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>The close relative has met any additional requirements prescribed by the Mayor pursuant to rules issued under <cite path="§4-251.26">§ 4-251.26</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may waive the eligibility requirements established in subsection (a)(1) and (2) of this section if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Agency determines that the child is at risk of removal from the parent, guardian, or custodian pursuant to <cite path="§4-1301.07">§ 4-1301.07</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The parent, guardian, or custodian permits the close relative to be the child's primary caregiver; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The parent, guardian, or custodian permits the child to reside with the close relative.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall recertify the eligibility of each close relative receiving a subsidy on at least an annual basis.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of the recertification, a close relative may be required to provide a signed statement, sworn under penalty of perjury, that the information provided to establish continued eligibility pursuant to this section, or any rules promulgated pursuant to <cite path="§4-251.26">§ 4-251.26</cite>, remains true and accurate to the best belief of the close relative.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall terminate subsidy payments to a close relative at any time if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Mayor determines the close relative no longer meets the eligibility requirements established by this section, or by rules issued under <cite path="§4-251.26">§ 4-251.26</cite> or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>There is a substantiated finding of child abuse or neglect against the close relative caregiver resulting in the removal of the child from the close relative's home.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A close relative whose subsidy payments are terminated as a result of the removal of the child from the close relative's home may reapply if the child has been returned to the close relative's home.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Eligibility for subsidy payments under this section may continue until the child reaches 18 years of age.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>An applicant whose application for a subsidy has been denied or whose subsidy has been terminated shall be entitled to a hearing under the applicable provisions of <cite path="2|5">Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>; provided, that a close relative shall not be entitled to a hearing if the denial or termination of a subsidy is based upon the unavailability of appropriated funds.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Any statement under this section made with knowledge that the information set forth therein is false shall be subject to prosecution as a false statement under <cite path="§22-2405|(a)">§ 22-2405(a)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation path="§103" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2019-11-26" eff="2019-07-16" doc="D.C. Act 23-84">
          For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see § 103 of Close Relative Caregiver Subsidy Pilot Program Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-84, July 16, 2019, 66 DCR 8274).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-11-26" doc="D.C. Act 23-84" eff="2019-07-16" path="§103" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation path="§103" type="Temporary Legislation" history="false" app="2019-11-27" eff="2019-10-24" doc="D.C. Law 23-25">
          For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see § 103 of Close Relative Caregiver Subsidy Pilot Program Establishment Temporary Amendment Act of 2019 (D.C. Law 23-25, Oct. 24, 2019, 66 DCR 12081).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-11-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-25" eff="2019-10-24" path="§103" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation path="§103" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2019-11-26" eff="2019-10-29" doc="D.C. Act 23-150">
          For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see § 103 of Close Relative Caregiver Subsidy Pilot Program Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-150, October 29, 2019, 66 DCR 14352).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-11-26" doc="D.C. Act 23-150" eff="2019-10-29" path="§103" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-11-26" doc="D.C. Law 23-32" eff="2019-11-26" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-11-26" doc="D.C. Law 23-32" eff="2019-11-26" path="§103" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
