<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-251.25</num>
  <heading>Reports.</heading>
  <text>Beginning February 28, 2021, and on an annual basis thereafter, the Mayor shall issue a report to the Council on the subsidy program established by <cite path="4|2A|II">this subchapter</cite>. At a minimum, the report shall include:</text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The number of applications filed for the subsidy;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The number of subsidies awarded;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The number of families receiving both the subsidy and TANF;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The number of applications denied for failure to meet eligibility criteria;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The number of applications denied for lack of appropriated funding;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>An estimate of the number of close relative caregivers whose income is less than 200% of the federally-defined poverty level but who have not applied for the subsidy;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The number of subsidies terminated by the Mayor pursuant to <cite path="§4-251.23">§ 4-251.23</cite> or voluntarily by the close relative caregiver;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The number of substantiated cases of fraud and a comparison of this figure to the proportion of cases of fraud involving other benefit programs, including TANF, food stamps, and Medicaid;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The number of children removed from households receiving a subsidy under the program established by <cite path="4|2A|II">this subchapter</cite> due to a substantiated allegation of child abuse or neglect; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Any legislative, policy, or administrative recommendations of the Family Court of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia or of agencies designated by the Mayor to execute the provisions of <cite path="4|2A|II">this subchapter</cite> that are intended to enhance the effectiveness of the program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation path="§105" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2019-11-26" eff="2019-07-16" doc="D.C. Act 23-84">
          For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see § 105 of Close Relative Caregiver Subsidy Pilot Program Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-84, July 16, 2019, 66 DCR 8274).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-11-26" doc="D.C. Act 23-84" eff="2019-07-16" path="§105" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation path="§105" type="Temporary Legislation" history="false" app="2019-11-27" eff="2019-10-24" doc="D.C. Law 23-25">
          For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see § 105 of Close Relative Caregiver Subsidy Pilot Program Establishment Temporary Amendment Act of 2019 (D.C. Law 23-25, Oct. 24, 2019, 66 DCR 12081).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-11-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-25" eff="2019-10-24" path="§105" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-11-26" doc="D.C. Law 23-32" eff="2019-11-26" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-11-26" doc="D.C. Law 23-32" eff="2019-11-26" path="§105" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
