<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-555.06</num>
  <heading>Requests by a District agency for disclosure of an actual address.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A District agency may request disclosure of a participant's actual address from OVSJG pursuant to this section by sending a written request to OVSJG on the District agency's letterhead with the following information:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the participant for whom the District agency seeks disclosure of the actual address;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An explanation of the reasons that the District agency is requesting the participant's actual address;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A statement that the agency has adopted internal procedures that would ensure that the confidentiality of the participant's actual address will be protected; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any other information that OVSJG may reasonably request to identify the participant in the records of OVSJG.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Upon the receipt of a request pursuant to this section, OVSJG shall provide the participant or the participant's representative with:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Written notice of the request for disclosure received pursuant to this section; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An opportunity to express whether the request should be granted.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply if the request for disclosure is made by a law enforcement agency investigating alleged criminal or delinquent conduct by the participant or when complying with paragraph (1) of this subsection would jeopardize an ongoing investigation or the safety of law enforcement personnel.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 30 days after receiving a request under this section, OVSJG shall determine whether to grant the request.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Upon making a determination under paragraph (1) of this subsection, OVSJG shall provide the participant or the participant's representative with written notice describing whether the request is being granted or denied.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall not apply if the request for disclosure is made by a law enforcement agency investigating alleged criminal or delinquent conduct by the participant or when complying with subparagraph (A) of this paragraph would jeopardize an ongoing investigation or the safety of law enforcement personnel.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If OVSJG grants a request pursuant to this section, OVSJG shall provide the District agency that submitted the request with the following information:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The participant's actual address;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A statement setting forth the permitted uses of the actual address and the persons permitted to have access to the actual address; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The date on which the permitted use expires, if expiration is appropriate, after which the agency may no longer use the actual address.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a District agency's request is granted pursuant to this section, the District agency may only use the participant's actual address as set forth in the statement required by paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If OVSJG denies a request under this section, OVSJG shall provide prompt written notice to the District agency that submitted the request, setting forth the specific reasons for the denial.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-555.06" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§4-555.06">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-118" path="">D.C. Law 22-118</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-118" path="§301">§ 301 of D.C. Law 22-118</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-118" path="§106">§ 106 of D.C. Law 22-118</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-07-03" doc="D.C. Law 22-118" eff="2018-07-03" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-07-03" doc="D.C. Law 22-118" eff="2018-07-03" path="§106" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 22-118" path="§106" codified:display="Note" app="2018-07-03" eff="2018-07-03">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-118" path="">D.C. Law 22-118</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-118" path="§301">§ 301 of D.C. Law 22-118</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-118" path="§106">§ 106 of D.C. Law 22-118</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-168" path="§7035" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2018-10-30" eff="2018-10-30"><cite doc="D.C. Law 22-168" path="§7035">Section 7035 of D.C. Law 22-168</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-118" path="§301">§ 301 of D.C. Law 22-118</cite> removing the applicability restriction impacting this section. Therefore the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-118">D.C. Law 22-118</cite> has been given effect.
          </annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§7035" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
