<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>4-651.03</num>
  <heading>External evaluation contractor.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>By December 1, 2018, DOH shall select an external evaluation contractor to conduct a community-based evaluation of the effectiveness of the Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Beginning January 1, 2020, and annually thereafter, primary care providers selected to participate in the Healthy Steps Pediatric Primary Care Demonstration Program ("Program") established pursuant to <cite path="§4-651.02">§ 4-651.02</cite> shall report to an external evaluation contractor, selected by the grantee, and approved by DOH:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A schedule of well-infant visits;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The percentage of infants and toddlers who are up-to-date on their immunizations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The percentage of infants and toddlers who are up-to-date on their lead screenings, pursuant to <cite path="§7-871.03|(b)">§ 7-871.03(b)</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The number of infants and toddlers placed in a home visiting program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The number of infants and toddlers that were not placed in a home visiting program due to a lack of available slots;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The number of referrals of patients to Strong Start, developmental health, behavioral health, and community-based social services providers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The number of patients screened for behavioral health and social service needs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The number of patients referred to lactation support services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The number of breastfeeding patients served;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Breastfeeding initiation and duration rates; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Other qualitative outcome and performance mechanisms chosen by primary care providers selected to participate in the Program to measure healthy early childhood development.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Beginning January 1, 2020, and annually thereafter, DOH, in coordination with primary care providers selected to participate in the Program and an  external evaluation contractor selected pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, shall submit a report to the Mayor, Council, Quality Improvement Network Interagency Steering Committee, Interagency Coordinating Council, and OSSE evaluating the information submitted pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-179" eff="2018-10-30" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-179" eff="2018-10-30" path="§103" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
