<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-754.36a</num>
  <heading>Discontinuation of permanent supportive housing.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A provider may discontinue permanent supportive housing for a client only when the client has:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Relocated to another program or facility for more than 180 days;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Abandoned his or her unit for more than 60 days and good-faith efforts to locate the client have failed, or the client has been located but has indicated by words or actions that he or she does not intend to return to and reside in the unit; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The client has not requested a reasonable accommodation to continue the permanent supportive housing for disability-related reasons, or has requested a reasonable accommodation and it was denied; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>No household members who have been approved as part of the household unit for purposes of the program remain in the permanent supportive housing placement.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Providers of permanent supportive housing shall give oral and written notice, in accordance with <cite path="§4-754.33|(d)">§ 4-754.33(d)</cite>, to clients of their discontinuation from services only after the required time period in subsection (a) of this section has lapsed, except where there is credible evidence that the client who has relocated to another program or facility is expected to be absent for more than 180 days. The notice shall be given at least 30 days before the effective date of the discontinuation of services. If it is not possible to provide written notice at the time of the action because the client’s whereabouts are unknown, a written notice shall be delivered to the client’s last known address or, upon request, within 90 days of the discontinuation of services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A client whose permanent supportive housing is discontinued pursuant to this section shall have the right to be re-housed in accordance with the District's centralized or coordinated assessment system protocol; provided, that the client continues to meet the eligibility criteria for the program.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-35" type="History" path="§22a">Oct. 22, 2005, D.C. Law 16-35, § 22a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">as added Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 5182(h), 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 5181 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle Q of Title V of the act may be cited as the “Homeless Services Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5182(h) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 5182(h) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> added this section.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-02-28" doc="D.C. Law 22-65" eff="2018-02-28" path="§2|(z)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-02-28" doc="D.C. Law 22-65" eff="2018-02-28" path="§2|(z)|(2)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-02-28" doc="D.C. Law 22-65" eff="2018-02-28" path="§2|(z)|(2)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-02-28" doc="D.C. Law 22-65" eff="2018-02-28" path="§2|(z)|(2)|(C)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-02-28" doc="D.C. Law 22-65" eff="2018-02-28" path="§2|(z)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-02-28" doc="D.C. Law 22-65" eff="2018-02-28" path="§2|(z)|(4)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
