<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>22-1862</num>
  <heading>Unlawful distribution of a prohibited animal product.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning one year after October 1, 2020, a person commits the offense of unlawful distribution of a prohibited animal product if that person knowingly imports, sells, offers for sale, purchases, barters, trades, or possesses with intent to sell a prohibited animal product.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, a person does not commit the offense of unlawful distribution of a prohibited animal product if the person:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Bequeaths the prohibited animal product to the legal beneficiary of an estate or trust upon the death of the owner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Gifts or donates the prohibited animal product without remuneration;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Is a government employee or agent conducting law enforcement activities pursuant to federal, state, or local law;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Is an educational or scientific institution that imports, sells, offers for sale, purchases, barters, trades, or possesses with intent to sell a prohibited animal product for educational or scientific purposes;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Is engaging in an activity that is expressly authorized by federal law or a permit issued pursuant to federal law;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Imports, sells, offers for sale, purchases, barters, trades, or possesses with intent to sell a prohibited animal product that is part of an antique that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is composed of not more than 20% of a prohibited animal product by volume; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The person can, through documentation, establish provenance and demonstrate that the antique is at least 100 years old; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Imports, sells, offers for sale, purchases, barters, trades, or possesses with intent to sell a prohibited animal product that is part of a musical instrument that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is composed of less than 20% of a prohibited animal product by volume; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The person can establish provenance and demonstrate that the musical instrument was manufactured before 1976.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The act of obtaining an appraisal of a prohibited animal product alone shall not constitute possession with intent to sell or offer for sale.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-1862" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§22-1862">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-126" path="">D.C. Law 23-126</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-126" path="§6">§ 6 of D.C. Law 23-126</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-126" path="§3">§ 3 of D.C. Law 23-126</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-08-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-126" eff="2020-08-06" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-126" eff="2020-08-06" path="§3" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 23-126" path="§3" codified:display="Note" app="2020-08-06" eff="2020-08-06">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-126" path="">D.C. Law 23-126</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-126" path="§6">§ 6 of D.C. Law 23-126</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-126" path="§3">§ 3 of D.C. Law 23-126</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2020-12-03" eff="2020-12-03" path="§7082" display="false"><cite doc="D.C. Law 23-149" path="§7082">Section 7082 of D.C. Law 23-149</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-126" path="§6">section 6 of D.C. Law 23-126</cite> removing the applicability provision impacting this section.  Therefore, the creation of this section by Law 23-126 has been implemented.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="§7082" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2020-12-03" eff="2020-12-03" path="§7082"><cite doc="D.C. Law 23-149" path="§7082">Section 7082 of D.C. Law 23-149</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-126" path="§6">section 6 of D.C. Law 23-126</cite> removing the applicability provision impacting this section.  Therefore, the creation of this section by Law 23-126 has been implemented.
        </annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
