<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>22-3705</num>
  <heading>Attorney General civil enforcement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Attorney General may, irrespective of any criminal prosecution, the result of any criminal prosecution, or any cause of action brought pursuant to <cite path="§22-3704">§ 22-3704</cite>, bring, in the name of the District of Columbia, a civil action for appropriate relief whenever any person, whether or not acting under color of law:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Commits a bias-related crime; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Through any act of violence, force, fraud, or intimidation:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Interferes or attempts to interfere with an individual's exercise of any right secured by the United States Constitution or District law; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Deprives any individual of the equal protection of the United States Constitution or District law.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In the course of an investigation to determine whether to seek relief under this section, the Attorney General may subpoena witnesses, administer oaths, require sworn written responses to written questions, examine an individual under oath, and compel production of records, books, papers, contracts, and other documents and materials, subject to the procedures in §§ <cite path="§1-301.88d">1-301.88d</cite> and <cite path="§1-301.88e">1-301.88e</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Appropriate relief under this section may include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Injunctive relief;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Actual or nominal damages for economic or non-economic loss, including damages for emotional distress;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Punitive damages in an amount to be determined by a jury or a court sitting without a jury, which may include treble damages for any economic or non-economic loss the person suffered;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Reasonable attorneys' fees and costs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A civil penalty of up to $10,000 per act giving rise to a cause of action under subsection (a) of this section; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Any other relief which the court determines proper.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-121" type="History" path="§6">May 8, 1990, D.C. Law 8-121, § 6</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-05-15" doc="D.C. Law 23-283" eff="2021-05-15" path="§4|(d)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
