<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-4235</num>
  <heading>Administrative support.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There are authorized such funds as may be necessary to support the CJCC.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The CJCC is authorized to hire staff and to obtain appropriate office space, equipment, materials, and services necessary to carry out its responsibilities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of <cite path="2|14|A">Unit A of Chapter 14 of Title 2</cite>, the CJCC shall use a ranking system based on a scale of 100 points for all employment decisions for positions within the CJCC.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An individual who is a District resident at the time of application shall be awarded a 10-point hiring preference over a nonresident applicant; provided, that the individual claims the preference. This 10-point preference shall be in addition to any points awarded on the 100-point scale.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>At the time of appointment, an individual who claimed the 10-point residency preference shall agree, in writing, to maintain District residency for a period of 7 consecutive years from the effective date of appointment into the position for which the individual claimed the residency preference.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>An individual who claimed the residency preference and who fails to maintain District residency for 7 consecutive years from the individual's effective date of appointment, shall forfeit the individual's District government employment.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Each applicant for a position covered by this paragraph, shall be informed in writing of the provisions of this paragraph at the time of application.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The CJCC shall verify and enforce District residency requirements pursuant to <cite path="§1-515.04">§ 1-515.04</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>By November 1 of each year and pursuant to <cite path="§1-515.06">§ 1-515.06</cite>, the CJCC shall submit to the Mayor an annual report detailing, for the previous fiscal year, compliance with residency requirements.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The CJCC shall serve as the personnel authority for all employees of the CJCC. The CJCC shall exercise this authority consistent with <cite path="1|6">Chapter 6 of Title 1</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The CJCC may exercise procurement authority to carry out the responsibilities of the CJCC, including contracting and contract oversight. The CJCC shall exercise this authority consistent with <cite path="2|3A">Chapter 3A of Title 2</cite> [<cite path="§2-351.01">§ 2-351.01</cite> et seq.], except <cite path="§2-352.01|(a)">§ 2-352.01(a)</cite> shall not apply.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History" path="§1506">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 1506, 48 DCR 6981</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-108" type="History">Feb. 6, 2008, D.C. Law 17-108, § 211, 54 DCR 10993</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 214, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 1406 of Fiscal Year 2002 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-124, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7861).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> substituted “consistent with <cite path="2|3A">Chapter 3A of Title 2</cite>; except that <cite path="§2-352.01|(a)">§ 2-352.01(a)</cite> shall not apply” for “consistent with Unit A of Chapter 3 of Title 2, except with regard to the powers and duties outlined in <cite path="§2-301.05|(a)" proof="true">§ 2-301.05(a)</cite>, (b), (c), and (e)” in (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-108">D.C. Law 17-108</cite> added subsec. (b-1).</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§10" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
