<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <reason/>
  <num>22-4330</num>
  <heading>Seizure of hunting and fishing equipment; sale at public auction and disposal of proceeds; disposal of property not sold at auction; payment of valid liens after sale.</heading>
  <text>Recodified at <cite path="§8-2221.30">§ 8-2221.30</cite>.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 85-730" type="History" path="§3">Aug. 23, 1958, 72 Stat. 814, Pub. L. 85-730, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-284" type="History">June 12, 1999, D.C. Law 12-284, § 5, 46 DCR 1328</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(205) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.11">§ 1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.14|(a)">§ 1-207.14(a)</cite>), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 5 of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization and Street Solicitation for Prostitution Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-428, August 6, 1998,  45 DCR 5884), § 5 of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-506, November 10, 1998,  45 DCR 8139), and § 5 of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-13, February 8, 1999,  46 DCR 2333).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 3(a) of the Safe Streets Anti-Prostitution Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-252, April 15, 1996,  43 DCR 2139).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary provision, on an emergency basis, making available for a reasonable fee the name, address, date of birth, occupation, and photograph of persons convicted of violation of §§ <cite path="§22-2701">22-2701</cite> or <cite path="§22-2703">22-2703</cite> 1981 Ed., see § 2 of the Safe Streets Anti-Prostitution Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-252, April 15, 1996,  43 DCR 2139).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 13(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-282">D.C. Law 12-282</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-282">D.C. Law 12-282</cite> inserted “or any designated civilian employee of the Metropolitan Police Department” in the first sentence of (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 22-1630.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-1630.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Return of property by property clerk, see <cite path="§5-119.16">§ 5-119.16</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-05-19" doc="D.C. Law 21-282" eff="2017-05-19" path="§411" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
