<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>22-938</num>
  <heading>Injunctive relief and protections.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Whenever the Attorney General or the United States Attorney has reason to believe that a person has engaged in financial exploitation of a vulnerable adult or elderly person in violation of <cite path="§22-933.01">§ 22-933.01</cite>, the Attorney General or the United States Attorney may petition the court, which may be by ex-parte motion and without notice to the person, for one or more of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A temporary restraining order;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A temporary injunction;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An order temporarily freezing the person's assets; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any other relief the court deems just.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The court may grant an ex-parte motion authorized by subsection (a) of this section without notice to the person against whom the injunction or order is sought if the court finds that facts offered in support of the motion establish that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is a substantial likelihood that the person committed financial exploitation of a vulnerable adult or elderly person;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The harm that may result from the injunction or order is clearly outweighed by the risk of harm to the vulnerable adult or elderly person if the inunction or order is not issued; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the Attorney General or the United States Attorney has petitioned for an order temporarily freezing assets, the order is necessary to prevent dissipation of assets obtained in violation of <cite path="§22-933.01">§ 22-933.01</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An order temporarily freezing assets without notice to the person pursuant to subsections (a)(3) and (b) of this section shall expire on a date set by the court, not later than 14 days after the court issues the order unless, before that time, the court extends the order for good cause shown.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A person whose assets were temporarily frozen under paragraph (1) of this subsection may move to dissolve or modify the order after notice to the Attorney General for the United States Attorney. The court shall hear and decide the motion or application on an expedited basis.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The court may issue an order temporarily freezing the assets of the vulnerable adult or elderly person to prevent dissipation of assets; provided, that the court also appoints a receiver or conservator for those assets. The order shall allow for the use of assets to continue care for the vulnerable adult or elderly person, and can only be issued upon a showing that a temporary injunction or temporary restraining order authorized by this section would be insufficient to safeguard the assets, or with the consent of the vulnerable adult or elderly person or his or her legal representative.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-301" type="History" path="§208">June 8, 2001, D.C. Law 13-301, § 208</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-11-23" doc="D.C. Law 21-166" eff="2016-11-23" path="§3|(i)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
