<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>22-933.01</num>
  <heading>Financial exploitation of a vulnerabl adult or elderly person.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person is guilty of financial exploitation of a vulnerable adult or elderly person if the person intentionally and knowingly:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Uses deception, intimidation, or undue influence to obtain the property, including money, of a vulnerable adult or elderly person, with the intent to deprive the vulnerable adult or elderly person of the property or use it for the advantage of anyone other than the vulnerable adult or elderly person;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Uses deception, intimidation, or undue influence to cause the vulnerable adult or elderly person to assume a legal obligation on behalf of, or for the benefit of, anyone other than the vulnerable adult or elderly person; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Violates any provision of law proscribing theft, extortion, forgery, fraud, or identity theft against the vulnerable adult or elderly person, so long as the offense was undertaken to obtain the property, including money, of a vulnerable adult or elderly person, or to cause the vulnerable adult or elderly person to assume a legal obligation on behalf of, or for the benefit of, anyone other than the vulnerable adult or elderly person.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>It is an affirmative defense that the accused knew or reasonably believed the victim was not a vulnerable adult or elderly person at the time of the offense, or could not have known or determined that the victim was a vulnerable adult or elderly person because of the manner in which the offense was committed. This defense shall be established by a preponderance of the evidence.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "undue influence" means mental, emotional, or physical coercion that overcomes the free will or judgment of a vulnerable adult or elderly person and causes the vulnerable adult or elderly person to act in a manner that is inconsistent with his or her financial, emotional, mental, or physical well-being.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-301" type="History" path="ยง203a">June 8, 2001, D.C. Law 13-301, ยง 203a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-11-23" doc="D.C. Law 21-166" eff="2016-11-23" path="ยง3|(d)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
