<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>22-937</num>
  <heading>Civil penalties for financial exploitation of a vulnerable adult or elderly person.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if the Attorney General has reason to believe that any person has violated, or intends to violate, <cite path="§22-933.01|(a)">§ 22-933.01(a)</cite>, the Attorney General may bring a civil action in the Court, in the name of the District, to seek any of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A temporary or permanent injunction;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Restitution of money or property;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The cost of the action, including reasonable attorney's fees;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Revocation of all permits, licenses, registrations, or certifications issued by the District authorizing the person to provide services to vulnerable adults or elderly persons.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Such a revocation shall be effective upon the issuance of the Court's judgment, and the person shall not be entitled to a hearing with the relevant licensing board or agency;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Civil penalties of not more than $10,000 per violation; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Any other relief the Court considers just.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In an action under this section:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A related criminal proceeding need not have been initiated, nor judgment secured, prior to bringing the action;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General shall not be required to prove damages; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The burden of proof shall be by a preponderance of the evidence.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-301" type="History" path="§207">June 8, 2001, D.C. Law 13-301, § 207</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-11-23" doc="D.C. Law 21-166" eff="2016-11-23" path="§3|(i)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-274" eff="2021-04-27" path="§302|(d)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
