<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>19-701</num>
  <heading>Escheatment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When there is no surviving spouse, surviving domestic partner, or relation of the intestate within the fifth degree, reckoned by counting down from the common ancestor to the more remote, the surplus of real and personal property escheats to the District of Columbia to be deposited in the Escheatment Fund, established by subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is established as a special fund the Escheatment Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Department of Human Services in accordance with subsection (3) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All cash, including real or personal property reduced to cash, received or obtained by the District pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be deposited in the Fund.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Money in the Fund shall be used for emergency assistance grants described in <cite path="§4-753.01|(e)">§ 4-753.01(e)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The money deposited into the Fund but not expended in a fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "domestic partner" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§32-701|(3)">§ 32-701(3)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-183" type="History">Sept. 14, 1965, 79 Stat. 701, Pub. L. 89-183, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 566</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 148(1)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-104" type="History">Apr. 30, 1988, D.C. Law 7-104,§ 5(c), 35 DCR 147</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-79" type="History">Apr. 4, 2006, D.C. Law 16-79, § 5(t), 53 DCR 1035</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 5042, 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Age of majority: Section 2 of the Act of July 22, 1976, <cite doc="D.C. Law 1-75">D.C. Law 1-75</cite>, provided: “Notwithstanding any rule of common or other law to the contrary in effect on the effective date of this act, the age of majority in the District of Columbia shall be eighteen years of age, except that this act shall not affect any common law or statutory right to child support.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 5041 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided that subtitle E of title V of the act may be cited as the “Emergency Housing Assistance Act of 2010”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 5042 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite>, in subsec. (a), added the last sentence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-79">D.C. Law 16-79</cite> rewrote section which had read as follows: “Where there is no surviving spouse or relations of the intestate within the fifth degree, reckoned by counting down from the common ancestor to the more remote, the surplus of real and personal property escheats to the District of Columbia to be used by the Mayor of the District of Columbia for the benefit of the poor.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 19-701.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 19-701.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§19-305">§ 19-305</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§3092" codified:display="Note" app="2019-07-22" eff="2019-07-22">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§3092">§ 3092 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019, 66 DCR 8497)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§3092" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§3092" codified:display="Note" app="2019-09-04" eff="2019-09-04">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§3092">§ 3092 of Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019, 66 DCR 11964)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§3092" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§3092" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
