<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-1313.12</num>
  <heading>Content of an application to amend an Underground Infrastructure Improvement Projects Plan and financing order.</heading>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-102" type="History" path="§312">May 3, 2014, D.C. Law 20-102, § 312, 61 DCR 1882</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-56" path="§2|(m)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-05-17" eff="2017-05-17">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-56" path="§2|(m)">§ 2(m) of Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Financing Emergency Amendment Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-56, May 17, 2017, 64 DCR 4909)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-05-17" doc="D.C. Act 22-56" eff="2017-05-17" path="§2|(m)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-07-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-5" eff="2017-07-11" path="§2|(m)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-07-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-5" eff="2017-07-11" path="§2|(m)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-07-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-5" eff="2017-07-11" path="§2|(m)|(3)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An application to the Commission by the electric company or DDOT to amend an existing Underground Infrastructure Improvement Projects Plan, approved by the Commission pursuant to <cite path="§34-1313.10">§ 34-1313.10</cite>, shall describe the purpose to be accomplished by the proposed amendment, the financial impacts, if any, to the electric company’s customers that are likely to result from the amendment, if approved, and include each item set forth in <cite path="§34-1313.08">§ 34-1313.08</cite>; provided, that for good cause shown in its application, the electric company may omit the material required in one more of the items listed in <cite path="§34-1313.08">§ 34-1313.08</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements of subsection (a) of this section, an application to amend an existing Underground Infrastructure Improvement Projects Plan shall request any amendment to the Commission's financing order for the corresponding period such that the work, surcharges and riders, and other contents of the financing order, as amended, are coordinated with the Underground Infrastructure Improvement Projects Plan, as amended.</text>
  </para>
</section>
