<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-1439</num>
  <heading>Rules, duties, and powers of the Commission.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commission may impose an administrative fee on a renewable energy credit transaction, but the amount of the fee may not exceed the Commission’s actual direct cost of processing the transaction.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>On or before May 1 of each year, the Commission shall provide a report to the Council on the implementation of <cite path="34|14A">this chapter</cite>, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The availability of tier one renewable sources;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Certification of the number of renewable energy credits used by electricity suppliers to meet the requirements of <cite path="§34-1432">§ 34-1432</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The amount of compliance fees paid pursuant to <cite path="§34-1434|(c)">§ 34-1434(c)</cite> in the previous calendar year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The amount of compliance fees estimated to be paid pursuant to <cite path="§34-1434|(c)">§ 34-1434(c)</cite> in the current calendar year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The total amount of the District's electric supply that was exempt from changes to the renewable energy portfolio standard pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-154" path="§4">section 4 of the Renewable Portfolio Standard Expansion Amendment Act of 2016, effective October 8, 2016 (D.C. Law 21-154; D.C. Official Code § 34-1434, note)</cite> for the previous year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The total amount of the District's electric supply that is estimated to be exempt from changes to the renewable energy portfolio standard pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-154" path="§4">section 4 of the Renewable Portfolio Standard Expansion Amendment Act of 2016, effective October 8, 2016 (D.C. Law 21-154; D.C. Official Code § 34-1434, note)</cite> for the current calendar year and each subsequent year that the exemption applies;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The total amount of the District's electric supply that was exempt from changes to the renewable energy portfolio standard pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-257" path="§101|(b)|(2)">section 101(b)(2) of the CleanEnergy DC Omnibus Amendment Act of 2018, passed on 2nd reading on December 18, 2018 (Enrolled version of Bill 22-904) ("CleanEnergy Act")</cite> for the previous calendar year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The total amount of the District's electric supply that is estimated to be exempted from changes to the renewable energy portfolio standard pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-257" path="§101|(b)|(2)">section 101(b)(2) of the CleanEnergy Act</cite> for the current calendar year and each subsequent year that the exemption applies; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Any other such information the Commission considers necessary or appropriate.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <text>Beginning in July 2019, and every 6 months thereafter, the Commission shall publish on its website the total amount of solar energy from solar energy systems meeting the requirements of <cite path="§34-1432|(e)|(1)">§ 34-1432(e)(1)</cite> for which interconnection requests have been submitted in the previous 6 months.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall establish standards, by order or regulation, to account for customer generation from eligible renewable resources for compliance with <cite path="§34-1432">§ 34-1432</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-340" type="History" path="§11">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-340, § 11, 52 DCR 2285</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 2112, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2112 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional ReviewEmergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2112 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2112 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> substituted “May 1” for “April 1” in (b).</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-257" eff="2019-03-22" path="§101|(f)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-257" eff="2019-03-22" path="§101|(f)|(2)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
