<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>34-133</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was added by emergency legislation that will expire on October 22, 2021.*
      </text>
  <heading>Restration of service.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For a period of 90 days beginning on October 12, 2021, a company shall restore service to a customer when the customer makes a payment to the company of at least $10; provided, that the customer enters into a payment plan pursuant to <cite path="§34-1151">§ 34-1151</cite>, or makes a showing that the utility was disconnected improperly pursuant to this act (D.C. Law 2). Amounts paid by a customer pursuant to this subsection shall be applied in full to reduce the amounts owed by the customer to the company.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>When a customer whose service has been disconnected, suspended, or degraded for nonpayment is certified by the Mayor or documented by the customer to be eligible for utility disconnection relief under <cite path="§34-131|(a)|(5)">§ 34-131(a)(5)</cite>, a company shall reconnect the customer without charge.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A company shall reconnect a customer under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph within 24 hours of receiving notice that the customer is qualified for utility disconnection relief under <cite path="§34-131|(a)|(5)">§ 34-131(a)(5)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-07-24" doc="D.C. Act 24-125" eff="2021-07-24" path="§3|(k)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-07-24" doc="D.C. Act 24-125" eff="2021-07-24" path="§3|(k)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-125" path="§3|(k)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-07-24" eff="2021-07-24">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-125" path="§3|(k)">§ 3(k) of Public Emergency Extension and Eviction and Utility Moratorium Phasing Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-125, July 24, 2021, 68 DCR 007342)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
