<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>34-1313.11</num>
  <heading>Use of DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon completion of construction by DDOT and acceptance by the electric company, the District shall transfer legal title to the DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvements to the electric company for the sum of one dollar.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvements shall be for exclusive use by the electric company. The electric company shall not earn a return on or of investment with respect to the DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvements transferred to the electric company as provided in this section. Taxes and fees, if any, on the transfer shall be recoverable by the electric company in rates as approved by the Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The transfer of real and personal property between the electric company and the District, including DDOT or any other District agency or instrumentality, pursuant to subsection (a) of this section or which is included in, or forms a part of, the DDOT Underground Electric Company Infrastructure Improvements shall be exempt from all taxes imposed by the District that relate to the transfer of real or personal property, including, as any may be amended from time to time, the:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Transfer tax imposed under <cite path="§47-903">§ 47-903</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Recordation tax imposed under <cite path="§42-1103">§ 42-1103</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Sales tax imposed under <cite path="§47-2002">§ 47-2002</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Use tax imposed under <cite path="§47-2202">§ 47-2202</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-102" type="History" path="§311">May 3, 2014, D.C. Law 20-102, § 311, 61 DCR 1882</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-56" path="§2|(l)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-05-17" eff="2017-05-17">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-56" path="§2|(l)">§ 2(l) of Electric Company Infrastructure Improvement Financing Emergency Amendment Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-56, May 17, 2017, 64 DCR 4909)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-05-17" doc="D.C. Act 22-56" eff="2017-05-17" path="§2|(l)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-07-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-5" eff="2017-07-11" path="§2|(l)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
