<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>34-2161</num>
  <heading>Reporting.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>Within 60 days after the end of each fiscal year, the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority ("DC Water") shall transmit to the Mayor and the Council and publicly post on the DC Water website a report that includes the following information for the preceding fiscal year:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For the lead water service line replacements under <cite path="§34-2158|(a)|(2)">§ 34-2158(a)(2)</cite>:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The number of times that DC Water replaced a damaged or leaking water service line on public property and requested the consent of the private property owner to replace the portion of the lead water service line on private property;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The number of private property owners that provided consent, did not provide consent, or did not respond to DC Water's request for consent within 30 days after delivery of the request described in <cite path="§34-2158|(a)|(2)|(C)">§ 34-2158(a)(2)(C)</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The number of locations, broken down by Ward and Advisory Neighborhood Commission, where DC Water replaced the portion of the lead water service line on public property but did not replace the portion of the lead water service line on private property; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the lead water service line replacement payment assistance program ("Program") established by <cite path="§34-2159">§ 34-2159</cite>:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The number of contractors who submitted an invoice to DC Water under <cite path="§34-2159|(g)|(1)">§ 34-2159(g)(1)</cite>, broken down by:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Whether or not DC Water paid the contractor the amount of the discount; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The Ward and Advisory Neighborhood Commission in which the property is located;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The most common reasons that DC Water declined to pay a contractor the amount of the discount submitted under <cite path="§34-2159|(g)|(1)">§ 34-2159(g)(1)</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>As of September 30 of the preceding fiscal year, the number of residential property owners with lead water service lines located on their private property where the portion of the water service line on public property is not a lead water service line;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The average number of days DC Water took to provide financial assistance to a contractor under the Program, from the date the contractor provided DC Water with an invoice to the date that DC Water paid the contractor the amount of the discount for which the residential property owner was approved; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>A description of efforts made by DC Water to publicize the availability of financial assistance through the Program, including a description of the total amount of expenditures by DC Water on such efforts.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History" path="§6019d">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 6019d</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-229" eff="2021-03-16" path="§3|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
