<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>34-2162</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
      </text>
  <heading>Reporting on lead water service line replacement spending.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority ("DC Water") and the Department of Energy and Environment ("DOEE") shall separately provide the Council with a report on agency spending of federal and local funds on lead water service line replacements, broken down by spending of federal and local funds and by program. DC Water's report shall also include a breakdown of spending on lead line replacements, program management costs, street restoration, water main replacements, and other costs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>DC Water and DOEE shall transmit the reports required by subsection (a) of this section twice a year, on:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>February 1 for the period beginning July 1 and ending December 31 of the immediately preceding year; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>August 1 for the period beginning January 1and ending June 30 of the same year.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History" path="§6019e">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 6019e</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§6142" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§6142" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§6142" codified:display="Note" app="2021-08-23" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§6142">§ 6142 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
