<container xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <prefix>Title</prefix>
  <num>32</num>
  <heading>Labor.</heading>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>1</num>
    <heading>Displaced Workers Protection.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-101.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-102.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-103.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>1A</num>
    <heading>Employee Sick Leave.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.01.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.02.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.03.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.04.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.05.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.06.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.07.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.08.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.09.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.10.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.10a.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.10b.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.11.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.12.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.13.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.14.xml"/>
    <section>
      <num>32-131.15</num>
      <heading>Report by the District of Columbia Auditor.</heading>
      <text>The District of Columbia Auditor shall prepare and submit to the Mayor and Council, annually, a report of this chapter’s economic impact on the private sector. Among other things, the District of Columbia Auditor shall audit a sample of District businesses to determine:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The compliance level of businesses; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Whether companies are utilizing staffing patterns to circumvent the intention of this chapter.</text>
      </para>
      <annotations>
        <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-89">D.C. Law 20-89</cite>: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-89">D.C. Law 20-89</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
        <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-89">D.C. Law 20-89</cite> was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7003, effective Feb. 26, 2015.</text>
        <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 2014, and that the act shall apply to violations occurring after October 1, 2014.</text>
        <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-152" type="History" path="§16">May 13, 2008, D.C. Law 17-152, § 16, 55 DCR 3452</annotation>
        <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-89" type="History">Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-89, § 2(i), 61 DCR 317</annotation>
        <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-89">D.C. Law 20-89</cite> deleted “with the posting requirements” following “businesses” in (1).</annotation>
        <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-57">D.C. Law 21-57</cite>, Jan. 30, 2016,   62 DCR 15602).</annotation>
        <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-89">D.C. Law 20-89</cite>, § 3, see § 7003 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
        <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-89">D.C. Law 20-89</cite>, § 3, see § 7003 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
        <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-89">D.C. Law 20-89</cite>, § 3, see § 7003 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884).</annotation>
        <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, §  7, see §  4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-188, Oct. 27, 2015,  62 DCR 14224).</annotation>
        <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-293, Jan. 27, 2016, 63 DCR 1215).</annotation>
        <annotation type="Editor's Notes" app="2016-08-17" eff="2016-08-17" doc="D.C. Law 21-143" path="§7">
       Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-143" path="">D.C. Law 21-143</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-143" path="§14">§ 14 of D.C. Law 21-143</cite> provided that the change made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-143" path="§7">§ 7 of D.C. Law 21-143</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been given effect.
      </annotation>
        <annotation app="2016-08-17" doc="D.C. Law 21-143" eff="2016-08-17" path="§7" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.15a.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.16.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-131.17.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>1B</num>
    <heading>Reducing Single Occupancy Vehicle Use by Encouraging Transit Benefits.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-151.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-152.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-153.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading>Employment of Minors.</heading>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>I</num>
      <heading>General.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-201.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-202.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-203.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-204.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-205.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-206.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-207.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-208.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-209.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-210.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-211.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-212.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-213.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-214.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-215.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-216.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-217.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-218.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-219.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-220.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-221.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-222.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-223.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-224.xml"/>
    </container>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>II</num>
      <heading>Programs for Youth Employment.</heading>
      <section>
        <num>32-241</num>
        <heading>Programs for employment and training of young District domiciliaries.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>The Mayor shall establish and implement programs, subject to the annual appropriation of funds, for the employment and training of young persons who are domiciliaries of the District of Columbia, as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <heading>Summer youth jobs. —</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <para>
                <num>(i)</num>
                <text>A summer youth jobs program to provide for the employment or training each summer of not fewer than 10,000 or more than 21,000 youth 14 to 21 years of age on the date of enrollment in the program.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <text>Youth ages 14 to 15 years at the date of enrollment shall receive an hourly work readiness training rate of not less than $5.25.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <text>Youth ages 16 to 21 years at the date of enrollment shall be compensated at an hourly rate of $8.25.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(A-i)</num>
              <text>Registration for the summer youth jobs program shall occur on or before the last day of January and shall conclude by the last day of April of each year.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>The weekly number of hours of employment under the summer youth jobs program shall be established according to the age of the youth to be employed and the nature and requirements of the job, but shall not be fewer than 20 hours or more than 40 hours per week. Participants in this program shall be employed for a period of no more than 6 weeks.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(C)</num>
              <text>Employment may include an appropriate number of supervisory positions at an hourly wage of $9.25 to $13. Supervisory positions shall not be subject to the requirements under this paragraph regarding the number of hours and weeks of employment.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(D)</num>
              <text>The Department of Employment Services shall implement the summer youth jobs program subject to the appropriation of funds or availability of funds through public-private partnerships between the District government and a District business that has the ability to employ youth under this program; provided, that these partnerships shall be subject to all federal and District laws, rules, and regulations relating to the procurement and award of contracts, grants, or other government assistance. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “District Business” means a corporation or any entity carrying on any trade or business in the District of Columbia that is subject to taxation under § <cite path="§47-1807.02">47-1807.02</cite> or § <cite path="§47-1808.03">47-1808.03</cite>.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(E)</num>
              <text>Repealed.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <heading>In school employment and work readiness training. —</heading>
            <text>An in-school employment and work readiness training program to provide for the employment or training during the school year of students aged 14 through 21 years on a part-time basis at no less than the federal minimum wage, or work readiness training rate at no less than $5.25 per hour. Priority shall be given to students who meet the eligibility criteria and standards of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, approved July 22, 2014 (128 Stat. 1425; 29 U.S.C. § 3101 et seq.) (“Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act”), as identified in regulations issued to implement this subchapter. The Mayor may provide financial incentives to increase performance outcomes.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <heading>Out-of-school, year-round employment and work readiness training. —</heading>
            <text>An out-of-school, year-round employment and work readiness training program to provide youth 16 through 24 years of age with employment at the prevailing entry level wage for the job being performed and no less than the federal minimum wage, or work readiness training at a training rate no less than $5.25 per hour. The Mayor may provide financial incentives to promote work readiness training activities and to increase performance outcomes. Priority shall be given to youth who meet the eligibility criteria and standards of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, as identified in regulations issued to implement this subchapter. The program shall include safeguards to assure that the prospect of employment resulting from this program does not induce students to drop out of school.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <heading>On-the-job training program for adults.—</heading>
            <text>An on-the-job training program for unemployed individuals at least 18 years of age. Priority shall be given to participants who meet the eligibility criteria and standards of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, as identified in regulations issued to implement this subchapter. The District government shall reimburse participating employers no more than 75% of the prevailing wage paid for an occupation, as determined by the Mayor, for a period not to exceed 12 months. The employer shall pay all wages in excess of the allowable reimbursement and all fringe benefits. The Mayor shall require that participating private-sector employers agree to hire persons who successfully complete the program. On-the-job training participants shall not displace existing employees or be used as substitutes for regular workers.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(5)</num>
            <heading>Training and retraining for employment.—</heading>
            <text>Programs for pre-employment training and retraining for persons 16 years of age and above. Priority shall be given to participants who meet the eligibility criteria and standards of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, as identified in regulations issued to implement this subchapter. Training programs established pursuant to this paragraph may be coupled with those conducted pursuant to paragraphs (3) and (4) of this subsection.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>Employment under the programs established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section may be provided directly with the government of the District of Columbia or with the private sector on a fully funded, partially or match-funded basis through grants to or by contract with nonprofit or profit-making organizations, associations, institutions or businesses. The Mayor shall not use more than 10% of funds for the programs for administrative and vendor costs. The Mayor may enter into performance-based contracts to implement programs described in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>The programs established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section may include, but shall not be limited to, the following supportive services and activities: Transportation; orientation; counseling and training; supplies and equipment; and program promotion.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this section, to give priority to participants who meet the eligibility criteria and standards of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act means to engage in a good-faith effort to fill at least 30% of a program’s available positions with persons who meet the eligibility criteria and standards of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(e)</num>
          <text>An employer required by law to pay a minimum wage higher than that specified in this section shall pay such higher wage to persons employed pursuant to this section.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(f)</num>
          <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia shall issue regulations to implement this section. The rules and regulations issued by the Mayor for the purpose of implementing the provisions of this section shall be submitted by the Mayor to the Council of the District of Columbia for a 45 calendar-day review period, excluding days of Council recess. No such rules or regulations shall take effect until the end of the 45 calendar-day period beginning on the day such rules or regulations are transmitted by the Mayor to the Chairman of the Council, and then only if during such period the Council does not adopt a resolution disapproving such rules and regulations in whole or in part.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(g)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The Department of Employment Services shall collect, and publish on its website, aggregated information on the participants of the summer youth jobs program, including statistics on:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>The demographics of participants;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>Participants’ activities in the program; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(C)</num>
              <text>Participants’ employment following the end of the program.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The information required by paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be published by February 1, 2016 and annually thereafter.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>It is the sense of the Council that the Department of Employment Services shall consult with the Council on revising the existing evaluation requirement for the summer youth jobs program to focus on program outcomes and program effectiveness.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>With regard to the summer 2015 program only, the Mayor shall conduct an assessment and evaluation of employment outcomes for summer employment participants 22 through 24 years of age.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <annotations>
          <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 1070 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle H of title I of the act may be cited as the “Summer Youth Employment Amendment Act of 2009”.</text>
          <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 2231 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided that subtitle T of title II of the act may be cited as the “Youth Workforce Development Planning and Evaluation Amendment Act of 2010”.</text>
          <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 2061 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> provided that subtitle G of title II of the act may be cited as “Summer Youth Employment Compensation Amendment Act of 2011”.</text>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-46" type="History" path="§2">Jan. 5, 1980, D.C. Law 3-46, § 2, 26 DCR 2310</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-124" type="History">July 2, 1982, D.C. Law 4-124, § 2, 29 DCR 2091</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-193" type="History">Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-193, § 2, 30 DCR 43</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-211" type="History">Feb. 28, 1987, D.C. Law 6-211, § 2, 34 DCR 847</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-231" type="History">May 10, 1989, D.C. Law 7-231, § 45, 36 DCR 492</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-22" type="History">Oct. 18, 2005, D.C. Law 16-22, § 2, 52 DCR 8076</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305" type="History">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 44, 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-221" type="History">Sept. 11, 2008, D.C. Law 17-221, § 2, 55 DCR 8293</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-223" type="History">Sept. 11, 2008, D.C. Law 17-223, § 2, 55 DCR 8297</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 1071, 57 DCR 181</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 2232(a), 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 2062, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 2032, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
          <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-328.05">1-328.05</cite>, § <cite path="§32-243">32-243</cite>, § <cite path="§32-771">32-771</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-1818.03">47-1818.03</cite>.</annotation>
          <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 36-702.</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-22">D.C. Law 16-22</cite>, rewrote subsec. (a)(1) which had read as follows: “(1) Summer youth jobs.—A summer youth jobs program to provide for the employment each summer of youths between the ages of 14 and 21 on the date of enrollment in the program, at a rate equal to the federal minimum wage as established by § 6 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 ( 29 U.S.C. § 206). The weekly number of hours of such employment shall be established according to the age of the youth to be employed and the nature and requirements of the job, but shall not be less than 20 nor more than 40 hours per week. Employment under this program may include an appropriate number of supervisory positions at a wage not to exceed the federal minimum wage by more than 12%.”</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite>, in subsec. (d)(4)(B), substituted “An individual with a disability” for “A handicapped individual”.</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-221">D.C. Law 17-221</cite> rewrote subsec. (d).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-223">D.C. Law 17-223</cite>, in subsec. (a)(2), substituted “basis, with the minimum of 10 hours per week,” for “basis”; in subsecs. (a)(2), (3), substituted “residents; provided, that youth who are not economically disadvantaged or public housing residents shall be eligible for the program” for “residents”; and, in subsec. (b), added “The Mayor shall not use more than 10% of funds for the programs for administrative and vendor costs.”</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite>, in subsec. (a)(1)(A), substituted “no less than 10,000 and no more than 21,000 youth” for “10,000 youth”; added subsec. (a)(1)(A-i ); and, in subsec. (a)(1)(B), substituted “period of no more than 6 weeks” for “minimum of”.</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> added a section heading; and, in subsec. (a)(1)(B), substituted “25 hours” for “40 hours”.</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> rewrote subsec. (a)(1)(A), which formerly read:</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(1)(A) Summer youth jobs—A summer youth jobs program to provide for the employment each summer of no less than 10,000 and no more than 21,000 youth between 14 and 21 years of age on the date of enrollment in the program, at a rate at least equal to the federal minimum wage established by section 6 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, approved June 25, 1938 (52 Stat. 1062;  29 U.S.C. § 206).”</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> rewrote (a)(1)(A) and (A-i); substituted “but shall not be fewer than 20 hours or more than 40 hours” for “but shall not be less than 20 nor more than 25 hours” in (a)(1)(B); rewrote (a)(1)(C); repealed (a)(1) (E); rewrote (a)(2), (3), (4), and (5); added the last sentence in (b); rewrote (d); and added (g).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Access to Youth Employment Programs Temporary Amendment Act of 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-75">D.C. Law 17-75</cite>, January 23, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 1455).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Youth Employment and Work Readiness Training Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-23">D.C. Law 21-23</cite>, Sept. 17, 2015,  62 DCR 8852).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 10 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-76">D.C. Law 21-76</cite>, Feb. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 264).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Marion S. Barry Summer Youth Employment Expansion Temporary Amendment Act of 2016 <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-104"> D.C. Law 21-104</cite>, April 20, 2016, 63 DCR 3656, 20 DCSTAT 3149).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Access to Youth Employment Programs Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-170, October 26, 2007,  54 DCR 10982).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1071 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2261 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1071 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2261 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2232(a) of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Youth Employment and Work Readiness Training Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-73, May 26, 2015,  62 DCR 6884, 21 DCSTAT 1449).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Youth Employment and Work Readiness Training Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-93, June 17, 2015,  62 DCR 8852).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2032 and 2034 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-23">D.C. Law 21-23</cite>, see § 2033 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-164, Oct. 16, 2015,  62 DCR 13734).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 8 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-292, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1211).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2 and 3 of the Marion S. Barry Summer Youth Employment Expansion Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-306, Feb. 18, 2016,  63 DCR 2180).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Authorization of funds for contract with D.C. Street Academy: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 4-124">D.C. Law 4-124</cite> provided that during the fiscal year ending September 30, 1983, the expenditure of funds is authorized for a direct contract with the D.C. Street Academy, a nonprofit, certified, and accredited secondary school specifically designed and established to serve the target population identified in § <cite path="§36-702">36-702</cite>(a)(5) § <cite path="§32-241">32-241</cite>, (2001 Ed.).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Editor's Notes" app="2016-05-12" eff="2016-05-12" doc="D.C. Law 21-112" path="§2">
       Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-112" path="">D.C. Law 21-112</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-112" path="§3">§ 3 of D.C. Law 21-112</cite> provided that the change made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-112" path="§2">§ 2 of D.C. Law 21-112</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been given effect.
      </annotation>
          <annotation app="2016-05-12" doc="D.C. Law 21-112" eff="2016-05-12" path="§2" type="History"/>
        </annotations>
      </section>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-242.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-243.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-244.xml"/>
    </container>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Employment Opportunities for Individuals with Disabilities.</heading>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>I</num>
      <heading>Employment Opportunities.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-301.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-302.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-303.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-304.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-305.xml"/>
    </container>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>II</num>
      <heading>Rehabilitation Services Program.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-331.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-331.01.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-332.xml"/>
    </container>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Employment Services Licensing and Regulation.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-401.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-402.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-403.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-404.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-405.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-406.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-407.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-408.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-409.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-410.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-411.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-412.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-413.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-414.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-415.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-416.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Family and Medical Leave.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-501.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-502.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-503.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-504.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-505.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-506.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-507.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-508.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-509.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-510.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-511.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-512.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-513.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-514.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-515.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-516.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-517.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>5A</num>
    <heading>Freedom to Contract Within the Broadcast Industry.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-531.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-532.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-533.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Government Pay Equity and Training.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-601.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-602.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-603.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-604.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-605.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-606.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-607.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-608.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-609.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>7</num>
    <heading>Health Care Benefits Expansion.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-701.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-702.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-703.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-704.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-705.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-706.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-707.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-708.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-709.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-710.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>7A</num>
    <heading>Health Coverage Continuation.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-731.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-732.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-733.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-734.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>7B</num>
    <heading>Job Opportunity Bank.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-751.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-752.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-753.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-754.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-755.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-756.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>7C</num>
    <heading>Job Training and Adult Education Programs Quarterly Reports.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-771.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>8</num>
    <heading>Industrial Safety.</heading>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>I</num>
      <heading>General.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-801.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-802.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-803.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-804.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-805.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-806.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-807.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-808.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-809.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-810.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-811.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-812.xml"/>
    </container>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>II</num>
      <heading>Seats for Employees.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-831.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-832.xml"/>
    </container>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>8A</num>
    <heading>Labor Peace Agreements for Hotel Development Projects.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-851.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-852.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-853.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-854.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-855.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-856.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>9</num>
    <heading>Lie Detectors.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-901.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-902.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-903.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>9A</num>
    <heading>Prohibition of Pre-Employment Marijuana Testing.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-931.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-932.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>10</num>
    <heading>Minimum Wages.</heading>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>I</num>
      <heading>General.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1001.xml"/>
      <section>
        <num>32-1002</num>
        <heading>Definitions.</heading>
        <text>For the purposes of this subchapter:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The term “employ” includes to suffer or permit to work.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The term “employee” includes any individual employed by an employer, except that this term shall not include:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Any individual who, without payment and without expectation of any gain, directly or indirectly, volunteers to engage in the activities of an educational, charitable, religious, or nonprofit organization;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Any lay member elected or appointed to office within the discipline of any religious organization and engaged in religious functions; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Any individual employed as a casual babysitter, in or about the residence of the employer.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>The term “employer” includes the District of Columbia government, any individual, partnership, general contractor, subcontractor, association, corporation, business trust, or any person or group of persons acting directly or indirectly in the interest of an employer in relation to an employee, but shall not include the United States government.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>The term “gratuities” means voluntary monetary contributions received by an employee from a guest, patron, or customer for services rendered.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>The term “Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia or the Mayor’s designated agent or representative, including the Department of Employment Services.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>The term “occupation” means any occupation, service, trade, business, industry, or branch or group of occupations or industries, or employment or class of employment, in which employees are gainfully employed.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6A)</num>
          <text>The term “office building” means any commercial property where the primary functions are the transaction of administrative, business, civic, or professional services, including properties where handling goods, wares, or merchandise, in limited quantities, is accessory to the primary occupancy or use. The term “office building” does not include libraries, museums, or universities.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>The term “regular rate” means all remuneration for employment paid to, or on behalf of, the employee, but shall not be considered to include the items set forth in the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended, 29 U.S.C. § 207(e)(1), (2), (3), (4), (5), (6), and (7). Extra compensation paid as described in § 207(e)(5), (6), and (7) shall be creditable toward overtime compensation.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7A)</num>
          <text>The term “security officer” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 2100 of Title 17 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>The term “wage” means compensation due to an employee by reason of the employee’s employment, payable in legal tender of the United States or checks on banks convertible into cash on demand at full face value, including allowances as may be permitted by any regulation issued under §§ <cite path="§32-1003">32-1003</cite> and <cite path="§32-1006">32-1006</cite>.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>The term “Washington metropolitan region” means the area consisting of the District of Columbia, Montgomery, and Prince George’s Counties in Maryland, Arlington and Fairfax Counties and the Cities of Alexandria, Fairfax and Falls Church in Virginia.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>The term “working time” means all the time the employee:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Is required to be on the employer’s premises, on duty, or at a prescribed place;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Is permitted to work;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Is required to travel in connection with the business of the employer; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>Waits on the employer’s premises for work.</text>
          </para>
          <aftertext>Interpretations of what constitutes working time shall be made in accordance with Title 29 of the Code of Federal Regulations, Part 785, Hours Worked Under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended, except that references to interpretations of the Portal-to-Portal Act shall have no force and effect.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <annotations>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-248" type="History" path="§3">Mar. 25, 1993, D.C. Law 9-248, § 3, 40 DCR 761</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-114" type="History">Mar. 20, 2008, D.C. Law 17-114, § 2(a), 55 DCR 1276</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-157" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-157, § 3(a), 61 DCR 10157</annotation>
          <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 36-220.1.</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-114">D.C. Law 17-114</cite> added pars. (6A) and (7A).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite> added “general contractor, subcontractor” in (3).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-240">D.C. Law 20-240</cite>, March 13, 2015,  62 DCR 1332).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-57">D.C. Law 21-57</cite>, Jan. 30, 2016,  62 DCR 15602).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 2(c) of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-544, Dec. 29, 2014,  62 DCR 243, 20 STAT 4458).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-188, Oct. 27, 2015,  62 DCR 14224).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-293, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1215).</annotation>
          <annotation type="References in Text">The “Portal-to-Portal Act”, referred to in (10), is  29 U.S.C. § 251 et seq.</annotation>
          <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 2014, and that the act shall apply to violations occurring after October 1, 2014.</annotation>
          <annotation app="2016-08-19" doc="D.C. Law 21-144" eff="2016-08-19" path="§2|(a)|(1)" type="History"/>
          <annotation app="2016-08-19" doc="D.C. Law 21-144" eff="2016-08-19" path="§2|(a)|(2)" type="History"/>
        </annotations>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>32-1003</num>
        <heading>Requirements.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Except as provided in subsection (h) of this section, as of January 1, 2005, the minimum wage required to be paid to any employee by any employer in the District of Columbia shall be $6.60 an hour, or the minimum wage set by the United States government pursuant to the Fair Labor Standards Act (29 U.S.C. § 206 et seq.) (“Fair Labor Standards Act”), plus $1, whichever is greater.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Except as provided in subsection (h) of this section, as of January 1, 2006, the minimum wage required to be paid to any employee by any employer in the District of Columbia shall be $7 an hour, or the minimum wage set by the United States government pursuant to the Fair Labor Standards Act, plus $1, whichever is greater.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Except as provided in subsection (h) of this section, as of July 1, 2014, the minimum wage required to be paid to any employee by any employer in the District of Columbia shall be $9.50 an hour, or the minimum wage set by the United States government pursuant to the Fair Labor Standards Act, plus $1, whichever is greater.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>Except as provided in subsection (h) of this section, as of July 1, 2015, the minimum wage required to be paid to any employee by any employer in the District of Columbia shall be $10.50 an hour, or the minimum wage set by the United States government pursuant to the Fair Labor Standards Act, plus $1, whichever is greater.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(5)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Except as provided in subsection (h) of this section and subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, the minimum hourly wage required to be paid to an employee by an employer shall be as of:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(i)</num>
                <text>July 1, 2016:  $11.50;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <text>July 1, 2017: $12.50;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <text>July 1, 2018: $13.25;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <text>July 1, 2019: $14.00; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(v)</num>
                <text>July 1, 2020: $15.00.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>If the minimum wage set by the United States government pursuant to the Fair Labor Standards Act ("U.S. minimum wage") is greater than the minimum hourly wage currently being paid pursuant to subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the minimum hourly wage paid to an employee by an employer shall be the U.S. minimum wage plus $1.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(6)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Except as provided in subsection (h) of this section, beginning on July 1, 2021, and no later than July 1 of each successive year, the minimum wage provided in this subsection shall be increased in proportion to the annual average increase, if any, in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers in the Washington Metropolitan Statistical Area published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the United States Department of Labor for the previous calendar year. Any increase under this paragraph shall be adjusted to the nearest multiple of $.05.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>Repealed.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>A person shall be employed in the District of Columbia when:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The person regularly spends more than 50% of their working time in the District of Columbia; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The person’s employment is based in the District of Columbia and the person regularly spends a substantial amount of their working time in the District of Columbia and not more than 50% of their working time in any particular state.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>No employer shall employ any employee for a workweek that is longer than 40 hours, unless the employee receives compensation for employment in excess of 40 hours at a rate not less than 1 1/2 times the regular rate at which the employee is employed.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>All workers with disabilities shall be paid at a rate not less than the minimum wage, except in those instances where a certificate has been issued by the United States Department of Labor that authorizes the payment of less to workers with disabilities under § 214(c) of the Fair Labor Standards Act [29 U.S.C. § 214(c)].</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(e)</num>
          <text>No employer shall be deemed to have violated subsection (c) of this section if the employee works for a retail or service establishment and:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The regular rate of pay of the employee is in excess of 11/2 times the minimum hourly rate applicable to the employee under this subchapter; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>More than 1/2 of the employee’s compensation for a representative period (not less than 1 month) represents commissions on goods or services.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(f)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The minimum hourly wage required to be paid by an employer to an employee who receives gratuities ("tipped minimum wage"), provided that the employee actually receives gratuities in an amount at least equal to the difference between the hourly wage paid and the minimum hourly wage as set by subsection (a) of this section, shall be as of:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>January 1, 2005: $2.77;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>July 1, 2017: $3.33;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(C)</num>
              <text>July 1, 2018: $3.89:</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(D)</num>
              <text>July 1, 2019: $ 4.45; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(E)</num>
              <text>July 1, 2020: $ 5.00.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Beginning on July 1, 2021, and no later than July 1 of each successive year, the tipped minimum wage shall be increased in proportion to the annual average increase, if any, in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers in the Washington Metropolitan Statistical Area published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the United States Department of Labor for the previous calendar year. Any increase under this paragraph shall be adjusted to the nearest multiple of $.05.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(f-1)</num>
          <text>The Mayor shall publish in the District of Columbia Register, on the Department of Employment Services website, and make available to employers in a bulletin, the adjusted minimum hourly wage to be paid by an employer to an employee pursuant to subsections (a)(5) and (6) and (f) of this section at least 30 days before an increase is scheduled to go into effect.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(g)</num>
          <text>Subsection (f) of this section shall not apply to an employee who receives gratuities unless:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The employee has been informed by the employer of the provisions of subsection (f) of this section; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>All gratuities received by the employee have been retained by the employee, except that this provision shall not be construed to prohibit the pooling of gratuities among employees who customarily receive gratuities.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(h)</num>
          <text>An employer shall pay a security officer working in an office building in the District of Columbia wages, or any combination of wages and benefits, that are not less than the combined amount of the minimum wage and fringe benefit rate for the guard 1 classification established by the United States Secretary of Labor pursuant to the Service Contract Act of 1965, approved October 22, 1965 (79 Stat. 1034; 41 U.S.C. § 351), as amended.</text>
        </para>
        <annotations>
          <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-91">D.C. Law 20-91</cite> provided that § 2(b)-(d) of the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
          <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7004 of Law 20-155 repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-91">D.C. Law 20-91</cite>, § 3.</text>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-248" type="History" path="§4">Mar. 25, 1993, D.C. Law 9-248, § 4, 40 DCR 761</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-296" type="History">Apr. 8, 2005, D.C. Law 15-296, § 2, 52 DCR 1483</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305" type="History">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 47, 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-114" type="History">Mar. 20, 2008, D.C. Law 17-114, § 2(b), 55 DCR 1276</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-91" type="History">Mar. 11, 2014, D.C. Law 20-91, § 2(a), 61 DCR 778</annotation>
          <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§4-205.19k">4-205.19k</cite>, § <cite path="§32-1002">32-1002</cite>, § <cite path="§32-1004">32-1004</cite>, § <cite path="§32-1006">32-1006</cite>, and § <cite path="§32-1607">32-1607</cite>.</annotation>
          <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 36-220.2.</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-296">D.C. Law 15-296</cite> rewrote subsecs. (a) and (f) which had read:</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a) On October 1, 1993, the minimum wage required to be paid to any employee by any employer in the District of Columbia shall be the minimum wage set by the United States government from time to time pursuant to the Fair Labor Standards Act ( 29 U.S.C. § 206 et seq.) (”Fair Labor Standards Act“), plus $1.”</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(f) In determining the wage of an employee who receives gratuities, the amount paid to the employee by the employer shall be deemed to be increased on account of gratuities by an amount determined by the employer, but not by an amount in excess of 55% of the minimum wage as set by subsection (a) of this section, except that the amount of the increase on account of gratuities determined by the employer shall not exceed the value of gratuities received by the employee.”</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite>, in subsec. (d), substituted “workers with disabilities” for “handicapped workers”.</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-114">D.C. Law 17-114</cite>, in subsecs. (a)(1) and (2), substituted “Except as provided in subsection (h) of this section, as” for “As”; and added subsec. (h).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-91">D.C. Law 20-91</cite> added (a)(3), (a)(4), (a)(5) and (a)(6).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Minimum Wage Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-614, November 30, 2004,  51 DCR 11438).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Minimum Wage Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-19, February 17, 2005,  52 DCR 20965).</annotation>
          <annotation app="2016-08-19" doc="D.C. Law 21-144" eff="2016-08-19" path="§2|(b)|(1)|(A)" type="History"/>
          <annotation app="2016-08-19" doc="D.C. Law 21-144" eff="2016-08-19" path="§2|(b)|(1)|(B)|(i)" type="History"/>
          <annotation app="2016-08-19" doc="D.C. Law 21-144" eff="2016-08-19" path="§2|(b)|(1)|(B)|(ii)" type="History"/>
          <annotation app="2016-08-19" doc="D.C. Law 21-144" eff="2016-08-19" path="§2|(b)|(2)" type="History"/>
          <annotation app="2016-08-19" doc="D.C. Law 21-144" eff="2016-08-19" path="§2|(b)|(3)" type="History"/>
        </annotations>
      </section>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1004.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1005.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1006.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1007.xml"/>
      <section>
        <num>32-1007.01</num>
        <heading>Reporting.</heading>
        <text>The Mayor shall submit biannually a report to the Council regarding any audits or inspections conducted related to compliance with <cite path="32|10|I">this subchapter</cite> or any regulation issued pursuant to <cite path="32|10|I">this subchapter</cite>. Each report shall include:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The number of employers inspected for compliance due to complaints received, categorized by size of the employer based on the number of employees;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The number of employers inspected for compliance as a result of a random audit, categorized by size of the employer based on the number of employees;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>The number of violations, by type of violation; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>An explication of the actions the Mayor took pursuant to <cite path="§32-1011">§ 32-1011</cite> against each employer charged with violating <cite path="32|10|I">this subchapter</cite> or any regulation issued pursuant to <cite path="32|10|I">this subchapter</cite>, including a list of fines assessed against the employer.</text>
        </para>
        <annotations>
          <annotation app="1993-03-25" doc="D.C. Law 9-248" eff="1993-03-25" path="§8a" type="History"/>
          <annotation app="2016-08-19" doc="D.C. Law 21-144" eff="2016-08-19" path="§2|(d)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
        </annotations>
      </section>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1008.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1008.01.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1009.xml"/>
      <section>
        <num>32-1009.01</num>
        <heading>Notice requirements for tipped wages.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>An employer who employs an employee who is paid in accordance with § <cite path="§32-1003">32-1003</cite>(f) shall submit a quarterly wage report within 30 days of the end of each quarter to the Mayor certifying that the employee was paid the required minimum wage.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The Mayor shall create an Internet-based portal for online reporting of the quarterly wage reports required by subsection (a) of this section.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>An employer shall submit its quarterly wage reports online unless the employer claims that online reporting creates a hardship, in which case the employer shall submit its reports in hard-copy form.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>The Mayor shall provide reporting requirements training to educate employers about the reporting requirements and use of the Internet-based portal.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>The Mayor shall:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Perform random reporting audits after each quarterly report deadline to ensure compliance; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Submit a quarterly report to the Secretary to the Council of the compliance data collected.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <annotations>
          <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-91">D.C. Law 20-91</cite> was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7003, effective Feb. 26, 2015.</text>
          <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-91">D.C. Law 20-91</cite>: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-91">D.C. Law 20-91</cite> provided that sections 2(b)-(d) of the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
          <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 2014, and that the act shall apply to violations occurring after October 1, 2014.</text>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-248" type="History" path="§10a">Mar. 25, 1993, D.C. Law 9-248, § 10a</annotation>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-91" type="History">as added Mar. 11, 2014, D.C. Law 20-91, § 2(c), 61 DCR 778</annotation>
          <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-91">D.C. Law 20-91</cite> added this section.</annotation>
          <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-240">D.C. Law 20-240</cite>, March 13, 2015,  62 DCR 1332).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-57">D.C. Law 21-57</cite>, Jan. 30, 2016,  62 DCR 15602).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-91">D.C. Law 20-91</cite> § 3, see § 7004 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-91">D.C. Law 20-91</cite>, § 3, see § 7004 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-91">D.C. Law 20-91</cite>, § 3, see § 7004 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-188, Oct. 27, 2015,  62 DCR 14224).</annotation>
          <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-293, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1215).</annotation>
          <annotation app="2016-08-19" doc="D.C. Law 21-144" eff="2016-08-19" path="§2|(c)" type="History"/>
        </annotations>
      </section>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1010.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1011.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1011.01.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1012.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1012.01.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1013.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1014.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1015.xml"/>
    </container>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>II</num>
      <heading>Repealed Provisions.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1031.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1032.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1033.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1034.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1035.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1036.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1037.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1038.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1039.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1040.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1041.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1042.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1043.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1044.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1045.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1046.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1047.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1048.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1049.xml"/>
    </container>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>10A</num>
    <heading>Building Service Employees Minimum Work Week.</heading>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.01</num>
      <heading>Definitions.</heading>
      <text>For the purposes of <cite path="32|10A">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>"Covered employee" or "building services employee" means an individual performing janitorial services, building maintenance services, or other services in or around a covered location to maintain the repair, cleanliness, and overall quality of the covered location.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>"Covered employer" means an individual, group of individuals, partnership, association, corporation, business trust, society, firm, company, joint stock company, or other entity that at a covered location:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Directly employs a covered employee;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Contracts for the services of a covered employee; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Subcontracts for the services of a covered employee.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>"Covered leave" means paid or unpaid temporary leave from work taken by a covered employee pursuant to:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Federal or District law;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>An employee handbook; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>A written request voluntarily initiated by the covered employee.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>"Covered location" means an office building, commonly owned office park, or a commonly owned and managed group of buildings, with over 350,000 square feet of net rentable commercial office space.  The term "covered location" excludes property owned or leased by a health-care facility licensed under the Health-Care and Community Residence Facility, Hospice and Home Care Licensure Act of 1983, effective February 24, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-48; D.C. Official Code § 44-501 <em>et seq.</em>), and affiliated subsidiaries.
          </text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>"Minimum work week" means the minimum number of compensated hours provided to a covered employee in any work week, including weeks in which the covered employee is taking covered leave.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <text>"Office park" means an area where a number of office buildings are together on landscaped grounds, which may include parking lots, parklike surroundings, and restaurants.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(7)</num>
        <text>"Work week" means a fixed regularly recurring period of 168 hours or 7 consecutive 24-hour periods.</text>
      </para>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§2" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.02</num>
      <heading>Minimum work week.</heading>
      <text>The minimum work week for a building services employee shall be 30 hours; except, that when a covered employee is taking covered leave, the leave shall count towards the 30-hour minimum work week; provided, that at each covered location up to 20% of the work hours scheduled for covered employees engaged in cleaning service may be preserved for part-time covered employees with a minimum shift of 4 hours per night and 20 hours per week per covered employee for up to a total of 10 part-time positions permitted per covered location.</text>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.03</num>
      <heading>Prohibited acts.</heading>
      <text>It shall be a violation of this act for a covered employer to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Fail to provide a minimum work week as required by this act or a regulation issue pursuant to this act;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Discharge, threaten, penalize, or in any other manner discriminate or retaliate against a covered employee because the covered employee has:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Made, or is believed to have made, a complaint to the covered employer, the Mayor, the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, a federal employee, or District government employee that the covered employer has engaged in conduct that the covered employee, reasonably and in good faith, believes violates this act or a regulation issued pursuant to this act;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Instituted, or will institute, a proceeding alleging a violation of this act;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Provided information related to a possible violation of this act to the Mayor, the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, or a federal or District government employee;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>Testified, or will testify, in an investigation or proceeding being conducted pursuant to this act; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(E)</num>
          <text>Exercised any other right protected by this act; or</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Hinder the Mayor in the enforcement of this act, including by failing to:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Admit the Mayor to a covered location;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Make available any record required to be made or retained by this act; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Post a summary or copy of this act and of any applicable regulation, as required by section 5.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§4" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.04</num>
      <heading>Posting requirements.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>A covered employer shall post and maintain in a conspicuous place a notice, which shall be prescribed by the Mayor and provided to each covered employer, that shall include excerpts or summaries of the pertinent provisions of this act and information about filing of a complaint pursuant to the act.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>A covered employer shall post every notice required to be posted by this act in English and all languages spoken by covered employees with limited or no-English proficiency, as defined in section 2 of the Language Access Act of 2004, effective June 19, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-167; D.C. Official Code § 2-1931).</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>A covered employer who fails to comply with the posting requirements of this section shall be subject to the penalty set forth in section 8.</text>
      </para>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§5" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.05</num>
      <heading>Mayor's authority.</heading>
      <text>The Mayor shall have the authority to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Investigate and ascertain the minimum work week of a covered employee;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Enter and inspect a covered location of a covered employer to:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Inspect and copy:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Books;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>Registers;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iii)</num>
            <text>Payrolls; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iv)</num>
            <text>Other records the Mayor considers necessary or appropriate; or</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Question a covered employee to ascertain whether the covered employer is in compliance with the requirements of this act;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Require a covered employer to provide a sworn statement pertaining to the employment of a covered employee regarding:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Wages and hours; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Any other information pertaining to the employment of the covered employee that the Mayor considers necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this act; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Following an admission of a violation by a respondent to a complaint, conduct an audit or issue a subpoena to determine if the rights of covered employees other than the complainant have also been violated.</text>
      </para>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§6" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.06</num>
      <heading>Confidentiality of reported information.</heading>
      <text>To encourage reporting and protect personal information received pursuant to this act, the Mayor shall keep confidential, to the maximum extent authorized by law, the name and any other identifying information of a covered employee, or other person, reporting a violation of this act during the course of an investigation; provided, that with the authorization of the covered employee or other person, whichever is applicable, the Mayor may disclose the name of the covered employee or other person and such identifying information as necessary to conduct a hearing and enforce this act or other employee-protection law.</text>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§7" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.07</num>
      <heading>Penalties.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, a covered employer who willfully violates the posting requirements of section 5 shall be assessed a civil penalty not to exceed $100 for each day that the covered employer fails to post the notice; provided, that the total penalty shall not exceed $500.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>No liability for failure to post the notice shall arise under this section if the Mayor has failed to provide the notice required by section 5 to the covered employer.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>A covered employer who fails to comply with any of the requirements of this act, other than the posting requirements of section 5, shall be subject to a fine of not more than $5,000 for each violation for each day that the violation continues.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this subsection, each violation of a covered employee's right provided by this act shall constitute a separate violation of this act.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Mayor shall assess an administrative penalty against a covered employer for a violation of this act. In assessing the amount of the fine to be imposed pursuant to the following authorized penalties, the Mayor may consider factors the Mayor determines appropriate, including a covered employer's past history of violations of this act:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>For the first violation, a maximum fine of up to $500; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>For any subsequent violation, a maximum fine of up to $1,000.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>No administrative penalty may be collected unless the Mayor provided a covered employer alleged to have violated this act:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Notification of the violation;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>The amount of the administrative penalty that may be imposed; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>An opportunity to request a hearing.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§8" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.08</num>
      <heading>Administrative action by the Mayor.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Subject to the statute of limitations described in subsection (b) of this section, upon a request by a covered employee for administrative enforcement of this act, the Mayor shall investigate and make an initial determination regarding the alleged violation.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, an aggrieved covered employee ("complainant") shall file a signed complaint against a covered employer for failure to provide a minimum work week with the Mayor no later than 3 years after the last date upon which the alleged violation occurred.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>A complainant may recover only those amounts that became lawfully due and payable within the 3-year period before the date the complaint was filed; except, that if the alleged failure to provide a minimum work week is ongoing at the time of the filing of the complaint, the complainant may also seek recovery of those amounts that accrued during the pendency of the claim.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>The 3-year statute of limitations shall be tolled during any period that the covered employer had failed to provide the covered employee with actual or constructive notice of the covered employee's rights or on other equitable grounds.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>The complaint shall:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Set forth the facts upon which it is based with sufficient specificity to determine that an allegation of failure to provide a minimum work week has been made;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Meet other criteria required in this section, or by regulations issued pursuant to this act;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Be sworn to as true by the complainant; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Include, or be attached thereto, the following information:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>The complainant's name, address, and telephone number (or alternate address or telephone number if the complainant desires);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Sufficient information to enable the Mayor to identify the covered employer through District records, such as the covered employer's:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>Name;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>Business address;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(iii)</num>
              <text>Motor vehicle license plate number; or</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(iv)</num>
              <text>Telephone number; and</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>If not set forth in the statement of facts required by paragraph (1) of this subsection, an explanation of the alleged violations, which may include:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>The approximate or actual dates the violations occurred;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>The estimated total amount of unpaid wages: and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(iii)</num>
              <text>An explanation of how the estimated total amount of unpaid wages was calculated.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>The Mayor may, as the Mayor determines necessary or appropriate, request that the complainant amend a complaint considered insufficient, including to:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Cure technical defects or omissions;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Clarify or amplify allegations; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>More fully or adequately allege the charge set forth in the original complaint.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The Mayor shall mail the complaint and the written notices described in paragraph (2) of this subsection to the covered employer or, if more than one, to each covered employer ("respondent").</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Notice to the respondent shall set forth the:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>Damages, penalties, and other costs for which the respondent may be liable;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>Rights and obligations of the parties; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(iii)</num>
              <text>Process for contesting the complaint.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Notice to covered employees shall state that an investigation by the Mayor is being conducted and provide information on how covered employees may participate in the investigation.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(f)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Upon receipt of the notice required by subsection (e)(2)(B) of this section, the respondent shall post the notice in a conspicuous place for a period of at least 30 days.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Within 20 days from the date the complaint and written notices are mailed, the respondent shall:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Admit that the allegations in the complaint are true; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Deny the allegations in the complaint and request that the Mayor make an initial determination regarding the allegations in the complaint.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>If a respondent admits the allegations, the Mayor shall issue an administrative order requiring the respondent to pay the unpaid wages due and, if any, other compensation, liquidated damages, and fine or penalty owed, and to cure the violation.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>If a respondent fails to respond to the allegations within 20 days as required by paragraph (2) of this subsection, the allegations in the complaint shall be deemed admitted and the Mayor shall issue an initial determination requiring the respondent to pay unpaid wages due and, if any, compensation, liquidated damages, and fine or penalty owed, and to cure the violation.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>The Mayor shall issue an initial determination within 120 days after the date the complaint is received. The initial determination shall contain:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>A brief summary of the evidence considered;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>The findings of fact;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(iii)</num>
              <text>The conclusions of law;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(iv)</num>
              <text>An order detailing the amount owed by the respondent or other relief, if any;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(v)</num>
              <text>The process by which to appeal the Mayor's determination or to seek other relief; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(vi)</num>
              <text>A preliminary determination as to whether the complainant is entitled to additional unpaid earned wages due to other District laws, including the:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(I)</num>
                <text>Accrued Sick and Safe Leave Act of 2008, effective May 13, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-152; D.C. Official Code § 32-131.01 <em>et seq.</em>);
                  </text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(II)</num>
                <text>Living Wage Act of 2006, effective June 8, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-118; D. C. Official Code § 2-220.01 <em>et seq</em>.);
                  </text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(III)</num>
                <text>Minimum Wage Act Revision Act of 1992, effective March 25, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-248; D.C. Official Code § 32-1001 <em>et seq.</em>); and
                  </text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(IV)</num>
                <text>An Act To provide for the payment and collection of wages in the District of Columbia, approved August 3, 1956 (70 Stat. 976; D.C. Official Code § 32-1301 <em>et seq.</em>).
                  </text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>The initial determination shall be provided to both parties.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>If the Mayor fails to issue an initial determination within 120 days after the date the complaint is received, the complainant shall have a right to request a formal hearing before an administrative law judge.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§9" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.09</num>
      <heading>Conciliation of dispute.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>The Mayor shall work with the parties in an attempt to conciliate a dispute pursuant to this act; provided, that any conciliation agreement entered into shall be between the respondent and the complainant, which shall be reproduced by the Mayor as an administrative order ("CAO").</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>If the CAO is breached, the Mayor or the complainant may enforce the CAO pursuant to section 12.</text>
      </para>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§10" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.10</num>
      <heading>Hearing before administrative law judge.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Within 30 days after the issuance of the initial determination or administrative order, other than an administrative order issued pursuant to section 10, either party may file for a formal hearing before an administrative law judge.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>An administrative law judge shall:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, schedule a hearing within 30 days after the date a request for the hearing was filed;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Provide notice to the parties of the time and place of the hearing; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Upon conclusion of the hearing, issue an order based on the findings.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The administrative law judge may grant each party one discretionary continuance due to hardship or a scheduling conflict of up to 15 days, and any other request for good cause only.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>If a respondent does not appear after having received notice of the hearing pursuant to this section, the administrative law judge shall proceed to hear proof of the complaint and render judgment accordingly.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>If a complainant does not appear after having received notice of the hearing pursuant to this section, the administrative law judge shall dismiss the complaint without prejudice.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The parties may:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Appear at the hearing with or without counsel;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Submit evidence;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Cross-examine witnesses;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>Obtain the issuance of subpoenas; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(E)</num>
            <text>Otherwise be heard.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Testimony taken at the hearing, or given and received by telephone, shall be under oath, and a transcript shall be made available at cost to any individual, unless the case is sealed.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>The burden of proof by a preponderance of the evidence shall rest upon the complainant, but shall shift to the respondent if:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>A respondent failed to keep records of a covered employee's schedule of hours and hours worked, or records of the covered employee's compensation provided to the covered employee are:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>Imprecise;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>Inadequate;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(iii)</num>
              <text>Missing;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(iv)</num>
              <text>Fraudulently prepared or presented; or</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(v)</num>
              <text>Substantially incomplete; and</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>A complainant presents evidence to show, as a matter of just and reasonable inference, as determined by the judge, the hours the complainant was scheduled and amount of work done.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>If the burden of proof shifts to the respondent pursuant to paragraph 3 of this subsection, the respondent shall present compelling evidence:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>Of an exemption from applicability of the minimum work week required by this act; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>To negate the reasonableness of the inferences drawn from the complainant's evidence.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>If the respondent fails to meet the burden of proof, as required by subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the administrative law judge shall award damages to the complainant based on the complainant's evidence and may award approximate damages as necessary.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Within 30 days after the conclusion of the hearing, the administrative law judge shall issue:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>A decision setting forth a brief summary of the evidence considered, findings of fact, and conclusions of law; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>An order detailing the determined relief.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Relief may include:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>All wages the covered employer would have paid the covered employee had the covered employer complied with this act;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>Compensation;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(iii)</num>
              <text>Reasonable attorneys' fees and costs; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(iv)</num>
              <text>Liquidated damages.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>An administrative law judge may award in liquidated damages an amount of up to treble the amount of owed wages.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>The decision and order of the administrative law judge shall be a final administrative ruling.  It shall be enforceable in a court of competent jurisdiction and reviewable as provided by applicable law.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§11" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.11</num>
      <heading>Enforcement of administrative order or conciliation agreement.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>A respondent shall comply with the provisions of any order or conciliation agreement affording relief and shall furnish proof of compliance to the Mayor.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>If a respondent refuses or fails to comply with the administrative order or conciliation agreement, the Mayor or the complainant may record a lien and may sue in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for a remedy, enforcement, or assessment or collection of a civil penalty; provided, that the Superior Court of the District of Columbia shall have no jurisdiction to adjudicate the merits of the underlying claim but shall be limited to enforcement of the administrative order or conciliation agreement.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The Mayor may, at the request of a covered employee, take an assignment in trust for the assigning covered employee of wages and join in a proceeding or action of such claims against the same covered employer as the Mayor considers appropriate.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The Mayor shall have power to settle and adjust any such claim on the terms the Mayor considers just; provided, that no settlement for an amount less than the amount awarded by the administrative law judge shall be agreed to without the complainant's consent.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>The Mayor shall maintain regular contact with the complainant concerning the procedural status of any legal action brought under the assignment, and the complainant shall have the right to inquire about and receive information regarding the status of the legal action.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>If a respondent fails to timely comply with an administrative order or conciliation agreement that has not been stayed, the Mayor shall:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Assess an additional late fee equal to 10% of the total amount owed for each month any portion of the award and accrued late penalty remain unpaid;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Require the respondent to post public notice of its failure to comply, in a form determined by the Mayor; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Consider any unpaid amount to be owed the District as past due restitution on behalf of a covered employee; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>Suspend any licenses issued to the covered employer to do business in the District as set forth in subsection (d) of this section.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Penalty amounts, including civil penalties and late fees, and any wages, compensation, damages, interest, costs, or other fees awarded to a covered employee, or a representative of the covered employee, shall be a lien upon the real estate and personal property of the person who owes the foregoing.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>The lien shall take effect by operation of law on the day immediately following the due date for payment, and, unless dissolved by payment, shall as of that date be considered a tax due and owing to the District, which may be enforced through any procedure available for tax collection.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>The Mayor shall:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Deny an application for a license to do business issued by the District if, during the 3-year period before the date of the application, the applicant admitted guilt or liability or had been found guilty or liable in any judicial or administrative proceeding of committing or attempting to commit a willful violation of this act;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Suspend any license to do business issued by the District if the licensee has failed to comply with an administrative order issued or conciliation agreement entered into pursuant to this act; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Upon learning of a licensee's alleged lack of compliance with an administrative order issued or conciliation agreement entered into pursuant to this act, notify the licensee that its license shall be suspended in 30 days and remain suspended until the licensee provides proof that it is in compliance with the administrative order or conciliation agreement, whichever applies, including any requirements for accelerated payment, interest, or additional damages in the event of a breach; provided, that before a license may be suspended, the Mayor shall provide the licensee the opportunity to have a hearing pursuant to the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, effective October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 <em>et seq.</em>).
            </text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§12" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.12</num>
      <heading>Representation.</heading>
      <text>Any person may be represented by counsel in any proceeding under this act. Any party, including corporate entities, as an alternative to counsel, may be assisted by a non-attorney authorized by that party in accordance with section 2835 of Title 1 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (1 DCMR § 2835), except where such representation is prohibited by law or disallowed by the administrative law judge for good cause.</text>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§13" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.13</num>
      <heading>Subpoenas; noncompliance.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>Any party may request that a subpoena be issued by the administrative law judge.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>Witnesses summoned by subpoena shall be entitled to the same witness and mileage fees as are witnesses in proceedings in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia; provided, that fees payable to a witness summoned by subpoena issued at the request of a party shall be paid by that party.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>Within 10 days after service of a subpoena upon a person, the person may petition the administrative law judge to quash or modify the subpoena, which the administrative law judge shall grant, if the judge finds that:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The subpoena requires appearance or attendance at an unreasonable time or place;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The subpoena requires production of evidence that does not relate to the matter at issue;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>The subpoena does not describe with sufficient particularity the evidence to be produced;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Compliance with the subpoena would be unduly onerous; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>The subpoena fails for other good reason.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>In the case of a refusal to obey a subpoena, the administrative law judge or any party may seek enforcement of a subpoena issued under the authority of this act by filing a petition for enforcement in a court of competent jurisdiction. In the enforcement proceeding, the court may award to the prevailing party all or part of the costs and attorney's fees incurred in obtaining the enforcement order.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <text>A person who fails or neglects to attend a proceeding to which the person was duly called to testify or refuses to answer any lawful inquiry or demand to produce records, documents, or other evidence, without good cause, may be fined by a court of competent jurisdiction not more than the amount set forth in section 101 of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Amendment Act of 2012, effective June 11, 2013 (D.C. Law 19-317; D.C. Official Code § 22-3571.01) ("Criminal Fine Proportionality Act") or imprisoned not more than 60 days, or both.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(f)</num>
        <text>A person who makes or causes to be made a false entry or false statement of fact in any report, account, record, or other document submitted to an administrative law judge pursuant to a subpoena or other order or who willfully mutilates, alters, or by any other means falsifies any documentary evidence may be fined by a court of competent jurisdiction not more than the amount set forth in the Criminal Fine Proportionality Act or imprisoned not more than 60 days, or both.</text>
      </para>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§14" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.14</num>
      <heading>Costs and attorney's fees.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>In any action brought under this act, the administrative law judge shall allow a prevailing plaintiff to recover the costs of the action from the defendant, including costs or fees of any nature and reasonable attorney's fees.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>In an administrative order in favor of a covered employee and in any proceeding to enforce an administrative order, the court shall award to each attorney for the covered employee an additional judgment for costs, including reasonable attorney's fees.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>If fees remain unpaid to the attorney at the time of any subsequent review, supplementation, or reconsideration of the fee award, the administrative law judge shall update the award to reflect the hours actually expended and the market rates in effect at that time. No reduction shall be made from this rate, or from the hours actually expended, except upon clear and convincing evidence that the reduction will serve the remedial purposes of this law.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>Costs shall also include expert witness fees, depositions fees, witness fees, juror fees, filing fees, certification fees, the costs of collecting and presenting evidence, and any other costs incurred in connection with obtaining, preserving, or enforcing the administrative order.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <text>The Mayor shall not be required to pay the filing fee or other costs or fees of any nature or to file bond or other security of any nature in connection with any action or proceeding under this act.</text>
      </para>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§15" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.15</num>
      <heading>Civil action.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>A covered employee aggrieved by a violation of this act may bring a civil action in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia and may be awarded such legal or equitable relief as may be appropriate to effectuate the purposes of this act, including without limitation:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Reinstatement;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Payment of lost wages totaling not less than the hourly rate of pay due to the covered employee but for the violation multiplied by the number of hours below the minimum work week that the covered employee was provided each work week during which a violation occurred;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Actual medical costs incurred by the covered employee as a result of the violation;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Liquidated damages in the amount of $100 per day for each day the violation continued; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Reasonable attorney's fees and costs of the action to be paid by the defendant to a prevailing plaintiff.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>An action to recover damages under this act may be maintained in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia by one or more covered employees aggrieved by a violation of this act or on behalf of a covered employee or covered employees who are similarly situated as long as at least one of the covered employees has exhausted all administrative remedies.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>For the purposes of this subsection, 2 or more covered employees are similarly situated if they:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>Are or were employed by the same covered employer, whether concurrently or otherwise, at some point during the applicable statute of limitations period;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>Allege one or more violations that raise similar questions as to liability; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(iii)</num>
              <text>Seek similar forms of relief.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Covered employees alleging violations of this act shall not be considered dissimilar under this subsection solely because their claims seek damages that differ in amount or their job titles, or other means of classifying them differ in ways that are unrelated to their claims.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an action commenced for a violation of this act on or after the applicability of this act shall be commenced within 3 years after the cause of action accrued or of the last occurrence if the cause of action is continuous, whichever is later, or the cause of action shall be forever barred.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The 3-year statute of limitations shall be tolled:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>From the date the covered employee files an administrative complaint with the Mayor until the Mayor notifies the covered employee in writing that the administrative complaint has been resolved or the administrative complaint is withdrawn by the covered employee;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>During any period that the covered employer has failed to provide the covered employee with actual or constructive notice of the covered employee's rights; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>On other equitable grounds.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§16" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.16</num>
      <heading>Rules.</heading>
      <text>The Mayor, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 <em>et seq.</em>), shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this act.
        </text>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§17" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>32-1051.17</num>
      <heading>Applicability.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>This act shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of this act.</text>
          <text>Sec. .  Fiscal impact statement.</text>
          <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <annotations>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-157" eff="2016-10-08" path="§18" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>11</num>
    <heading>Occupational Safety and Health.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1101.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1102.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1103.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1104.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1105.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1106.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1107.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1108.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1109.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1110.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1111.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1112.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1113.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1114.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1115.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1116.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1117.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1118.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1119.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1120.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1121.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1122.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1123.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1124.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>12</num>
    <heading>Parental Leave.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1201.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1202.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1203.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1204.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1205.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1206.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>12A</num>
    <heading>Reasonable Accommodations for Pregnant and Nursing Workers.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1231.01.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1231.02.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1231.03.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1231.04.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1231.05.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1231.06.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1231.07.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1231.08.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1231.09.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1231.10.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1231.11.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1231.12.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1231.13.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1231.14.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1231.15.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>13</num>
    <heading>Wages and Workplace Fraud.</heading>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>I</num>
      <heading>Payment and Collection of Wages.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1301.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1302.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1303.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1304.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1305.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1306.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1307.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1307.01.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1308.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1308.01.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1309.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1310.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1311.xml"/>
    </container>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>II</num>
      <heading>Workplace Fraud.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1331.01.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1331.02.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1331.03.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1331.04.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1331.05.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1331.06.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1331.07.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1331.08.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1331.09.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1331.10.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1331.11.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1331.12.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1331.13.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1331.14.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1331.15.xml"/>
    </container>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>13A</num>
    <heading>Transitional Employment and Pre-Apprenticeship Programs.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1331.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1332.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>13B</num>
    <heading>Hiring of Ex-Offenders.</heading>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>I</num>
      <heading>Fair Criminal Record Screening.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1341.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1342.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1343.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1344.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1345.xml"/>
    </container>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>II</num>
      <heading>Public Works programs.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1351.xml"/>
    </container>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>13C</num>
    <heading>Prohibition on Discrimination against the Unemployed.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1361.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1362.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1363.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1364.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1365.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1366.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1367.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1368.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>13D</num>
    <heading>Unemployment Profile.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1371.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>14</num>
    <heading>Voluntary Apprentices.</heading>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>I</num>
      <heading>General.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1401.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1402.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1403.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1404.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1405.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1406.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1407.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1408.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1409.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1410.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1411.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1412.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1412.01.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1413.xml"/>
    </container>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>II</num>
      <heading>Registration Requirement for Contractors.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1431.xml"/>
    </container>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>14A</num>
    <heading>Wage Transparency.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1451.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1452.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1453.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1454.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1455.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1456.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1457.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>15</num>
    <heading>Workers’ Compensation.</heading>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1501.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1502.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1503.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1504.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1505.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1506.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1507.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1508.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1509.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1510.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1511.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1512.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1513.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1514.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1515.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1516.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1517.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1518.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1519.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1520.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1521.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1521.01.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1522.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1523.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1524.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1525.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1526.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1527.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1528.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1529.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1530.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1531.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1532.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1533.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1534.xml"/>
    <section>
      <num>32-1535</num>
      <heading>Compensation for injuries where third persons are liable.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>If, on account of a disability or death for which compensation is payable under this chapter, the person entitled to such compensation determines that some person other than those enumerated in § <cite path="§32-1504">32-1504</cite>(b) is liable for damages, he need not elect whether to receive such compensation or to recover damages against such third person.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>Acceptance of such compensation under an award in a compensation order filed with the Mayor shall operate as an assignment to the employer of all rights of the person entitled to compensation to recover damages against such third person unless such person shall commence an action against such third person within 6 months after such award. If the employer fails to commence an action against such third person within 90 days after the cause of action is assigned under this section, the right to bring the action shall revert to the person entitled to compensation.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>A payment made pursuant to §§ <cite path="§32-1509">32-1509</cite> and <cite path="§32-1540">32-1540</cite>(d)(1) shall operate as an assignment to the employer of all rights of the legal representative of the deceased (hereinafter referred to as “representative”) to recover damages against such third person.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>Such employer on account of such assignment may either institute proceedings for the recovery of such damages or may compromise with such third person either without or after instituting such proceeding.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <text>Any amount recovered by such employer on account of such assignment, whether or not as the result of a compromise, shall be distributed as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The employer shall retain an amount equal to:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>The expenses incurred by him in respect to such proceedings or compromise (including a reasonable attorney’s fee as determined by the Mayor);</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>The cost of all benefits actually furnished by him to the employee under § <cite path="§32-1507">32-1507</cite>;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>All amounts paid as compensation; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>The present value of all amounts thereafter payable as compensation, such present value to be computed in accordance with a schedule prepared by the Mayor, and the present value of the cost of all benefits thereafter to be furnished under § <cite path="§32-1507">32-1507</cite>, to be estimated by the Mayor, and the amounts so computed and estimated to be retained by the employer as a trust fund to pay such compensation and the cost of such benefits as they become due, and to pay any sum finally remaining in excess thereof to the person entitled to compensation or to the representative; and</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The employer shall pay any excess to the person entitled to compensation or to the representative, less one fifth of such excess which shall belong to the employer.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(f)</num>
        <text>If the person entitled to compensation institutes proceedings within the period described in subsection (b) of this section, the employer shall be required to pay as compensation under this chapter a sum equal to the excess of the amount which the Mayor determines is payable on account of such injury or death over the amount recovered against such third person.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(f-1)</num>
        <text>If the person entitled to compensation institutes proceedings within the period described in subsection (b) of this section and recovers an amount against a third person, the costs of litigation and attorneys’ fees shall be proportionally shared between the person entitled to compensation, or the employee’s eligible survivors or legal representative, and the employer relative to the amount each received in the settlement against the third person.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(g)</num>
        <text>If compromise with such third person is made by the person entitled to compensation or such representative of an amount less than the compensation to which such person or representative would be entitled under this chapter, the employer shall be liable for compensation as determined in subsection (f) of this section, only if the written approval of such compromise is obtained from the employer and his insurance carrier by the person entitled to compensation or such representative at the time of or prior to such compromise in a form and manner prescribed by the Mayor.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(h)</num>
        <text>Where the employer is insured and the insurance carrier has assumed the payment of the compensation, the insurance carrier shall be subrogated to all the rights of the employer under this section.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>The right to compensation or benefits under this chapter shall be the exclusive remedy to an employee when he is injured, or to his eligible survivors or legal representative if he is killed, by the negligence or wrong of any other person or persons in the same employ; provided, that this provision shall not affect the liability of a person other than an officer or employee of the employer.</text>
      </para>
      <annotations>
        <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-77" type="History" path="§36">July 1, 1980, D.C. Law 3-77, § 36, 27 DCR 2503</annotation>
        <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-159" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-159, § 2, 61 DCR 10733</annotation>
        <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§32-1507">32-1507</cite>.</annotation>
        <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 36-335.</annotation>
        <annotation type="Prior Codifications">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 2014, and that the act shall apply to violations occurring after October 1, 2014.</annotation>
        <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-159">D.C. Law 20-159</cite> added the last sentence in (b).</annotation>
        <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2 and 3 of the Workers’ Compensation Statute of Limitations Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-25">D.C. Law 20-25</cite>, Oct. 17, 2013,  60 DCR 11115), applicable to causes of action for negligence for which the 3-year statute of limitations has not expired.</annotation>
        <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2 and 3 of the Workers’ Compensation Statute of Limitations Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-137">D.C. Law 20-137</cite>, Sept. 9, 2014,  61 DCR 6781).</annotation>
        <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, §  7, see §  4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Temporary Amendemnt Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-57">D.C. Law 21-57</cite>, Jan. 30, 2016,  62 DCR 15602).</annotation>
        <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2 and 3 of the Workers’; Compensation Statute of Limitations Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-98, June 27, 2013,  60 DCR 9851, 20 DCSTAT 1456).</annotation>
        <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2 and 3 of the Workers’ Compensation Statute of Limitations Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-177, October 4, 2013,  60 DCR 3958).</annotation>
        <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2 and 3 of the Workers’ Compensation Statute of Limitations Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-334, May 22, 2014,  61 DCR 5373).</annotation>
        <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2 and 3 of the Worker’s Compensation Statute of Limitations Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-436, Oct. 7, 2014,  61 DCR 1072820 STAT 4164).</annotation>
        <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-188, Oct. 27, 2015,  62 DCR 14224).</annotation>
        <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-157">D.C. Law 20-157</cite>, § 7, see § 4 of the Wage Theft Prevention Correction and Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-293, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1215).</annotation>
        <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-159">D.C. Law 20-159</cite>: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-159">D.C. Law 20-159</cite> provided that the act applies to causes of action for negligence for which the 3-year statute of limitations has not expired.</annotation>
        <annotation app="2016-05-12" doc="D.C. Law 21-111" eff="2016-05-12" path="§2|(a)" type="History"/>
        <annotation app="2016-05-12" doc="D.C. Law 21-111" eff="2016-05-12" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
      </annotations>
    </section>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1536.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1537.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1538.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1539.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1540.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1541.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1542.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1542.01.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1542.02.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1542.03.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1542.04.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1543.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1544.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="./sections/32-1545.xml"/>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>16</num>
    <heading>Workforce Investment Implementation.</heading>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>I</num>
      <heading>General.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1601.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1602.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1602.01.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1603.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1603.01.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1604.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1605.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1605.01.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1606.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1607.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1608.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1609.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1610.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1610.01.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1611.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1611.01.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1612.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1612.01.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1613.xml"/>
    </container>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>II</num>
      <heading>Workforce Investment Implementation Individual Training Accounts Limitation.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1631.xml"/>
    </container>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>III</num>
      <heading>Educational Stepladder Program.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1651.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1652.xml"/>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1653.xml"/>
    </container>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>III-A</num>
      <heading>Adult Literacy Task Force.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1661.xml"/>
    </container>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num>IV</num>
      <heading>Adult Training Funding.</heading>
      <xi:include href="./sections/32-1671.xml"/>
    </container>
  </container>
</container>
