<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2021.03</num>
  <heading>Access to quality child care grant-making authority.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall award funds from the Access to Quality Child Care Fund available pursuant to <cite path="§7-2021.02|(c)|(1)">§ 7-2021.02(c)(1)</cite>, on a competitive basis, as grants to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Organizations that provide child care services to infants and toddlers to open child development facilities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Existing child development facilities to expand available space to serve infants and toddlers; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Organizations that provide child care services to carry out other activities necessary to expand access to child care and improve the quality of child care services provided in the District consistent with the findings of the evaluation and studies conducted pursuant to <cite path="§7-2021.02|(c)|(4)">§ 7-2021.02(c)(4)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The OSSE may award a grant or contract to a single nonprofit organization that does not provide child care services to infants and toddlers; provided, that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The grantee or contractor has a proven track record of success in grant-making related to child development facilities;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The grantee or contractor agrees to use 90% of OSSE's award to award subgrants to organizations that provide child care services, for the purposes of expanding child care services in accordance with the terms of this section;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The grantee or contractor agrees to undergo an annual audit and submit quarterly reports to OSSE on its financial health and its use of the OSSE award; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The grantee or contractor has a proven track record in providing financing and investment approaches and technical assistance in child development facility financing and development.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A grant or contract awarded pursuant to this subsection shall be awarded for a term of at least 2 years, subject to the availability of funding.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The grantee or contractor shall award subgrants for terms of at least 2 years, subject to the availability of funding.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>All subgrants of District funds shall be awarded on a competitive basis.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Subgrants shall be awarded for the following purposes:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Improving the supply of child care services for infants and toddlers, which may include establishing new, renovating existing, or expanding child development facilities serving infants and toddlers; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Carrying out other activities necessary to expand access to child care and improving the quality of child care services provided in the District consistent with the findings of the evaluation and studies conducted pursuant to <cite path="§7-2021.02|(c)|(4)">§ 7-2021.02(c)(4)</cite>.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>At least 50% of amounts awarded under this section shall be used to improve the supply of child care services for infants and toddlers eligible for subsidized child care.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The OSSE may not award a grant or contract under this section in excess of $1 million during a 12-month period, either singularly or cumulatively, unless the grant is first submitted to the Council for approval, in accordance with <cite path="§1-204.51|(b)">§ 1-204.51(b)</cite>, or by act.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2021.03" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§7-2021.03">
          For temporary (90-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§4104">§ 4104 of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017, effective July 20, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104; 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.
        </codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2021.03" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§7-2021.03">
          For temporary (90-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§4104">§ 4104 of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017, effective October 24, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167; 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.
        </codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="IV" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§4104" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§4104" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2017-12-13" eff="2017-12-13">
          For temporary (90-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§4104">§ 4104 of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017, effective July 20, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104; 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§4104" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§4104" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2017-12-13" eff="2017-12-13">
          For temporary (90-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§4104">§ 4104 of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017, effective October 24, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167; 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.
        </annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
