<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2021.02</num>
  <heading>Access to Quality Child Care Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Access to Quality Child Care Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Office of the State Superintendent of Education in accordance with <cite path="§7-2021.03">§ 7-2021.03</cite> and subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>There shall be deposited into the Fund:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In Fiscal Year 2018, $11 million from local appropriations; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Private donations, gifts, and grants.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used to provide grants or contracts to fund the following activities that expand access to child care:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Improving the supply of child care services for infants and toddlers, which may include establishing new or expanding existing child development facilities serving infants and toddlers; provided, that at least 50% of amounts expended pursuant to this paragraph are used to improve the supply of child care services for infants and toddlers eligible for subsidized child care;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Supporting the costs of certification, higher education, and credentialing of child development facility staff;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Providing technical assistance and training to child development facility operators to support compliance with the licensure process or efficient and effective operations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Evaluating and assessing the availability, quality, and willingness of child development facility operators to expand services for infants and toddlers in the District and conducting studies authorized pursuant to <cite path="7|20|I-A">subchapter I-A of this chapter</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Carrying out other activities as determined by OSSE related to expanding access to infant and toddler child care and improving the quality of child care services provided in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2021.02" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§7-2021.02">
          For temporary (90-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§4103">§ 4103 of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017, effective July 20, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104; 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.
        </codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2021.02" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§7-2021.02">
          For temporary (90-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§4103">§ 4103 of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017, effective October 24, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167; 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.
        </codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="IV" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§4103" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§4103" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2017-12-13" eff="2017-12-13">
          For temporary (90-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§4103">§ 4103 of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017, effective July 20, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104; 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§4103" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§4103" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2017-12-13" eff="2017-12-13">
          For temporary (90-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§4103">§ 4103 of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017, effective October 24, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167; 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.
        </annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
