<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2231.11</num>
  <heading>District government continuity of operations planning.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Agency shall coordinate COOP planning for the District government, including by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Designating a senior Agency employee to serve as the District COOP Program Manager, whose primary responsibility shall be to implement this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Developing internal policies and procedures, including after-action reviews, for the Agency to govern its implementation of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Maintaining a complete and accurate list of COOP Coordinators and backup COOP Coordinators;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Developing, updating, and distributing a COOP Plan template and guidance for each District government agency;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Ensuring each District government agency develops, updates, and conducts exercises of its COOP Plan;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Consulting with each District government agency on after-action reviews of exercises of its COOP Plan;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Monitoring the status of each District government agency's COOP Plan and bringing the District government agency into compliance with subsection (b) of this section; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Submitting an annual report to the City Administrator, Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice, and Council Committee with jurisdiction over the Agency on COOP planning for the District government, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An after-action review of the Agency's implementation of this section; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For each District government agency, a description of the:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Agency's implementation of this section, specifically with respect to that District government agency, since the submission of the last report; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>District government agency's compliance or noncompliance with subsection (b) of this section.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each District government agency shall work with the Agency to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 30 days after March 16, 2021, designate a senior employee to serve as its COOP Coordinator and an employee to serve as its backup COOP Coordinator, should the COOP Coordinator be unavailable at any time, and submit their names and contact information to the District COOP Program Manager;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By October 1, 2021, develop and submit a COOP Plan that conforms with the Agency's COOP Plan template and guidance to the District COOP Program Manager;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>By July 1, 2022, and annually thereafter, conduct an exercise of its COOP Plan and an after-action review of the exercise, which shall include the preparation of a report, submitted to the District COOP Program Manager, describing any deficiencies in and necessary revisions to the COOP Plan identified through the exercise; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>By October 1, 2022, and annually thereafter, update its COOP Plan submitted pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection, in coordination with the District COOP Program Manager, and re-submit the updated COOP Plan to the District COOP Program Manager.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The COOP Coordinator and backup COOP Coordinator designated pursuant to subsection (b)(1) of this section shall work with the District COOP Program Manager to facilitate and ensure the District government agency's compliance with subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>By January 31, 2022, the Inspector General shall audit COOP planning for the District government, including in relation to COVID-19, and submit a report to the Mayor and Council on the Inspector General's findings.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 81-2-ch686" path="ยง210">Aug. 11, 1950, 64 Stat. 440, ch. 686, ยง 211</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-219" eff="2021-03-16" path="ยง2|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
