<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2205.01</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on April 15, 2021.*
      </text>
  <heading>Fusion center.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Director of the Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency, subject to the direction and control of the Mayor, shall establish a fusion center for the District within the Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency.  The fusion center for the District, at the discretion of the Mayor and the Director of the Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency, may also serve as the primary fusion center in the National Capital Region.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The primary mission of the fusion center of the District is to receive, coordinate and facilitate the sharing of resources, expertise, and information, including criminal history record information and law enforcement intelligence information, among law enforcement, first responder, and criminal justice agencies, and to coordinate and integrate information from such agencies, with the goal of detecting and preventing criminal activity, such as terrorism, criminal conspiracy, bomb threats, possession of illegal firearms and explosives, identity theft, money laundering, hate crimes, and organized crime, and for the purpose of investigating and responding to such activity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency is designated a law enforcement agency, and the fusion center is designated a law enforcement unit, for the purposes of carrying out the functions set forth in subsection (b) of this section and for the purposes of receiving, analyzing, handling, and sharing criminal history record information and law enforcement intelligence information.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The fusion center for the District shall work in partnership with other state, local, regional, and federal fusion centers and with other state, local, regional, and federal law enforcement, criminal justice, and intelligence agencies.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The fusion center for the District shall represent the District's interests in the national network of fusion centers.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-01-15" doc="D.C. Act 24-2" eff="2021-01-15" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-01-15" doc="D.C. Act 24-2" eff="2021-01-15" path="§2" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-2" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2021-01-15" eff="2021-01-15">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-2" path="§2">§ 2 of Homeland Security Fusion Center and Law Enforcement Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-2, Jan. 15, 2021, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
