<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2205.01</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by temporary legislation that will expire on  December 24, 2021.*
      </text>
  <heading>Fusion center.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Director of the Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency ("HSEMA") shall, subject to the direction and control of the Mayor, establish and direct the administration and operations of an intelligence fusion center for the District within HSEMA. The fusion center shall, at the discretion of the Mayor and the Director of HSEMA, also serve as the primary fusion center in the National Capital Region.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The primary mission of the fusion center is to receive, coordinate, and share resources, expertise, and information, including criminal history record information and law enforcement intelligence information, from and among law enforcement, first responder, and criminal justice agencies; to facilitate and coordinate the receipt and sharing of such resources, expertise, and information from and among such agencies; and to analyze, handle, coordinate, and integrate such resources, expertise, and information from and among such agencies, with the goal of detecting and preventing terrorist and other criminal activity, such as criminal conspiracy, bomb threats, possession of illegal firearms and explosives, identity theft, money laundering, hate crimes, and organized crime, and for the purpose of investigating and responding to such activity. The fusion center shall collect, coordinate, and share information with law enforcement agencies only if a reasonable suspicion exists that the subject is involved in specific criminal acts or possible terrorist activity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The District's intelligence fusion center, which shall be a division of HSEMA, is designated a law enforcement unit for the purposes of carrying out the functions set forth in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The fusion center shall work in partnership with other state, local, regional, and federal fusion centers and other state, local, regional, and federal law enforcement, criminal justice, and intelligence agencies.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The fusion center shall represent the District's interests in the national network of fusion centers.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 81-2-ch686" path="§3a" display="false">Aug. 11, 1950, 64 Stat. 439, ch. 686, § 3a</annotation>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 81-2-ch686" path="§3a">Aug. 11, 1950, 64 Stat. 439, ch. 686, § 3a</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-2" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2021-05-13" eff="2021-01-15">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-2" path="§2">§ 2 of Homeland Security Fusion Center and Law Enforcement Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-2, Jan. 15, 2021, 68 DCR 001527)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-05-13" doc="D.C. Act 24-2" eff="2021-01-15" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-68" path="§3" codified:display="Note" app="2021-05-13" eff="2021-04-14">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-68" path="§3">§ 3 of Non-Public Student Educational Continuity and Homeland Security Fusion Center and Law Enforcement Authority Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-68, Apr. 14, 2021, 68 DCR 004911)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-05-13" doc="D.C. Act 24-68" eff="2021-04-14" path="§3" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-05-13" doc="D.C. Law 24-2" eff="2021-05-13" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-05-13" doc="D.C. Law 24-2" eff="2021-05-13" path="§2" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 24-2" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2021-05-13" eff="2021-05-13">For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-2" path="§2">§ 2 of Homeland Security Fusion Center and Law Enforcement Authority Temporary Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Law 24-2, May 13, 2021, 68 DCR 003438)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
