<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2371.02c</num>
  <heading>CPR and AED program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 120 days after October 8, 2016, each school shall meet the requirements of <cite path="§7-2371.02">§ 7-2371.02</cite> and:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Establish procedures for responding to a medical emergency involving cardiac arrest, including the appropriate use of CPR and an AED;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Have at least one AED on-site at the school;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Have, in coordination with the Department of General Services, a maintenance schedule established for each AED that is in accordance with the manufacturer's guidelines and includes:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Periodic testing;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Periodic inspection; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Annual maintenance;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Ensure that each AED at the school is appropriate for use on children and adults;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Have had the following individuals successfully complete a CPR and AED program; provided, that individuals newly hired for the following positions shall be required to successfully complete a CPR and AED program within 60 days after their hire date:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Athletic coach, coaching assistant, and athletic trainer;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Athletic director;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Team or game physician;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>School nurse; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Every anticipated AED user employed by the school, as designated by the school;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Require that at least one individual trained in a CPR and AED program be present during the school's hours of operation and during any athletic activity; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Inform all school employees, at least annually, of the location of each AED in the school.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Establish baseline requirements and guidelines for a CPR and AED program;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Approve each existing CPR and AED program that the Mayor determines meets or exceeds the baseline requirements and guidelines for a CPR and AED program, and any new CPR and AED programs established pursuant to this subchapter; provided, that the Mayor shall approve the existing programs listed in <cite path="§7-2371.02|(a)|(1)">§ 7-2371.02(a)(1)</cite> and the program offered by the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department pursuant to <cite path="§5-401|(b-1)">§ 5-401(b-1)</cite>, as meeting the requirements of this section;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Require each school to maintain a written record of the periodic testing, inspection, and maintenance of each AED; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Require the successful completion of a CPR and AED program by each employee in a position listed in subsection (a)(5) of this section.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A CPR and AED program may be conducted by a private or public entity.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § 44-232.03</annotation>
    <annotation app="2001-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 13-278" eff="2001-04-27" path="§3c" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3144|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-02-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-207" eff="2019-02-22" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
