<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-231.11</num>
  <heading>Delayed registration of live birth.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An individual may submit a delayed report of live birth of an individual born in the District one year or more after the live birth in a manner to be prescribed by rules issued pursuant to <cite path="ยง7-231.29">ยง 7-231.29</cite>. A delayed report of live birth shall not be registered until evidence to substantiate the facts of live birth in the District has been supplied to the Registrar.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A live birth registered one year or more after the date of live birth shall be marked "delayed" and display the date of the delayed registration on the face of the certificate.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Registrar shall prepare a written summary of the evidence submitted in support of the delayed registration, which shall be included in the record. The applicant shall sign the report under oath and this signature shall be notarized.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If an applicant does not submit the minimum documentation required to file a delayed report, or the Registrar has reasonable cause to question the validity or adequacy of the applicant's sworn notarized statement or the documentary evidence, and the deficiencies are not corrected, the Registrar shall not register the live birth.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Registrar shall state in writing to the applicant the reason for not registering the live birth and shall advise the applicant in writing of the right to bring an action in court to establish the date, place of live birth, and parentage of the person whose live birth is to be registered.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Registrar may reject a delayed report of live birth that is incomplete or insufficient pursuant to subsection (d) of this section if the applicant does not correct the deficiencies within 30 days of the initial filing of the report.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>No delayed report of live birth shall be registered for a deceased individual.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-164" eff="2018-10-30" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-164" eff="2018-10-30" path="ยง111" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
