<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-231.03</num>
  <heading>Appointment and duties of Registrar of Vital Records Division.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Director of the Department shall appoint the Registrar.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Registrar shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Administer and enforce the provisions of <cite path="7|2A">this chapter</cite> and any implementing rules issued pursuant to <cite path="ยง7-231.29">ยง 7-231.29</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide instructions for the efficient administration of the vital statistics system;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Direct and supervise the vital statistics system and the Vital Records Division and serve as custodian of its records;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Administer and maintain the confidentiality and security of the vital statistics system;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Direct, supervise, and control the activities of each individual engaged in the activities of the Vital Records Division;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Develop and conduct training programs to promote uniformity of policy and procedures pertaining to the vital statistics system;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Develop and distribute all forms as will accomplish the purpose of complete, accurate, and timely reporting and registration;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>[sic.] Prepare and publish reports of vital statistics of the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Provide information derived from vital records and vital reports required under <cite path="7|2A">this chapter</cite> that are necessary for Department programs and health planning activities, which shall remain the property of the Vital Records Division, and under the Registrar's control; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Prepare a plan to provide for the continuity of operations of the system of vital statistics in the event of an emergency that:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>To the extent practicable, anticipates natural and man-made events that interrupt normal activities of the vital statistics system, identifies essential vital statistics services, and provides guidance for maintaining services; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Includes:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(I)</num>
            <text>Alternative locations for operations;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(II)</num>
            <text>An identification of essential equipment, document needs, and where to obtain them; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(III)</num>
            <text>An identification of essential staff and a mechanism for communication with such individuals in an emergency.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The plan shall be confidential and shall not be subject to compelled disclosure; provided, that the Registrar may authorize disclosure of all or part of the plan as the Registrar deems necessary to implement the plan.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Registrar may establish or eliminate offices to aid in the efficient administration of the system of vital statistics.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Registrar may delegate functions and duties to employees of the Vital Records Division and to employees of any office established pursuant to subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-164" eff="2018-10-30" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-164" eff="2018-10-30" path="ยง103" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
