<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-231.05</num>
  <heading>Individuals required to keep records.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each individual in charge of an institution, or his delegate, shall keep a record of personal data concerning each individual admitted or confined to the institution. This record shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Include the information required for a reportable vital event; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Be created at the time of admission from information obtained from the individual admitted or confined.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If the individual admitted or confined cannot provide the information, the institution shall obtain the information from relatives or another individual acquainted with the facts, and shall include the name, address, and relationship of the individual providing the information in the record.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A licensed health care provider shall keep a record of personal data concerning each individual under the provider's care for a condition that results in a reportable vital event when the documentation is not maintained by an institution pursuant to subsection (a) of this section. This record shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Include information required for the provider to submit a report of live birth, death, fetal death, or induced termination of pregnancy; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Contain information provided by the individual being treated. If the individual being treated cannot provide the information, then the licensed health care provider shall obtain the information from a relative or another individual acquainted with the facts, and shall include the name, address, and relationship of the individual providing the information in the record.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>When a dead body or fetus is released by an institution, the individual in charge of the institution, or his delegate, shall keep a record identifying the name of the decedent, date of death, name and address of the individual to whom the body or fetus is released, and the date of removal from the institution.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>When final disposition of a dead body or fetus is made by an institution, the individual in charge of the institution, or his delegate, shall record the date, place, and manner of final disposition.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A funeral director or other authorized individual who removes from the place of death, transports, or makes final disposition of a dead body or fetus, in addition to filing any required record or report, shall keep a record that identifies the body and the information pertaining to the receipt, removal, delivery, burial, or cremation of the body as required in accordance with rules issued pursuant to <cite path="ยง7-231.29">ยง 7-231.29</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Records created pursuant to this section shall be retained for no less than 5 years and shall be made available for inspection by the Registrar upon request.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-164" eff="2018-10-30" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-164" eff="2018-10-30" path="ยง105" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
