<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2304.02</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by temporary legislation that will expire on February 4, 2022.*
      </text>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on October 22, 2021. To view the text of the temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-9" path="§507|(c)">Temporary Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Public health emergency response grants.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the Grant Administration Act of 2013, effective December 24, 2013 (D.C. Law 20-61; D.C. Official Code § 1-328.11 <em>et seq.</em>), from March 11, 2020 until November 5, 2021, the Mayor may issue a grant or loan to a program, organization, business, or entity, including a grant or loan for the purpose of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Increasing awareness and participation in disease investigation and contact tracing;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Purchasing and distributing personal protective equipment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Promoting and facilitating social distancing measures;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Providing public health awareness outreach;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Assisting residents with obtaining disease testing, contacting health care providers, and obtaining medical services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Covering the costs of operating a business or organization including rent, utilities, or employee wages and benefits; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Providing technical assistance to the business community.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may issue one or more grants to a third-party grant-managing entity for the purpose of issuing or administering grants on behalf of the Mayor in accordance with the requirements of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, and any third-party entity chosen pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, shall maintain a list of all grants and loans awarded pursuant to this section with respect to each public health emergency for which grants or loans are issued.  The list shall identify, for each award, the grant or loan recipient, the date of award, the intended use of the award, and the award amount.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall publish the list online no later than 60 days after the first grant or loan is issued under this section with respect to a specific public health emergency and shall publish an updated list online within 30 days after each additional grant or loan, if any, is issued with respect to the specific public health emergency.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to <cite path="§2-505">§ 2-505</cite>, may issue rules to implement the provisions of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-149" type="History" path="§5b">Mar. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 3-149, § 5b</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-30" path="§507|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-06-24" eff="2021-03-17">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-30" path="§507|(c)">§ 507(c) of Coronavirus Support Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-30, Mar. 17, 2021, 68 DCR 003101)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-06-24" doc="D.C. Act 24-30" eff="2021-03-17" path="§507|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-96" path="§507|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-06-24" eff="2021-06-07">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-96" path="§507|(c)">§ 507(c) of Coronavirus Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-96, June 7, 2021, 68 DCR 006025)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-06-24" doc="D.C. Act 24-96" eff="2021-06-07" path="§507|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-06-24" doc="D.C. Law 24-9" eff="2021-06-24" path="§507|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-06-24" doc="D.C. Law 24-9" eff="2021-06-24" path="§507|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 24-9" path="§507|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-06-24" eff="2021-06-24">For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-9" path="§507|(c)">§ 507(c) of Coronavirus Support Temporary Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Law 24-9, June 24, 2021, 68 DCR 004824)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-07-24" doc="D.C. Act 24-125" eff="2021-07-24" path="§3|(y)|(2)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-07-24" doc="D.C. Act 24-125" eff="2021-07-24" path="§3|(y)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-125" path="§3|(y)|(2)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-07-24" eff="2021-07-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-125" path="§3|(y)|(2)">§ 3(y)(2) of Public Emergency Extension and Eviction and Utility Moratorium Phasing Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-125, July 24, 2021, 68 DCR 007342)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
