<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2371.02</num>
  <heading>Access by the public to defibrillation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person who or entity that acquires an AED shall ensure that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Facility AED Coordinator receives training from or is certified by the American Heart Association, the American Red Cross, or an equivalent state or nationally recognized course, such as the Heart Saver CPR AED course, in cardiopulmonary resuscitation (“CPR”) and in the use of an AED, and that the users maintain their certification in CPR and AED use;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The defibrillator is maintained and tested according to the manufacturer’s operational guidelines, and written records of the maintenance and testing are maintained;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A physician licensed in the District of Columbia shall oversee all aspects of the defibrillation program, including training, coordination with the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department (“Department”), protocol approval, AED deployment strategies, and equipment maintenance plan, and shall review each case in which the AED is used by the program; provided, that a physician is not required if a person or entity enters into an agreement with the Department pursuant to which the Department provides the equipment, training, and oversight required by this subsection; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any person who uses an AED to provide emergency care or treatment on a person in cardiac arrest shall activate the Department’s emergency medical service system as soon as possible, and shall report any clinical use of the AED to the licensed physician or medical authority. Data on AED use shall be submitted to the Department and reviewed by the Department.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any person or entity who acquires an AED shall notify the Chief of the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department ("Chief of the Department") or his or her designee and the call center, as defined in <cite path="§1-327.51|(2)" technical="Should be (2) not (a)(2).">§ 1-327.51(2)</cite>, of the AED and the location and type of the AED.  If an AED is removed, the Chief of the Department shall be notified.  The Chief of the Department may issue a citation if the requirements of this subsection are not followed; provided, that the Chief of the Department has adopted regulations governing the issuance of the citations.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-278" type="History" path="§3">Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-278, § 3, 48 DCR 1869</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-362" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-362, § 2(b), 56 DCR 1211</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-362">D.C. Law 17-362</cite>, in subsec. (b), designated the existing text as par. (1), inserted “Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection,” and added par. (2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§44-232.01">§ 44-232.01</cite> and <cite path="§44-234">§ 44-234</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § 44-232</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3144|(b)|(1)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3144|(b)|(1)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3144|(b)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3144|(b)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-02-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-207" eff="2019-02-22" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
