<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-231.06</num>
  <heading>Duties to furnish information.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An individual with knowledge of the facts related to a reportable vital event shall furnish any information that he or she may possess to the Registrar within 5 days of a request by the Registrar.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No later than the 10th day of each month, the individual in charge of each institution, or his delegate, shall send to the Vital Records Division a list showing each live birth, death, fetal death, or induced termination of pregnancy that occurred at that institution during the preceding month. The list shall be in a format prescribed by the Registrar in rules issued pursuant to <cite path="§7-231.29">§ 7-231.29</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No later than the 10th day of each month, each funeral director shall send to the Registrar a list showing each dead body received, embalmed, prepared for final disposition, or finally disposed of in the preceding month. The list shall be in a format prescribed by the Registrar in rules issued pursuant to <cite path="§7-231.29">§ 7-231.29</cite> and shall also include a record of the date, place, and manner of final disposition of each dead body, if applicable.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Within 5 days of receipt of any autopsy results or other information that would provide pending or missing information or correct errors in a reported cause of death, the physician or medical examiner required to report the death shall send to the Registrar a delayed diagnosis report of the cause of death to amend the record.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-164" eff="2018-10-30" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-164" eff="2018-10-30" path="§106" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
