<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-231.26</num>
  <heading>Fraud or misrepresentation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>When the Registrar receives information that a vital event report or record may have been registered, corrected, or amended through fraud or misrepresentation, the Registrar may withhold issuance of any certificate or amendment of that certificate pending inquiry by appropriate authorities to determine whether fraud or misrepresentation has occurred.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If, upon conclusion of the inquiry conducted pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, no fraud or misrepresentation is found, the Registrar shall resume processing requests for a certificate or a modification of the record.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>When the Registrar receives information that an application for a vital record service may have been submitted for the purpose of fraud or misrepresentation, the Registrar may withhold performance of that service pending inquiry by appropriate authorities to determine whether fraud or misrepresentation has occurred.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If, upon conclusion of the inquiry, there is reasonable cause to suspect fraud or misrepresentation, the Registrar shall provide copies of the application, report, or record and any other evidence to the appropriate authorities for further investigation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If, upon conclusion of this investigation, fraud or misrepresentation is found, the Registrar may suspend further action regarding the record, or void or seal the record. The Registrar shall provide a written statement of these actions, including references to all the investigative findings and evidence that form the basis for the actions, to the registrant or the registrant's legal representative.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Registrar shall retain all voided or sealed records and evidence, including the application, but such records and evidence shall not be subject to inspection or copying except upon order of the court or by the Registrar for purposes of administering the vital records system.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Registrar shall periodically test and audit the vital records systems for the purpose of detecting fraud. If fraud is detected, the Registrar shall provide copies of the evidence to the proper authorities for further investigation. The results of the tests and audits shall be retained but shall not be subject to inspection or copying except by the Registrar for the purpose of administering the vital records system.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-164" eff="2018-10-30" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-164" eff="2018-10-30" path="ยง126" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
