<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2304.02</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by temporary legislation that will expire on April 1, 2021.*
      </text>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on March 18, 2021.*
      </text>
  <heading>Public health emergency response grants.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon the Mayor's declaration of a public health emergency pursuant to <cite path="§7-2304.01|(d)">§ 7-2304.01(d)</cite>, and for a period not exceeding 90 days after the end of the public health emergency, the Mayor may, notwithstanding <cite path="1|3|XII-A|B">part B of subchapter XII-A of Chapter 3 of Title 1</cite>, and in the Mayor's sole discretion, issue a grant or loan to a program, organization, business, or entity to assist the District in responding to the public health emergency, including a grant or loan for the purpose of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Increasing awareness and participation in disease investigation and contact tracing;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Purchasing and distributing personal protective equipment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Promoting and facilitating social distancing measures;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Providing public health awareness outreach;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Assisting residents with obtaining disease testing, contacting health care providers, and obtaining medical services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Covering the costs of operating a business or organization including rent, utilities, or employee wages and benefits; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Providing technical assistance to the business community.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may issue one or more grants to a third-party grant-managing entity for the purpose of issuing or administering grants on behalf of the Mayor in accordance with the requirements of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, and any third-party entity chosen pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, shall maintain a list of all grants and loans awarded pursuant to this section with respect to each public health emergency for which grants or loans are issued.  The list shall identify, for each award, the grant or loan recipient, the date of award, the intended use of the award, and the award amount.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall publish the list online no later than 60 days after the first grant or loan is issued under this section with respect to a specific public health emergency and shall publish an updated list online within 30 days after each additional grant or loan, if any, is issued with respect to the specific public health emergency.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to <cite path="§2-505">§ 2-505</cite>, may issue rules to implement the provisions of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-149" type="History" path="§5b">Mar. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 3-149, § 5b</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-405" path="§507|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2020-10-11" eff="2020-08-19">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-405" path="§507|(c)">§ 507(c) of Coronavirus Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Act 23-405, Aug. 19, 2020, 67 DCR 10235)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-10-11" doc="D.C. Act 23-405" eff="2020-08-19" path="§507|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-09" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" eff="2020-10-09" path="§507|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-09" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" eff="2020-10-09" path="§507|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" path="§507|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2020-10-09" eff="2020-10-09">For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-130" path="§507|(c)">§ 507(c) of Coronavirus Support Temporary Amendment Act of 2020 [Effective from October 9, 2020] (D.C. Law 23-130, Oct. 9, 2020, 67 DCR 8622)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-18" doc="D.C. Act 23-524" eff="2020-12-18" path="§3|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-18" doc="D.C. Act 23-524" eff="2020-12-18" path="§3|(b)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-18" doc="D.C. Act 23-524" eff="2020-12-18" path="§3|(b)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-18" doc="D.C. Act 23-524" eff="2020-12-18" path="§3|(b)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-18" doc="D.C. Act 23-524" eff="2020-12-18" path="§3|(b)|(4)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-524" path="§3|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2020-12-18" eff="2020-12-18">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-524" path="§3|(b)">§ 3(b) of Coronavirus Public Health Extension Emergency Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Act 23-524, Dec. 18, 2020, 67 DCR 14747)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
