<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-2361.05</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on November 30, 2021. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite path="§7-2361.05(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Recognition of volunteer health practitioners licensed in other states.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (a-1) of this section, while an emergency declaration is in effect, a volunteer health practitioner registered with a registration system that complies with <cite path="§7-2361.04">§ 7-2361.04</cite> and licensed and in good standing in the state upon which the practitioner’s registration is based may practice in the District to the extent authorized by this chapter as if the practitioner were licensed in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including <cite path="§7-2304.01">§ 7-2304.01</cite>, or whether an emergency declaration is in effect, a volunteer health practitioner qualified under subsection (a) of this section or a licensed health care provider as described in <cite path="§7-2304.01">§ 7-2304.01</cite> may practice in the District until December 31, 2021, to the extent authorized by Department of Health Administrative Order 2020-02.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A volunteer health practitioner qualified under subsection (a) of this section is not entitled to the protections of this chapter if the practitioner is licensed in more than one state and any license of the practitioner is suspended, revoked, or subject to an agency order limiting or restricting practice privileges, or has been voluntarily terminated under threat of sanction.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-184" type="History" path="§6">July 1, 2010, D.C. Law 18-184, § 6, 57 DCR 3655</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 6 of the Uniform Emergency Volunteer Health Practitioners Act.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-09-01" doc="D.C. Act 24-166" eff="2021-09-01" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-09-01" doc="D.C. Act 24-166" eff="2021-09-01" path="§2|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-09-01" doc="D.C. Act 24-166" eff="2021-09-01" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-166" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2021-09-01" eff="2021-09-01">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-166" path="§2">§ 2 of Uniform Emergency Volunteer Health Practitioners Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-166, Sept. 1, 2021, 68 DCR 009483)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
