<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2411</num>
  <heading>Office of Neighborhood Safety and Engagement establishment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established an Office of Neighborhood Safety and Engagement ("ONSE"). The ONSE shall include the following programs:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Community Stabilization Program, which shall be transferred to the ONSE from the Office of the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice, along with all functions assigned, authorities delegated, positions, personnel, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available for the purposes of the program; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Safer, Stronger DC Community Partnerships Program, which shall be transferred to the ONSE from the Office of the Deputy Mayor for Health and Human Services, along with all functions assigned, authorities delegated, positions, personnel, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available for the purposes of the program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The ONSE shall be responsible for:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Coordinating the District's overall violence prevention strategy and programs, with a focus on utilizing public health approaches to respond to and prevent violence;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Identifying, recruiting, and engaging individuals determined to be at high risk of participating in, or being a victim of, violent crime;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Collaborating with other District agencies and nonprofit organizations to provide immediate wrap-around services to victims and families affected by violent crime;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Identifying priority neighborhoods and Metropolitan Police Department Police Service Areas ("PSAs") with high trends of violent crime and connecting residents in those neighborhoods and PSAs to services through a streamlined approach;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Developing positive relationships with youth and young adults using recreational and other positive behavior reinforcement activities; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Coordinating with District agencies and community-based organizations to develop programs that focus on employment and job-training opportunities for individuals residing in priority neighborhoods or PSAs or who are most at risk of participating in, or being a victim of, violent crime, including through the use of financial incentives for participation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The ONSE shall be headed by an Executive Director who shall report to the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice. The Executive Director shall have at least 3 years of relevant experience in criminal justice and public health-based approaches to violence, including matters affecting the deterrence of violent criminal behavior.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Beginning on January 31, 2018, and by January 31 of each year thereafter, the ONSE shall provide a report to the Mayor and Council that excludes personally identifiable information and includes the following information from the reporting period and in the aggregate:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The number of individuals successfully recruited and engaged;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The duration of individuals' participation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The status of participants' progress; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The participants' age, race or ethnicity, gender, and ward of residence.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The ONSE may apply for and receive grants and accept private donations to fund its program activities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The ONSE shall have grant-making authority for the purpose of providing funds that seek to reduce and prevent violent crime. Grants made pursuant to this subsection shall be administered pursuant to the requirements set forth in <cite path="1|3|XII-A|B">part B of subchapter XII-A of Chapter 3 of Title 1</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2411" type="Applicability" history="false" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§7-2411"><cite doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§7014">Section 7014 of D.C. Law 22-33</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-125" path="§901">§ 901 of D.C. Law 21-125</cite>. Therefore the changes made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-125">D.C. Law 21-125</cite> have been given effect.
          </codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-06-30" doc="D.C. Law 21-125" eff="2016-06-30" path="I|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-06-30" doc="D.C. Law 21-125" eff="2016-06-30" path="§101" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" app="2016-06-30" eff="2016-06-30" doc="D.C. Law 21-125" path="§101">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-125" path="">D.C. Law 21-125</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-125" path="§901">§ 901 of D.C. Law 21-125</cite> provided that the change made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-125" path="§101">§ 101 of D.C. Law 21-125</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been given effect.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§3032|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§3032|(a)" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2017-12-13" eff="2017-12-13"><cite doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§7014">Section 7014 of D.C. Law 22-33</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-125" path="§901">§ 901 of D.C. Law 21-125</cite>. Therefore the changes made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-125">D.C. Law 21-125</cite> have been given effect.
          </annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§3032|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
