<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2415</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
      </text>
  <heading>Violence prevention, interruption, and response services.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To support initiatives, programs, and interventions that aim to prevent, interrupt, or respond to violence in the District, the Mayor may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Issue housing vouchers, financial assistance for housing, housing counseling, and other supportive services to individuals and families who have been victims of gun violence or are at risk of gun violence;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Waive statutory, regulatory, and administrative fees, including vital record fees and driver license and non-driver identification fees, for, and settle or forgive debts owed to the District government by, individuals participating in or potentially eligible to participate in a violence prevention, violence interruption, violence response, or victim services program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Pay private, local, state, and federal fees, including fees for licenses and certifications, vital records, educational fees, and background and suitability checks, for individuals participating in or potentially eligible to participate in a violence prevention, violence interruption, violence response, or victim services program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Provide social, economic, educational, health, and other services and supports for the purposes of violence prevention, violence interruption, violence response, and victim services to individuals participating in or eligible to participate in a violence prevention, violence interruption, violence response, or victim services program. Services and supports provided pursuant to this paragraph may include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Transportation, including transportation to government offices and non-governmental service providers and transportation of public-school students in safe passage areas;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Housing relocation costs, including moving costs and the costs of establishing a new household;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Tests and test preparation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Post office boxes;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Secure document storage;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Cell phones and cell phone service; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Driver education;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Provide financial payments to individuals participating in or potentially eligible to participate in a violence prevention, violence interruption, or violence response program to incentivize such individuals to apply for, participate in, or continue to participate in, such program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Issue grants in support of violence prevention, violence interruption, violence response, and victim services programs; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Provide the services and supports described in <cite path="§1-604.02a">§ 1-604.02a</cite>, including paid internships, to individuals participating in a violence prevention, violence interruption, violence response, or victim services program, regardless of whether the individual has received a high school diploma or its equivalent.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The financial assistance for housing provided pursuant to subsection (a)(1) of this section shall be used to assist the recipients with relocation from their current housing and to provide them with short- and mid-term housing supports.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Payments made for services and supports under subsection (a)(4) and (5) of this section may be made by direct voucher.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-125" type="History" display="false">June 30, 2016, D.C. Law 21-125, § 103b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-125" type="History">June 30, 2016, D.C. Law 21-125, § 103b</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-06-30" doc="D.C. Law 21-125" eff="2016-06-30" path="I|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§3033" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§3033" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§3033" codified:display="Note" app="2021-08-23" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§3033">§ 3033 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
