<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2421</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subtitle, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"ACSH" means the Advisory Committee on Street Harassment established by section 1043.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"High-risk area" means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The enclosed area within any Metrorail car, Metrobus, MetroAccess vehicle, DC Circulator bus, DC Streetcar, or any other commercial vehicle capable of carrying more than 6 passengers;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The area within 25 feet of any Metrorail station, Metrobus stop, DC Circulator stop, DC streetcar stop, or a location designated for the loading and unloading of a commercial vehicle capable of carrying more than 6 passengers;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The enclosed area within any private vehicle-for-hire, as that term is defined in section 4(16A) of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles Establishment Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-97; D.C. Official Code § 50-301.03(16A)), or public vehicle-for-hire, as that term is defined in section 4(17) of the Department of For-Hire Vehicles Establishment Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-97; D.C. Official Code § 50-301.03(17));</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A food service entity, as that term is defined in section 401(4) of the Sustainable DC Omnibus Amendment Act of 2014, effective December 17, 2014 (D.C. Law 20-142; D.C. Official Code § 8-1531(4)), hotel, as that term is defined in D.C. Official Code § 25-101(25), nightclub, as that term is defined in D.C. Official Code § 25-101(33), tavern, as that term is defined in D.C. Official Code § 25-101(52), and any other establishment that serves food or alcohol;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Any school, library, or other building primarily used for the instruction of students, including a day care center, nursery, elementary school, secondary school, college, and university;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Any bank, health care facility, laundromat, retail store, shopping mall, sports arena, music venue, and theater;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>All the publicly owned property between property lines shown on the records of the District, including any roadway, sidewalk, or parking between such property lines; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>All buildings or land that are owned, leased, or occupied by the District government.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"OHR" means the Office of Human Rights established by section 202 of the Office of Human Rights Establishment Act of 1999, effective October 20, 1999 (D.C. Law 13-38; D.C. Official Code § 2-1411.01).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Street harassment" means disrespectful, offensive, or threatening statements, gestures, or other conduct directed at an individual in a high-risk area without the individual's consent and based on the individual's actual or perceived ethnicity or housing status, or a protected trait identified in the Human Rights Act of 1977, effective December 13, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-38; D.C. Official Code § 2-1401.01 <em>et seq.</em>)<em>.</em></text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2421" display-template="" history="false" action="creation of this section" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§7-2421" codified:display="Note"/>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="I|E" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="§1042" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§1042" codified:display="Note" app="2018-07-30" eff="2018-07-30">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§1042">§ 1042 of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-434, July 30, 2018, 65 DCR 8200)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" eff="2018-10-03" path="§1042" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§1042" codified:display="Note" app="2018-10-03" eff="2018-10-03">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§1042">§ 1042 of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-458, Oct. 3, 2018, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
