<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-2510.09</num>
  <heading>Return or disposal of firearms or ammunition.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If an extreme risk protection order is terminated, or expires and is not renewed, the Metropolitan Police Department shall notify the respondent that he or she may request the return of any firearm or ammunition surrendered or removed if that firearm or ammunition had been lawfully possessed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Metropolitan Police Department shall return any surrendered or removed firearm or ammunition requested by a respondent only after confirming that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The respondent is eligible to own or possess the firearms and ammunition;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The firearm or ammunition was lawfully possessed; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The respondent has paid any applicable fee charged against the respondent by the Metropolitan Police Department pursuant to subsection 1007(e).</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a respondent who lawfully possessed a firearm or ammunition does not wish to have the firearm or ammunition returned, or the respondent is no longer eligible to own or possess firearms or ammunition, the respondent may sell or transfer title of the firearm or ammunition in accordance with applicable law.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Metropolitan Police Department shall transfer possession of a firearm or ammunition through a licensed firearm dealer to a purchaser or recipient, but only after the licensed firearms dealer has displayed written proof of the sale or transfer of the firearm or ammunition from the respondent to the dealer, and the Metropolitan Police Department has verified the transfer with the respondent.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the respondent does not request return of a firearm or ammunition under subsection (a) of this section, or sell or transfer a firearm or ammunition under subsection (b) of this section, within 6 months after the date the extreme risk protection order is terminated, or expires and is not renewed, the Metropolitan Police Department shall treat the firearm or ammunition as surrendered and the firearm or ammunition shall be subject to <cite path="§7-2507.05|(b)">§ 7-2507.05(b)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-85" type="History" path="§101">Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, title X, § 1009</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Act 23-41" path="§2|(e)" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2019-06-01" eff="2019-04-15"><cite doc="D.C. Act 23-41" path="2|(e)">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see § 2(e) of Firearms Safety Omnibus Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-41, Apr. 15, 2019, 66 DCR 5255)</cite>.
            </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-06-01" doc="D.C. Act 23-41" eff="2019-04-15" path="§2|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-05-10" doc="D.C. Law 22-314" eff="2019-05-10" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-05-10" doc="D.C. Law 22-314" eff="2019-05-10" path="§2|(e)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
