<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-3201</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of <cite path="7|32">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"DBH" means the Department of Behavioral Health.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"DHCF" means the Department of Health Care Finance.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"DISB" means the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"DOC" means the Department of Corrections.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"DOH" means the Department of Health.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Health care provider" means a physician, advance practice registered nurse, clinic, hospital, DBH-certified provider organizations, or neighborhood health center, licensed by the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Health insurer" means any person that provides one or more health benefit plans or insurance in the District, including an insurer, a hospital and medical services corporation, a fraternal benefit society, a health maintenance organization, a multiple employer welfare arrangement, or any other person providing a plan of health insurance subject to the authority of the Commissioner of DISB.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Hospital" means a facility that provides 24-hour inpatient care, including diagnostic, therapeutic, and other health-related services, for a variety of physical or mental conditions, and may, in addition, provide outpatient services, particularly emergency care.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"In-network health care provider" means the health care providers or health care facilities that have contracted with a health insurer to provide services to plan members for negotiated rates.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Opioid use disorder" means a pattern of opioid use leading to clinically significant impairment or distress, as manifested by symptoms identified in the most recent publication of the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders of the American Psychiatric Association.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Opioid use disorder treatment medication" means all medications approved by the United States Food and Drug Administration for the treatment of opioid use disorders.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>"Prescriber" means a person who is licensed, registered, or otherwise authorized by the District to prescribe and administer prescription drugs in the course of a professional practice.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>"Telehealth" means the delivery of healthcare services through interactive audio, video, or other electronic media used for the purpose of diagnosis, consultation, or treatment; provided, that services delivered through audio-only telephones, electronic mail messages, or facsimile transmissions are not included.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-288" eff="2019-04-11" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-288" eff="2019-04-11" path="ยง101" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
