<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-431</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of <cite path="7|4A">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Bather" means any person using a swimming pool or spa pool and adjoining deck area for the purpose of water sports, recreation therapy, or related activities.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Class C, semi-public swimming pool" or "swimming pool" means any swimming pool operated solely for and in conjunction with lodgings such as hotels, motels, cooperatives, apartments, and condominiums.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Diving board" means a recreational mechanism for entering a swimming pool, consisting of a semi-rigid board that derives its elasticity through the use of a fulcrum mounted below the board.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Lifeguard" means a person responsible for the safety of the users of a swimming pool or spa pool who possesses a current:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>American Red Cross, Young Men's Christian Association, or other lifeguard certification;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>First aid certificate; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Cardiopulmonary resuscitation certificate, issued by a nationally recognized aquatic training organizations, such as the International Lifeguard Training Program, that is adopted and recognized by the Department of Health.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Sauna" means an aquatic feature including the application of water vapor from hot water facilities such as Jacuzzis, hot tubs, and steam baths.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Spa pool" means a structure intended for either warm or cold water where prolonged exposure is not intended. Spa structures are intended to be used for bathing or other recreational uses and are not usually drained and refilled after each use and may include hydrotherapy, air induction bubbles, and recirculation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-03-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-273" eff="2018-03-03" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-03-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-273" eff="2018-03-03" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-273" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2018-03-03" eff="2018-03-03">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-273" path="§2">§ 2 of Pools Without Penalties Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-273, Mar. 3, 2018, 65 DCR 2374)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 22-101" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2018-06-05" eff="2018-06-05">For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-101" path="§2">§ 2 of Pools Without Penalties Temporary Act of 2018 (D.C. Law 22-101, June 5, 2018, 65 DCR 3771)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-06-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-101" eff="2018-06-05" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-07-17" doc="D.C. Law 22-147" eff="2018-07-17" path="§2" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
