<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-756.01</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Commission on Health Equity.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Commission on Health Equity ("Commission") to prepare, through the Department of Health's Office on Violence Prevention and Health Equity, comprehensive recommendations to the Department of Health, the Council, and the Mayor that examine and address health inequities across the District and differing opportunities for healthcare by demographic subpopulations and geographic areas, including in each election ward of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall have 9 voting members, who shall be appointed as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Six voting members shall be appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council, in accordance with <cite path="ยง1-523.01|(f)">ยง 1-523.01(f)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Mayor's initial 6 appointments shall include 3 members appointed to 3-year terms and 3 members appointed to 2-year terms. All subsequent appointments by the Mayor shall be for 3-year terms.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Three voting members shall be appointed by the Council.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Council's initial 3 appointments shall be for one-year terms.  All subsequent appointments by the Council shall be for 3-year terms.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Each voting member shall have expertise in at least one of the following areas:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Health equity, social determinants, and health disparities;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Social and human services and vulnerable populations;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Early learning and education;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Minority communities and population health outcomes and improvement;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Economic and community development; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Ecology and the natural and built environment.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall appoint the Chairperson of the Commission from among its voting members.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Commission shall include the following nonvoting advisory members:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Chairperson of the Council committee with jurisdiction over the Department of Health, who shall serve as an ex-officio member;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Three community advisory members, one each from Wards 5, 7, and 8, appointed by the Council;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>One patient organization representative, appointed by the voting members of the Commission; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The presidents or chief executive officers of 2 District hospitals and a representative from an insurance company who have access to health outcomes databases, or their designees.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term "patient organization representative" means an individual who works for a national or local healthcare or health promotion organization.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>All vacancies on the Commission shall be filled in the same manner in which the initial appointment is made.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>All members of the Commission shall be appointed within one year after October 8, 2016.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="V" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="ยง5043" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
