<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-771.07c</num>
  <text>
               *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
              </text>
  <heading>DC HealthCare Alliance Reform Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the DC HealthCare Alliance Reform Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Department in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Local funds appropriated in Fiscal Years 2022 through 2024 for the Department that remain unspent at the close of each fiscal year shall be deposited into the Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used exclusively within the Department of Health Care Finance to fully fund reforms to the D.C. HealthCare Alliance Program, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Permanently eliminating the requirement for a face-to-face interview as a recertification requirement for the DC HealthCare Alliance program; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Extending the period of time before recertification of enrollment from 6 months to one year.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund but not expended in a fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, money in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§5113" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§5113" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§5113" codified:display="Note" app="2021-08-23" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§5113">§ 5113 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
