<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>7-858.03</num>
  <heading>Birthing facility report cards; inspections; annual reports.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each hospital and birthing facility shall report to the Department information regarding inpatient services and processes for each of the following elements as the Department may require through rulemaking, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Newborn screening requirements established under <cite path="7|8B-ii">this chapter</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Lactation support services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Education requirements on newborn and postpartum health;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Discharge standards established under <cite path="7|8B-ii">this chapter</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Clinical quality measures of obstetrical and neonatal care.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department may inspect each hospital and birthing facility to verify compliance with the requirements of <cite path="7|8B-ii">this chapter</cite> and to assess performance related to the elements set forth in subsection (a) of this section while conducting its annual inspection of each hospital and birthing facility.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Department shall issue an annual report that includes a report card for each hospital and birthing facility that summarizes the results of the hospital or birthing facility for each element set forth in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-290" type="History" path="ยง303">Apr. 11, 2019, D.C. Law 22-290, ยง303</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-290" eff="2019-04-11" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-06-24" doc="D.C. Law 23-118" eff="2020-06-24" path="ยง2|(e)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
