<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>48-855.02a</num>
  <heading>Insulin copayment or coinsurance limitation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A health insurer that provides coverage for prescription insulin drugs pursuant to the terms of a health benefits plan the insurer offers shall limit the total amount that an insured is required to pay for a 30-day supply of covered prescription insulin drugs at an amount not to exceed $30, regardless of the quantity or type of covered prescription insulin drug used to fill the insured's prescription.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A health insurer that provides coverage for diabetes devices and diabetic ketoacidosis devices pursuant to the terms of a health benefits plan offered by the insurer, shall limit the total amount that an insured is required to pay for a 30-day supply of all medically necessary covered diabetes devices and diabetic ketoacidosis devices that are in accordance with the insured's diabetes treatment plan at an amount not to exceed $100.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) of this section, prescription insulin drugs, diabetes devices, and diabetic ketoacidosis devices shall be covered without being subject to a deductible and any cost sharing paid by an insured shall be applied toward the insured's deductible obligation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section prevents an insurer from reducing an insured's copayment or coinsurance by an amount greater than the amount specified in subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>On July 1 of each year, the limit on a required copayment or coinsurance an insured is required to pay under subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall increase by a percentage equal to the percentage change from the preceding year in the medical care component of the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers, Washington-Arlington-Alexandria, DC-VA-MD-WV metropolitan area, as published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the United States Department of Labor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>This section shall apply as of January 1, 2022.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-248" type="History" path="ยง3a">April 7, 2017, D.C. Law 21-248, ยง 3a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-04-07" doc="D.C. Law 21-248" eff="2017-04-07" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-252" eff="2021-03-16" path="ยง2|(d)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
