<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>48-853.03b</num>
  <heading>Registration requirement for practitioners and dispensers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any practitioner who is licensed, registered, or otherwise permitted to prescribe, distribute, dispense, conduct research with respect to, or to administer a controlled substance or other covered substance in the course of his or her professional practice, and any dispenser who is licensed in the District of Columbia to dispense a controlled substance or other covered substance to an ultimate user, the user's agent, or owner in the case of animals, shall be registered with the Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Beginning 90 days afterJune 24, 2020, each practitioner or dispenser who is required to be registered with the Program, pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, shall register with the Program within 90 days of obtaining a new health professional license or before renewing an existing health professional license, whichever occurs first.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Health Occupations Boards shall not approve a practitioner or dispenser, who is required to be registered with the Program pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, for reinstatement, reactivation, or renewal of licensure without proof that the practitioner or dispenser has registered with the Program as required.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Failure to timely register with the Program shall constitute grounds for disciplinary action by the relevant health occupations board pursuant to <cite path="§3-1205.14|(c)">§ 3-1205.14(c)</cite>, and the imposition of civil fines pursuant to <cite path="§2-1801.04">§ 2-1801.04</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-66" type="History" path="§4b">Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-66, § 4b</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-06-24" doc="D.C. Law 23-116" eff="2020-06-24" path="§4|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
