<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>48-853.07</num>
  <heading>Criteria for indicators of misuse; Director’s authority to disclose information; intervention.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Director may establish through rulemaking:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Criteria for indicators of misuse or abuse of covered substances;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A method for analysis of data collected by the Program using the criteria for indicators of misuse or abuse of covered substances;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Criteria for indications of a possible violation of law or a possible breach of professional standards by a prescriber or dispenser; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A method for analysis of data collected by the Program using the criteria for indications of a possible violation of law or a possible breach of professional standards by a prescriber or dispenser.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Upon the development of the criteria and data analysis, the Program may review prescription monitoring program data for indications of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Possible misuse or abuse of a covered prescription drug; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A possible violation of law or possible breach of professional standards by a prescriber or a dispenser.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the Program's review of prescription monitoring data indicates a possible violation of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Director may, in addition to any discretionary disclosure of information pursuant to <cite path="48|8G">this chapter</cite>:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Report the possible misuse or abuse by a patient to the specific prescriber or dispenser of the covered prescription drug for the purpose of intervention to prevent such misuse or abuse;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Notify the prescriber or dispenser of the possible violation of law or possible breach of professional standards; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Provide education to the prescriber or dispenser.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-66" type="History" path="§8">Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-66, § 8, 61 DCR 7</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-288" eff="2019-04-11" path="§401|(d)|(1)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-288" eff="2019-04-11" path="§401|(d)|(1)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-288" eff="2019-04-11" path="§401|(d)|(1)|(C)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-288" eff="2019-04-11" path="§401|(d)|(2)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
