<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>48-921.51</num>
  <heading>Findings and declaration of policy.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The people of the District of Columbia find that use of entheogenic plants and fungi have been demonstrated, through scientific studies, to be beneficial in addressing a variety of afflictions, including substance abuse, addiction, trauma, post-traumatic stress syndrome, chronic depression, anxiety, diabetes, cluster headaches, and other conditions; and that practices with entheogenic plants and fungi have long existed, have been considered sacred to a number of cultures and religions for millennia, and continue to be enhanced and improved.  Citizens of the District of Columbia seeking to improve their health and well-being through the use of entheogenic plants and fungi currently use them in fear of arrest and prosecution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>It is declared that the policy of <cite path="48|9C">this chapter</cite> is to make investigation and arrest of adults for non-commercial planting, cultivating, purchasing, transporting, distributing, possessing, or engaging in practices with entheogenic plants and fungi among the lowest law enforcement priorities for the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§48-921.51" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§48-921.51">
      This section was created by Initiative No. 81, the Entheogenic Plant and Fungus Policy Act of 2020, D.C. Law 23-268, March 16, 2021, 68 DCR 1376.
    </codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-268" eff="2021-03-16" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-268" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-268" path="§2" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="2021-03-16" eff="2021-03-16">
      This section was created by Initiative No. 81, the Entheogenic Plant and Fungus Policy Act of 2020, D.C. Law 23-268, March 16, 2021, 68 DCR 1376.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-268" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
