<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>35-244</num>
  <heading>Transit subsidy for youth in the District's foster care system.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may establish a program ("Foster Youth Program") to allow youth in the District's foster care system to receive free fares on the Metrorail system, Metrobus system, and public transit services operated by the District government.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To be eligible to participate in the Foster Youth Program, a foster youth must be under 21 years of age.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may require each foster youth, or the foster youth's parent, guardian, or custodian to file an application on behalf of the foster youth to participate in the Foster Youth Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may impose a fee for the issuance or replacement of a transit card.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may establish standards for eligibility to participate in the Foster Youth Program, and may impose such other restrictions on eligibility and the use of free fares, including limiting the use of free fares to educational and employment purposes, that the Mayor deems appropriate for the proper operational and fiscal administration and of the Foster Youth Program.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation codify:doc="D.C. Code" path="§6045" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91">
          For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§6045">§ 6045 of the Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019</cite>, 66 DCR 8497).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§6045" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation codify:doc="D.C. Code" path="§6045" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112">
          For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§6045">§ 6045 of the Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019</cite>, 66 DCR 11964).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§6045" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="VI" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§6045" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
