<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>35-243</num>
  <heading>Kids Ride Free transit subsidy program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may establish a subsidy program, to be known as Kids Ride Free ("Kids Ride Free Program"), under which District elementary and secondary school students shall receive free fares on the Metrorail system, Metrobus system, and public transit systems operated by the District government.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To be eligible for the Kids Ride Free Program, a student shall be:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A resident of the District under 22 years of age; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Enrolled in one of the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A traditional District of Columbia public school or public charter school;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An alternative, adult, or special education District of Columbia public school or public charter school;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A private school, including a parochial school, in the District;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>An education program operated by the Office of the State Superintendent of Education; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Homeschooling in the District.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may require each student, student's parent or guardian, or student's school to file an application on behalf of the student to participate in the Kids Ride Free Program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may impose a fee for the issuance or replacement of a transit card.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may establish standards for eligibility to participate in the Kids Ride Free Program and may impose such other restrictions on eligibility and the use of free fares, including limiting the use of free fares to educational and employment purposes, that the Mayor deems appropriate for the proper operational and fiscal administration of the Kids Ride Free Program.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation codify:doc="D.C. Code" path="§6044" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91">
          For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§6044">§ 6044 of the Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019</cite>, 66 DCR 8497).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§6044" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation codify:doc="D.C. Code" path="§6044" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112">
          For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§6044">§ 6044 of the Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019</cite>, 66 DCR 11964).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§6044" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="VI" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§6044" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
