<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 15-194">
  <num type="law">15-194</num>
  <heading type="short">Omnibus Public Safety Agency Reform Amendment Act of 2004</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2004-09-30</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/15-194.pdf">D.C. Law 15-194</citation>
      <citation type="register">51 DCR 9406</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B15-0032">
      <narrative>Law 15-194, the “Omnibus Public Safety Agency Reform Amendment Act of 2004”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 15-32, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 6, 2004, and June 1, 2004, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 24, 2004, it was assigned Act No. 15-463 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 15-194 became effective on September 30, 2004.</narrative>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <container>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="5|4|II|B"/>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>II</num>
    <heading>TRAINING FOR FIRE AND EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES DEPARTMENT</heading>
    <section>
      <num>202</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-441"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="5|10A"/>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>V</num>
    <heading>DISCIPLINARY ACTIONS</heading>
    <container>
      <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="5|10A|I"/>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>A</num>
      <heading>DISCIPLINARY ACTIONS</heading>
      <section>
        <num>502</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1031"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>503</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1032"/>
      </section>
    </container>
    <container>
      <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="5|10A|II"/>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>B</num>
      <heading>FIREFIGHTER RETIREMENT WHILE UNDER DISCIPLINARY INVESTIGATION</heading>
      <section>
        <num>511</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1051"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>512</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1052"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>513</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1053"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>514</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1054"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>515</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1055"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>516</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1056"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>517</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1057"/>
      </section>
    </container>
  </container>
  <container>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="5|6A"/>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>VI</num>
    <heading>MEDICAL LEAVE AND LIMITED DUTY PROGRAM</heading>
    <container>
      <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="5|6A|I"/>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>B</num>
      <heading>LIMITED DUTY</heading>
      <section>
        <num>621</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-631"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>622</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-632"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>623</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-633"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>624</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-634"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>625</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-635"/>
      </section>
    </container>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="5|6A" after="I" history="false">
      <container>
        <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
        <num>II</num>
        <heading>Fire and Emergency Medical Services Employee Presumptive Disability.</heading>
      </container>
    </codify:insert>
    <container codify:applicability="2016-10-01">
      <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="5|6A|II"/>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>D</num>
      <heading>FIRE AND EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES EMPLOYEE PRESUMPTIVE DISABILITY</heading>
      <section>
        <codify:insert num-value="5-651"/>
        <num>651</num>
        <heading>Definitions.</heading>
        <text>For the purposes of <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="VI|D">this subtitle</code-cite>, the term:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>"Department" means the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>"Director" means the medical services officer for the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>"Documented" means the member or EMS employee gave notice to the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department, in writing, of his or her occupational exposure to blood or bodily fluids.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>"EMS employee" means a person that qualifies as an "emergency medical services personnel" as defined by <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-357" path="§2|(7)">section 2(7) of the Emergency Medical Services Act of 2008, effective March 25, 2009 (D.C. Law 17-357; D.C. Official Code § 7-2341.01(7))</code-cite>, is employed by the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department, and is not a sworn member of the Department.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>"Full range of duties" shall have the same meaning as provided in <code-cite path="§621|(5)" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">section 621(5)</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>"Member " means a sworn member of the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department who is employed by the Department.</text>
          <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3052|(a)|(1)" type="History"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>"Pre-employment physical examination" means the physical examination required under <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§721">section 721 of the Police and Fire Minimum Standards Amendment Act of 2004, effective September 30, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-194; D.C. Official Code § 5-451)</code-cite>.</text>
          <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3052|(a)|(2)" type="History"/>
        </para>
        <codify:annotation codify:applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§651">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§656">§ 656 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> provided that the the addition of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§651">§ 651 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been given effect.</codify:annotation>
        <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311">D.C. Law 19-311</cite> added this section.</annotation>
        <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 656 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>, as added by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311">D.C. Law 19-311</cite>, § 2, provided that this subchapter shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</annotation>
        <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 656 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>, as added by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311">D.C. Law 19-311</cite>, § 2, provided that this section shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</annotation>
        <annotation app="2013-05-01" doc="D.C. Law 19-311" eff="2013-05-01" path="§2" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
        <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§3052|(d)" app="2016-10-08" eff="2016-10-08">Section 3102(b) of Law 21-160 amended or repealed section 901 of D.C. Law 21-125, removing the applicability restriction affecting this section, therefore the creation of this section by section 104 of D.C. Law 21-125 has been implemented.</annotation>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3052|(d)" type="History"/>
        <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§651" app="2004-09-30" eff="2004-09-30">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§656">§ 656 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> provided that the the addition of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§651">§ 651 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been given effect.</annotation>
        <annotation app="2004-09-30" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" eff="2004-09-30" path="§651" type="History"/>
      </section>
      <section codify:applicability="notfunded">
        <codify:insert num-value="5-652"/>
        <num>652</num>
        <heading>Presumption as to disability or death from heart disease, hypertension, or respiratory disease.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>A member shall be presumed to have a performance-of-duty injury or illness that is covered by <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="VI|B">Subtitle B of Title VI of this act</code-cite> , <code-cite doc="Stat. 64-1-ch433" path="§12">section 12 of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and seventeen, and for other purposes, approved September 1, 1916 (39 Stat. 718; D.C. Official Code § 5-701 <em>passim</em>)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-708">sections 1 through 3 of An Act To provide for the payment of the cost of medical, surgical, hospital, or related health care services provided certain retired, disabled officers and members of the Metropolitan Police force of the District of Columbia, the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, the United States Park Police force, the Executive Protective Service, and the United States Secret Service, and for other purposes, approved August 16, 1971 (85 Stat. 341; D.C. Official Code § 5-708)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 96-122" path="§204|(c)" codify:value="§§ {{ target.num }}">sections 204(c)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 96-122" path="§205|(c)" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">205(c)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 96-122" path="§206|(b)" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">206(b)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 96-122" path="§208|(b)" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">208(b)</code-cite>, and <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 96-122" path="§209|(a)|(2)" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">209(a)(2) of  An Act To establish an actuarially sound basis for financing retirement benefits for police officers, fire fighters, teachers, and judges of the District of Columbia and to make certain changes in such benefits, approved November 17, 1979 (93 Stat. 866; D.C. Official Code §§ 5-711, 5-715, 5-702, 5-705, and 5-719, respectively)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 93-407" path="§122">section 122 of  An Act To increase compensation for District of Columbia policemen, firemen, and teachers; to increase annuities payable to retired teachers in the District of Columbia; to establish an equitable tax on real property in the District of Columbia; to provide for additional revenue for the District of Columbia; and for other purposes, approved September 3, 1974 (88 Stat. 1041; D.C. Official Code § 5-722)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 85-157" path="§4" codify:value="§§ {{ target.num }}">sections 4</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 85-157" path="§6" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">6</code-cite>, and <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 85-157" path="§7" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">7 of the Policemen and Firemen's Retirement and Disability Act amendments of 1957, approved August 21, 1957 (71 Stat. 399; D.C. Official Code § 5-731<em> et seq</em>.)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Stat. 74-1-ch241" path="§1">section 1 of An Act Making appropriations for the government of the District of Columbia and other activities chargeable in whole or in part against the revenues of such District for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1936, and for other purposes, approved June 14, 1935 (49 Stat. 358; D.C. Official Code § 5-741)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Stat. 80-1-ch272">An Act To credit active service in the military or naval forces of the United States in determining eligibility for and the amount of benefits from the policemen and firemen's relief fund, District of Columbia, approved July 21, 1947 (61 Stat. 398; D.C. Official Code § 5-742)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Stat. 71-2-ch783" path="§6">section 6 of An Act To fix the salaries of officers and members of the Metropolitan police force and the fire department of the District of Columbia, approved July 1, 1930 (46 Stat. 841: D.C. Official Code § 5-743)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Stat. 81-1-ch394" path="§3">section 3 of An Act to provide increased pensions for widows and children of deceased members and retired members of the Police Department and the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, approved August 4, 1949 (63 Stat. 566; D.C. Official Code § 5-744)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-745" technical="TODO. Confirm citation" codify:value="§§ {{ target.num }}">sections 301</code-cite> and <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-746" technical="TODO. Confirm citation" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">302 of An Act To adjust the salaries of officers and members of the Metropolitan Police force, the United States Park Police, the White House Police, and the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved June 20, 1953 (67 Stat. 75; D.C. Official Code §§ 7-745 and 7-746)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-747">sections 1 and 2 of  An Act To extend benefits of the Policemen and Firemen's Retirement and Disability Act Amendments of 1957 to widows and surviving children of former members of the Metropolitan Police force, the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, the United States Park Police force, the White House Police force, or the United States Secret Service Division, who were retired or who died in the service of any such organization prior to the effective date of such amendments, approved August 24, 1962 (76 Stat. 402; D.C. Official Code § 5-747)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 9-163" path="§2">section 2 of Retired Police Officer Redeployment Act of 1992, effective September 29, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-163; D.C. Official Code § 5-761)</code-cite>, and <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 10-136" path="§2">section 2 of the Retired Police Officer Public Schools Security Personnel Deployment Amendment Act of 1994, effective July 23, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-136; D.C. Official Code § 5-762)</code-cite>, unless such presumption is overcome by a preponderance of evidence to the contrary or the member is disqualified from the presumption pursuant to <code-cite path="§655" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">section 655</code-cite>, if:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The member has been diagnosed with heart disease, hypertension, or respiratory disease;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The heart disease, hypertension, or respiratory disease results in the member's inability to perform the full range of duties or in death;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>The member has undergone a pre-employment physical examination and the member was found, at the time of the examination, to be free of the performance-of-duty injury or illness underlying the presumption provided for in this subsection; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>The member, upon request of the Director, submits to a physical examination conducted by physicians selected by the Director.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>An EMS employee shall be presumed to have an occupational disease suffered in the line of duty that is covered by <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 3-77" path="I">the District of Columbia Workers' Compensation Act of 1979, effective July 1, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-77; D.C. Official Code § 32-1501 <em>et seq</em>.)</code-cite>, unless such presumption is overcome by a preponderance of evidence to the contrary or the member is disqualified from the presumption pursuant to <code-cite path="§655" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">section 655</code-cite>, if:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The EMS employee has been diagnosed with heart disease, hypertension, or respiratory disease;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The heart disease, hypertension, or respiratory disease results in the EMS employee's disability, as defined by <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 3-77" path="§2|(8)">section 2(8) of the District of Columbia Workers' Compensation Act of 1979, effective July 1, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-77; D.C. Official Code § 32-1501(8))</code-cite>, or in death;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>The EMS employee has undergone a pre-employment physical examination and the EMS employee was found, at the time of the examination, to be free of the occupational disease underlying the presumption provided for in this subsection; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>The EMS employee, upon request of the Director, submits to a physical examination conducted by physicians selected by the Director.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <codify:annotation codify:applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§652">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§656">§ 656 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> provided that the the addition of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§652">§ 652 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been given effect.</codify:annotation>
        <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311">D.C. Law 19-311</cite> added this section.</annotation>
        <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 656 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>, as added by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311">D.C. Law 19-311</cite>, § 2, provided that this subchapter shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</annotation>
        <annotation app="2013-05-01" doc="D.C. Law 19-311" eff="2013-05-01" path="§2" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
        <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§652" app="2004-09-30" eff="2004-09-30">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§656">§ 656 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> provided that the the addition of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§652">§ 652 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been given effect.</annotation>
        <annotation app="2004-09-30" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" eff="2004-09-30" path="§652" type="History"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert num-value="5-653"/>
        <num>653</num>
        <heading>Presumption as to disability or death from cancer.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>A member shall be presumed to have a performance-of-duty injury or illness that is covered by <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="VI|B">Subtitle B of Title VI of this act</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Stat. 64-1-ch433" path="§12">section 12 of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and seventeen, and for other purposes, approved September 1, 1916 (39 Stat. 718; D.C. Official Code § 5-701 <em>passim</em>)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-708">sections 1 through 3 of An Act To provide for the payment of the cost of medical, surgical, hospital, or related health care services provided certain retired, disabled officers and members of the Metropolitan Police force of the District of Columbia, the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, the United States Park Police force, the Executive Protective Service, and the United States Secret Service, and for other purposes, approved August 16, 1971(85 Stat. 341; D.C. Official Code § 5-708)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 96-122" path="§204|(c)" codify:value="§§ {{ target.num }}">sections 204(c)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 96-122" path="§205|(c)" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">205(c)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 96-122" path="§206|(b)" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">206(b)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 96-122" path="§208|(b)" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">208(b)</code-cite>, and <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 96-122" path="§209|(a)|(2)" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">209(a)(2) of  An Act To establish an actuarially sound basis for financing retirement benefits for police officers, fire fighters, teachers, and judges of the District of Columbia and to make certain changes in such benefits, approved November 17, 1979 (93 Stat. 866; D.C. Official Code §§ 5-711, 5-715, 5-702,5-705, and 5-719, respectively)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 93-407" path="§122">section 122 of  An Act To increase compensation for District of Columbia policemen, firemen, and teachers; to increase annuities payable to retired teachers in the District of Columbia; to establish an equitable tax on real property in the District of Columbia; to provide for additional revenue for the District of Columbia; and for other purposes, approved September 3, 1974 (88 Stat. 1041; D.C. Official Code § 5-722)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 85-157" path="§4" codify:value="§§ {{ target.num }}">sections 4</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 85-157" path="§6" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">6</code-cite>, and <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 85-157" path="§7" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">7 of the Policemen and Firemen's Retirement and Disability Act amendments of 1957, approved August 21, 1957 (71 Stat. 399;D.C. Official Code § 5-731<em> et seq</em>.)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Stat. 74-1-ch241" path="§1">section 1 of An Act Making appropriations for the government of the District of Columbia and other activities chargeable in whole or in part against the revenues of such District for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1936, and for other purposes, approved June 14, 1935 (49 Stat. 358; D.C. Official Code § 5-741)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Stat. 80-1-ch272">An Act To credit active service in the military or naval forces of the United States in determining eligibility for and the amount of benefits from the policemen and firemen's relief fund, District of Columbia, approved July 21, 1947 (61 Stat. 398; D.C. Official Code § 5-742)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Stat. 71-2-ch783" path="§6">section 6 of An Act To fix the salaries of officers and members of the Metropolitan police force and the fire department of the District of Columbia, approved July 1, 1930 (46 Stat. 841: D.C. Official Code § 5-743)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Stat. 81-1-ch394" path="§3">section 3 of An Act to provide increased pensions for widows and children of deceased members and retired members of the Police Department and the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, approved August 4, 1949 (63 Stat. 566; D.C. Official Code § 5-744)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-745" technical="TODO. Confirm citation" codify:value="§§ {{ target.num }}">sections 301</code-cite> and <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-746" technical="TODO. Confirm citation" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">302 of An Act To adjust the salaries of officers and members of the Metropolitan Police force, the United States Park Police, the White House Police, and the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved June 20, 1953 (67 Stat. 75; D.C. Official Code §§ 7-745 and 7-746)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-747">sections 1 and 2 of  An Act To extend benefits of the Policemen and Firemen's Retirement and Disability Act Amendments of 1957 to widows and surviving children of former members of the Metropolitan Police force, the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, the United States Park Police force, the White House Police force, or the United States Secret Service Division, who were retired or who died in the service of any such organization prior to the effective date of such amendments, approved August 24, 1962 (76 Stat. 402; D.C. Official Code § 5-747)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 9-163" path="§2">section 2 of Retired Police Officer Redeployment Act of 1992, effective September 29, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-163; D.C. Official Code § 5-761)</code-cite>, and <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 10-136" path="§2">section 2 of the Retired Police Officer Public Schools Security Personnel Deployment Amendment Act of 1994, effective July 23, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-136; D.C. Official Code § 5-762)</code-cite>, unless such presumption is overcome by a preponderance of evidence to the contrary or the member is disqualified from the presumption pursuant to <code-cite path="§655" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">section 655</code-cite>, if:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The member has been diagnosed with leukemia or breast, ovarian, pancreatic, prostate, rectal, testicular, or respiratory cancer, and that member has been in contact with or exposed to a toxic substance while in the line of duty that is associated with an increased risk of leukemia or cancer;</text>
            <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3052|(b)|(1)" type="History"/>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The member has completed at least 10 years of service with the Department;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>The leukemia or cancer results in the members' inability to perform the full range of duties or in death;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>The member has undergone a pre-employment physical examination and the member was found, at the time of the examination, to be free of the performance-of-duty injury or illness underlying the presumption provided for in this subsection; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(5)</num>
            <text>The member, upon request of the Director, submits to a physical examination conducted by physicians selected by the Director.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>An EMS employee shall be presumed to have an occupational disease suffered in the line of duty that is covered by <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 3-77" path="I">the District of Columbia Workers' Compensation Act of 1979, effective July 1, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-77; D.C. Official Code § 32-1501 <em>et seq</em>.)</code-cite>, unless such presumption is overcome by a preponderance of evidence to the contrary or the member is disqualified from the presumption pursuant to <code-cite path="§655" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">section 655</code-cite>, if:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The EMS employee has been diagnosed with leukemia or breast, ovarian, pancreatic, prostate, rectal, testicular, or respiratory cancer, and that EMS employee has been in contact with or exposed to a toxic substance while in the line of duty that is associated with an increased risk of leukemia or cancer;</text>
            <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3052|(b)|(2)" type="History"/>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The EMS employee has completed at least 10 years of service with the Department;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>The leukemia or cancer results in the EMS employee's disability, as defined by <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 3-77" path="§2|(8)">section 2(8) of the District of Columbia Workers' Compensation Act of 1979, effective July 1, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-77; D.C. Official Code § 32-1501(8))</code-cite>, or in death;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>The EMS employee has undergone a pre-employment physical examination and the EMS employee was found, at the time of the examination, to be free of the occupational disease underlying the presumption provided for in this subsection; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(5)</num>
            <text>The EMS employee, upon request of the Director, submits to a physical examination conducted by physicians selected by the Director.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <codify:annotation codify:applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§653">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§656">§ 656 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> provided that the the addition of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§653">§ 653 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been given effect.</codify:annotation>
        <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311">D.C. Law 19-311</cite> added this section.</annotation>
        <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 656 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>, as added by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311">D.C. Law 19-311</cite>, § 2, provided that this subchapter shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</annotation>
        <annotation app="2013-05-01" doc="D.C. Law 19-311" eff="2013-05-01" path="§2" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
        <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§3052|(d)" app="2016-10-08" eff="2016-10-08">Section 3102(b) of Law 21-160 amended or repealed section 901 of D.C. Law 21-125, removing the applicability restriction affecting this section, therefore the creation of this section by section 104 of D.C. Law 21-125 has been implemented.</annotation>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3052|(d)" type="History"/>
        <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§653" app="2004-09-30" eff="2004-09-30">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§656">§ 656 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> provided that the the addition of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§653">§ 653 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been given effect.</annotation>
        <annotation app="2004-09-30" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" eff="2004-09-30" path="§653" type="History"/>
      </section>
      <section codify:applicability="notfunded">
        <codify:insert num-value="5-654"/>
        <num>654</num>
        <heading>Presumption as to disability or death from infectious disease.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>A member shall be presumed to have a performance-of-duty injury or illness that is covered by <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="VI|B">Subtitle B of Title VI of this act</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Stat. 64-1-ch433" path="§12">section 12 of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and seventeen, and for other purposes, approved September 1, 1916 (39 Stat. 718; D.C. Official Code § 5-701 <em>passim</em>)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-708">sections 1 through 3 of An Act To provide for the payment of the cost of medical, surgical, hospital, or related health care services provided certain retired, disabled officers and members of the Metropolitan Police force of the District of Columbia, the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, the United States Park Police force, the Executive Protective Service, and the United States Secret Service, and for other purposes, approved August 16, 1971(85 Stat. 341; D.C. Official Code § 5-708)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 96-122" path="§204|(c)" codify:value="§§ {{ target.num }}">sections 204(c)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 96-122" path="§205|(c)" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">205(c)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 96-122" path="§206|(b)" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">206(b)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 96-122" path="§208|(b)" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">208(b)</code-cite>, and <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 96-122" path="§209|(a)|(2)" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">209(a)(2) of  An Act To establish an actuarially sound basis for financing retirement benefits for police officers, fire fighters, teachers, and judges of the District of Columbia and to make certain changes in such benefits, approved November 17, 1979 (93 Stat. 866; D.C. Official Code §§ 5-711, 5-715, 5-702,5-705, and 5-719, respectively)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 93-407" path="§122">section 122 of  An Act To increase compensation for District of Columbia policemen, firemen, and teachers; to increase annuities payable to retired teachers in the District of Columbia; to establish an equitable tax on real property in the District of Columbia; to provide for additional revenue for the District of Columbia; and for other purposes, approved September 3, 1974 (88 Stat. 1041; D.C. Official Code § 5-722)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 85-157" path="§4" codify:value="§§ {{ target.num }}">sections 4</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 85-157" path="§6" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">6</code-cite>, and <code-cite doc="Pub. L. 85-157" path="§7" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">7 of the Policemen and Firemen's Retirement and Disability Act amendments of 1957, approved August 21, 1957 (71 Stat. 399;D.C. Official Code § 5-731<em> et seq</em>.)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Stat. 74-1-ch241" path="§1">section 1 of An Act Making appropriations for the government of the District of Columbia and other activities chargeable in whole or in part against the revenues of such District for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1936, and for other purposes, approved June 14, 1935 (49 Stat. 358; D.C. Official Code § 5-741)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Stat. 80-1-ch272">An Act To credit active service in the military or naval forces of the United States in determining eligibility for and the amount of benefits from the policemen and firemen's relief fund, District of Columbia, approved July 21, 1947 (61 Stat. 398; D.C. Official Code § 5-742)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Stat. 71-2-ch783" path="§6">section 6 of An Act To fix the salaries of officers and members of the Metropolitan police force and the fire department of the District of Columbia, approved July 1, 1930 (46 Stat. 841: D.C. Official Code § 5-743)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="Stat. 81-1-ch394" path="§3">section 3 of An Act to provide increased pensions for widows and children of deceased members and retired members of the Police Department and the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, approved August 4, 1949 (63 Stat. 566; D.C. Official Code § 5-744)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-745" technical="TODO. Confirm citation" codify:value="§§ {{ target.num }}">sections 301</code-cite> and <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-746" technical="TODO. Confirm citation" codify:value="{{ target.num }}">302 of An Act To adjust the salaries of officers and members of the Metropolitan Police force, the United States Park Police, the White House Police, and the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved June 20, 1953 (67 Stat. 75; D.C. Official Code §§ 7-745 and 7-746)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-747">sections 1 and 2 of  An Act To extend benefits of the Policemen and Firemen's Retirement and Disability Act Amendments of 1957 to widows and surviving children of former members of the Metropolitan Police force, the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, the United States Park Police force, the White House Police force, or the United States Secret Service Division, who were retired or who died in the service of any such organization prior to the effective date of such amendments, approved August 24, 1962 (76 Stat. 402; D.C. Official Code § 5-747)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 9-163" path="§2">section 2 of Retired Police Officer Redeployment Act of 1992, effective September 29, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-163; D.C. Official Code § 5-761)</code-cite>, and <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 10-136" path="§2">section 2 of the Retired Police Officer Public Schools Security Personnel Deployment Amendment Act of 1994, effective July 23, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-136; D.C. Official Code § 5-762)</code-cite>, unless such presumption is overcome by a preponderance of evidence to the contrary or the member is disqualified from the presumption pursuant to <code-cite path="§655" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">section 655</code-cite>, if:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The member has been diagnosed with hepatitis, meningococcal meningitis, tuberculosis, or human immunodeficiency virus ("HIV");</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The member has had a documented exposure to blood or bodily fluids during the performance of job duties;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>The hepatitis, meningococcal meningitis, tuberculosis, or HIV results in the member's inability to perform the full range of duties or in death;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>The member has undergone a pre-employment physical examination and the was found, at the time of the examination, to be free of the performance-of-duty injury or illness underlying the presumption provided for in this subsection; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(5)</num>
            <text>The member, upon request of the Director, submits to a physical examination conducted by physicians selected by the Director.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>An EMS employee shall be presumed to have an occupation disease suffered in the line of duty that is covered by <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 3-77" path="I">the District of Columbia Workers' Compensation Act of 1979, effective July 1, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-77; D.C. Official Code § 32-1501 <em>et seq</em>.)</code-cite>, unless such presumption is overcome by a preponderance of evidence to the contrary or the member is disqualified from the presumption pursuant to <code-cite path="§655" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">section 655</code-cite>, if:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The EMS employee has been diagnosed with hepatitis, meningococcal meningitis, tuberculosis, or human immunodeficiency virus ("HIV");</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The EMS employee has had a documented exposure to blood or bodily fluids during the performance of job duties;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>The hepatitis, meningococcal meningitis, tuberculosis, or HIV results in the EMS employee's disability, as defined by <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 3-77" path="§2|(8)">section 2(8) of the District of Columbia Workers' Compensation Act of 1979, effective July 1, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-77; D.C. Official Code § 32-1501(8))</code-cite>, or in death;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>The EMS employee has undergone a pre-employment physical examination and the EMS employee was found, at the time of the examination, to be free of the occupational disease underlying the presumption provided for in this subsection; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(5)</num>
            <text>The EMS employee, upon request of the Director, submits to a physical examination conducted by physicians selected by the Director.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <codify:annotation codify:applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§654">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§656">§ 656 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> provided that the the addition of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§654">§ 654 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been given effect.</codify:annotation>
        <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311">D.C. Law 19-311</cite> added this section.</annotation>
        <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 656 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>, as added by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311">D.C. Law 19-311</cite>, § 2, provided that this subchapter shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</annotation>
        <annotation app="2013-05-01" doc="D.C. Law 19-311" eff="2013-05-01" path="§2" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
        <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§654" app="2004-09-30" eff="2004-09-30">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§656">§ 656 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> provided that the the addition of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§654">§ 654 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been given effect.</annotation>
        <annotation app="2004-09-30" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" eff="2004-09-30" path="§654" type="History"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert num-value="5-655"/>
        <num>655</num>
        <heading>Disqualification from presumption as to disability or death.</heading>
        <text>A member or an EMS employee shall be disqualified from a presumption under <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="VI|D">this subtitle</code-cite> if:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Any standard, medically recognized vaccine or other form of immunization or prophylaxis exists for the prevention of any injury or illness for which a presumption is established under <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="VI|D">this subtitle</code-cite>, if medically indicated by the given circumstances pursuant to immunization policies established by the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices of the United States Public Health Service;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The member or EMS employee is required by the Department to undergo the immunization or prophylaxis, unless the member or EMS employee has a written declaration from his or her physician stating that the immunization or prophylaxis would pose a significant risk to the person's health; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>The member or EMS employee has failed to or refused to undergo such immunization or prophylaxis.</text>
        </para>
        <codify:annotation codify:applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§655">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§656">§ 656 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> provided that the the addition of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§655">§ 655 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been given effect.</codify:annotation>
        <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311">D.C. Law 19-311</cite> added this section.</annotation>
        <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 656 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>, as added by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311">D.C. Law 19-311</cite>, § 2, provided that this subchapter shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</annotation>
        <annotation app="2013-05-01" doc="D.C. Law 19-311" eff="2013-05-01" path="§2" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
        <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§3052|(d)" app="2016-10-08" eff="2016-10-08">Section 3102(b) of Law 21-160 amended or repealed section 901 of D.C. Law 21-125, removing the applicability restriction affecting this section, therefore the creation of this section by section 104 of D.C. Law 21-125 has been implemented.</annotation>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3052|(d)" type="History"/>
        <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§655" app="2004-09-30" eff="2004-09-30">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§656">§ 656 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> provided that the the addition of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§655">§ 655 of D.C. Law 15-194, as added by § 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been given effect.</annotation>
        <annotation app="2004-09-30" doc="D.C. Law 15-194" eff="2004-09-30" path="§655" type="History"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="5|6A|II" after="§5-655" num-value="5-655.01"/>
        <num>655a</num>
        <heading>Physical examinations; maintaining eligibility.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>In order to be eligible to make a claim under <code-cite path="VI" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">this title</code-cite> that relies on a presumption created by <code-cite path="VI|D" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">this subtitle</code-cite>, a member shall, in addition to meeting any other requirements as required by <code-cite path="VI|D" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">this subtitle</code-cite> or rules issued pursuant to <code-cite path="§655c" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">section 655c</code-cite>, have undergone a pre-employment physical examination and complied with any subsequent physical examination requirements, such as annual physical examinations, that are, or were during the period of covered service, applicable to all members.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>In order to be eligible to make a claim under <code-cite path="VI" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">this title</code-cite> that relies on a presumption created by <code-cite path="VI|D" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">this subtitle</code-cite>, an EMS employee shall, in addition to meeting any other requirements as required by <code-cite path="VI" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">this subtitle</code-cite> or rules issued pursuant to <code-cite path="§655c" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">section 655c</code-cite>, have undergone a pre-employment physical examination and complied with any subsequent physical examination requirements, such as annual physical examinations, that are, or were during the period of covered service, applicable to all EMS employees.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>For any member or EMS employee hired after May 1, 2013, the District may require additional, appropriate laboratory and other diagnostic studies to be included as part of the pre-employment physical examination; provided, that any such requirements shall be applicable to all members or EMS employees.</text>
        </para>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3052|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="5|6A|II" after="§5-655.01" num-value="5-655.02"/>
        <num>655b</num>
        <heading>Reporting requirements.</heading>
        <text>By January 31, 2018, and by January 31 of each subsequent year, the Department, in coordination with the Police and Fire Clinic, shall submit an annual report to the Council that contains the following information from the preceding calendar year:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The total number of claims made by members in which a presumption was created under <code-cite path="§652" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">section 652</code-cite>;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The total number of claims made by EMS employees in which a presumption was created under <code-cite path="§652" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">section 652</code-cite>;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>The total number of claims made by members in which a presumption was created under <code-cite path="§653" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">section 653</code-cite>;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>The total number of claims made by EMS employees in which a presumption was created under <code-cite path="§653" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">section 653</code-cite>;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>The total number of claims made by members in which a presumption was created under <code-cite path="§654" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">section 654</code-cite>; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>The total number of claims made by EMS employees in which a presumption was created under <code-cite path="§654" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">section 654</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3052|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="5|6A|II" after="§5-655.02" num-value="5-655.03"/>
        <num>655c</num>
        <heading>Rules.</heading>
        <text>The Mayor, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 <em>et seq.</em>), may issue rules to implement the provisions of this subtitle.</text>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3052|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <codify:insert num-value="5-656"/>
        <num>656</num>
        <heading>Applicability.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, <code-cite path="VI|D" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">this subtitle</code-cite> shall apply as of October 1, 2016.</text>
          <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="VI|D" date="2016-10-01" history="false"/>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Sections <code-cite path="§652" codify:value="{{ target.num }}" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">652</code-cite> and <code-cite path="§654" codify:value="{{ target.num }}" doc="D.C. Law 15-194">654</code-cite> shall apply upon the date of inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
            <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§652" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
            <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 15-194" path="§654" date="notfunded" history="false"/>
            <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-654" history="false" type="Applicability"><cite doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§3052|(d)">
                    Section 3052(d) of Law 21-160</cite> amended section 656 of D.C. Law 19-311, retaining the applicability restriction affecting this section, therefore the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311" path="§2">section 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> has not been implemented. 
                  </codify:annotation>
            <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-655" history="false" type="Applicability"><cite doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§3052|(d)">
                    Section 3052(d) of Law 21-160</cite> amended section 656 of D.C. Law 19-311, removing the applicability restriction affecting this section, therefore the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311" path="§2">section 2 of D.C. Law 19-311</cite> has been implemented. 
                  </codify:annotation>
            <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311">D.C. Law 19-311</cite> added this section.</annotation>
            <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 656 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>, as added by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311">D.C. Law 19-311</cite>, § 2, provided that this subchapter shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</annotation>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of these sections.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
        <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311">D.C. Law 19-311</cite> added this section.</annotation>
        <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 656 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-194">D.C. Law 15-194</cite>, as added by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-311">D.C. Law 19-311</cite>, § 2, provided that this subchapter shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</annotation>
        <annotation app="notfunded" doc="D.C. Law 19-311" eff="2013-05-01" path="§2" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
        <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3052|(d)" type="History"/>
      </section>
    </container>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>VII</num>
    <heading>METROPOLITAN POLICE DEPARTMENT AND FIRE AND EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES DEPARTMENT MINIMUM STANDARDS</heading>
    <container>
      <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="5|4|III"/>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>B</num>
      <heading>TODO</heading>
      <section>
        <num>721</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-451"/>
      </section>
    </container>
  </container>
  <container>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="5|1|XV-B"/>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>X</num>
    <heading>METROPOLITAN POLICE DEPARTMENT RESERVE CORPS</heading>
    <section>
      <num>1002</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-129.51"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>TITLE</prefix>
    <num>XI</num>
    <heading>DETECTIVE ADVISERS</heading>
    <container>
      <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="5|1|XV-A"/>
      <prefix>SUBTITLE</prefix>
      <num>A</num>
      <heading>TODO</heading>
      <section>
        <num>1102</num>
        <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-129.31"/>
      </section>
    </container>
  </container>
</document>
