<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="D.C. Law 18-160" flag="true" doc-type="dclaw" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify">
  <num type="law">18-160</num>
  <heading type="short">Attorney General for the District of Columbia Clarification and Elected Term Amendment Act of 2010</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2010-05-27</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/18-160.pdf">D.C. Law 18-160</citation>
      <citation type="register">57 DCR 3012</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B18-0065">
      <narrative>Law 18-160, the “Attorney General for the District of Columbia Clarification and Elected Term Amendment Act of 2010”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-65, which was referred to the Committee on Public Safety and the Judiciary. The bill was adopted on first and second readings on January 5, 2010, and February 2, 2010, respectively. Deemed approved without the signature of the Mayor on March 30, 2010, it was assigned Act No. 18-351 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-160 became effective on May 27, 2010.</narrative>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>101</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.81" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>102</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.82" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>103</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.83" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>104</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.84" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>105</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.85" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>106</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.86" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>106a</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.86a" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>106b</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.86b" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>107</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.87" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>108</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.88" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>108a</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.88a" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>108b</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.88b" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>109</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.89" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>110</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.89a" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>111</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.89b" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>110a</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.89c" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>121</num>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.90" />
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:organic num-value="1-301.88e" />
    <num>110b[108e]</num>
    <heading>Authority to issue subpoenas in matters involving the financial exploitation of vulnerable adults and the elderly.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding section 110(a), and subject to the requirements under this section, the Attorney General for the District of Columbia shall have the authority to issue subpoenas for the production of documents and materials or for the attendance and testimony of witnesses under oath, or both, for the purposes of seeking relief under sections 207 and 208 of the Criminal Abuse, Neglect, and Financial Exploitation of Vulnerable Adults and the Elderly Act of 2000,  passed on 2nd reading on July 12, 2016 (Enrolled version of Bill 21-326).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subpoena authority established by this section may only be used in furtherance of seeking relief under sections 207 and 208 of the Criminal Abuse, Neglect, and Financial Exploitation of Vulnerable Adults and the Elderly Act of 2000, passed on 2nd reading on July 12, 2016 (Enrolled version of Bill 21-326).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Testimony obtained pursuant to this subpoena authority shall not be used in furtherance of a criminal investigation related to a violation of section 203a of the Criminal Abuse, Neglect, and Financial Exploitation of Vulnerable Adults and the Elderly Act of 2000, passed on 2nd reading on July 12, 2016 (Enrolled version of Bill 21-326), and shall not be admissible in a criminal proceeding against the person who provided the information.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General shall not have the authority to issue a subpoena under this section if an indictment, information, or petition has been filed with the court formally charging the target of the investigation with a violation of section 203a of the Criminal Abuse, Neglect, and Financial Exploitation of Vulnerable Adults and the Elderly Act of 2000, passed on 2nd reading on July 12, 2016 (Enrolled version of Bill 21-326).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The power to issue subpoenas pursuant to this section shall not be delegated other than to the Chief Deputy Attorney General, a Deputy Attorney General, or an Assistant Deputy Attorney General.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Subpoenas issued pursuant to this section shall contain the information required in section 110a(b).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Unless otherwise permitted by the Office of the Attorney General, only attorneys for the Office of the Attorney General and their staff, other people involved in the investigation, the witness under examination, his or her attorney, interpreters when needed, and, for the purpose of taking the evidence, a stenographer or operator of a recording device may be present during the taking of testimony.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>In the case of refusal to obey a subpoena issued under this section, the Attorney General may petition the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for an order requiring compliance. Any failure to obey the order of the court may be treated by the court as contempt.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Any person to whom a subpoena has been issued under this section may exercise the privileges enjoyed by all witnesses.  A person to whom a subpoena has been issued may move to quash or modify the subpoena in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia on grounds including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Attorney General failed to follow or satisfy the procedures set forth in this section for issuance of a subpoena;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The Attorney General lacked the authority to issue the subpoena under this section; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Any other grounds that exist under statute or common law for quashing or modification of a subpoena.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <annotation app="2016-11-23" doc="D.C. Law 21-166" eff="2016-11-23" path="§4" prefix="as added" type="History" />
  </section>
</document>