<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 17-250" flag="true">
  <num type="law">17-250</num>
  <heading type="short">Clean and Affordable energy Amendment Act of 2008</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2008-10-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/17-250.pdf">D.C. Law 17-250</citation>
      <citation type="register">55 DCR 9225</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B17-0492">
      <narrative>Law 17-250, the “Clean and Affordable energy Amendment Act of 2008”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-492 which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 1, 2008, and July 15, 2008, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 4, 2008, it was assigned Act No. 17-497 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-250 became effective on October 22, 2008.</narrative>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>101</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1773.01"/>
  </section>
  <container>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="8|17N|II"/>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>II</num>
    <heading>MANAGEMENT OF SUSTAINABLE ENERGY PROGRAMS.</heading>
    <section>
      <num>201</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1774.01"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>202</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1774.02"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>203</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1774.03"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>204</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1774.04"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>205</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1774.05"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>206</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1774.06"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>207</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1774.07"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>208</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1774.08"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>209</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1774.09"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>210</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1774.10"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>211</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1774.11"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>213</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1774.13"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>214</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1774.14"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>215</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1774.15"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <codify:organic num-value="8-1774.16"/>
      <num>216</num>
      <heading>Solar for All Program.</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>There is established the Solar for All Program ("Program") to increase the access of seniors, small local businesses, nonprofits, and low-income households in the District to the benefits of solar power. The Program shall reduce by at least 50% the electric bills of at least 100,000 of the District's low-income households with high energy burdens by December 31, 2032.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>The Program shall be administered by DOEE and operate until the end of Fiscal Year 2032. In administering the Program, DOEE shall coordinate with the Sustainable Energy Utility.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>From Fiscal Year 2017 through Fiscal Year 2032, the Program shall be funded annually from the Renewable Energy Development Fund established by <code-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-340" path="§8">section 8 of the Renewable Energy Portfolio Standard Act of 2004, effective April 12, 2005 (D.C. Law 15-340; D.C. Official Code § 34-1436)</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <text>The funding allocated in subsection (c) of this section may be used to supplement programs supporting the creation of new solar energy sources in the District through the Sustainable Energy Utility contract established by <code-cite path="§201" doc="D.C. Law 17-250"> section 201</code-cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(e)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>By February 1, 2017, DOEE shall develop, publish on its website, and submit to the Council a plan to implement the Program. The plan shall include:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>A description of programs to be implemented by DOEE that would target seniors, small local businesses, nonprofits, and low-income households in the District;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>An estimated timeline for implementation of the programs described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Annual benchmarks for reducing by at least 50% the electric bills of at least 100,000 of the District's low-income households with high energy burdens by December 31, 2032.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>If DOEE revises or updates the plan, DOEE shall publish on its website the revision or update within 30 days of its completion.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(f)</num>
        <text>Beginning December 1, 2017, DOEE shall publish on its website and submit to the Council an annual report on the expenditure of the funds allocated to the Program, the amount of progress toward achieving the benchmarks established in subsection (e)(1)(C) of this section, and the number of solar systems installed pursuant to this section in the previous fiscal year.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(g)</num>
        <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>"Area median income" means:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>For a household of 4 persons, the area median income for a household of 4 persons in the Washington Metropolitan Statistical Area as set forth in the periodic calculation provided by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>For a household of 3 persons, 90% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons, as described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>For a household of 2 persons, 80% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons, as described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>For a household of one person, 70% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons, as described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(E)</num>
            <text>For a household of more than 4 persons, the area median income for a household of 4 persons, as described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, increased by 10% for each person in the household in excess of 4 persons (for example, the area median income for a household of 5 persons shall be 110% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons, as described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, and the area median income for a household of 6 persons shall be 120% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons, as described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph).</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>"Energy burden" means the percentage of household income spent on home energy bills.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>"Low-income" means a household income equal to, or less than, 80% of the area median income.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>"Solar system" means a solar photovoltaic or solar thermal system.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-154" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <section>
    <num>601</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1775.01"/>
  </section>
  <container>
    <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="34|15A"/>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>VII</num>
    <heading>Submetering Provisions.</heading>
    <section>
      <num>701</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-1551"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>702</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-1552"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>703</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-1553"/>
    </section>
  </container>
</document>
