<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="Stat. 75-3-ch31">
  <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="50|11|I"/>
  <heading/>
  <meta>
    <effective>1938-02-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law">ch. 31</citation>
    </citations>
  </meta>
  <page citation="52 Stat. 78"/>
  <section>
    <num>1</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1101"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1102"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1103"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1104"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1105"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1106"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1107"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1108"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>9</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1109"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert after="§50-1109" num-value="50-1110"/>
    <num>10</num>
    <heading>Self-service exhaust emissions testing pilot program.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Within 120 days after <span codify:value="October 8, 2016">the effective date of the Self-Service Exhaust Emissions Testing Pilot Program Amendment Act of 2016,passed on 2nd reading on June 21, 2016 (Enrolled version of Bill 21-669)</span>, the Department of Motor Vehicles ("Department") shall establish a pilot program to provide for the use of one or more self-service kiosks to test motor vehicles for exhaust emissions.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At a minimum, each kiosk shall allow:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>An individual to test a motor vehicle to determine whether the vehicle complies with the exhaust emissions standards established under <code-cite doc="Stat. 75-3-ch31">this act</code-cite> and regulations issued pursuant to <code-cite doc="Stat. 75-3-ch31">this act</code-cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>For testing 24 hours per day, 7 days per week, on a first-come, first-served basis; provided, that the Department may periodically close a kiosk for necessary maintenance.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>The Department shall establish the specifications for the kiosks, the types of motor vehicles that are eligible for self-service exhaust emissions testing, the location of the kiosks, and the cost per test; provided, that the cost per test shall not exceed the cost per test of an exhaust emissions test conducted at a non-self-service inspection station.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Department may enter into contracts with one or more vendors for the equipment, operation, and maintenance necessary to conduct the pilot program.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>On or before March 30, 2018, the Department shall submit a written report to the Council that evaluates the pilot program's operations, including the number of vehicles inspected, a description of issues that arose during the reporting period, and a study of the impact of the pilot program on the number of vehicles inspected and wait times at non-self-service inspection stations.</text>
    </para>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§6142" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </section>
</document>
