<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-125</num>
  <heading>Distillery pub permit requirements and qualifications.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A distillery pub permit shall authorize the licensee to manufacture, blend, rectify, and store distilled spirits at one location from fruits, grains, neutral grain spirits, or distilled spirits transported from an area that produces distilled spirits to the licensed restaurant, tavern, multipurpose facility, hotel, or nightclub for on-premises consumption, and for sale to licensed wholesalers for the purpose of resale to other licensees.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A distillery pub permit shall be issued only to the licensee under an on-premises restaurant, tavern, multipurpose facility, hotel, or nightclub license, class C, in conjunction with the issuance of an on-premises restaurant, tavern, multipurpose facility, hotel, or nightclub license, class C.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The location used to manufacture or age distilled spirits shall be on or immediately adjacent to the restaurant, tavern, multipurpose facility, hotel, or nightclub licensed to the distillery pub owner in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a licensee has submitted a completed application for or received a distillery pub permit on or after February 7, 2018, the establishment shall only be permitted to sell distilled spirits to patrons in sealed bottles or other closed containers for off-premises consumption if the spirits are:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Manufactured at the distillery pub permit holder's licensed location;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Manufactured by the holder of the distillery pub permit or an entity with a shared ownership interest of 5% or more in the location where the distillery pub permit is located, regardless of jurisdiction; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Manufactured by the holder of the distillery pub permit as a part of a collaboration with another distilled spirits manufacturer, regardless of jurisdiction.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Sales of distilled spirits in accordance with this subsection shall be limited to the hours of 7:00 a.m. to 12:00 a.m., 7 days a week.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d-1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a licensee possesses or has submitted a completed application for a distillery pub permit before February 7, 2018, the establishment may sell distilled spirits to patrons in sealed bottles or other closed containers for off-premises consumption if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Within 60 days of receiving the distillery pub permit, the licensee, at all times, makes distilled spirits manufactured at the licensed premises available to and offers it for sale to patrons or has distilled spirits that is in the process of being manufactured and currently undergoing the production process on the licensed premises; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The holder of the distillery pub permit has distilled spirits manufactured at the licensed premises available and offered for sale to patrons on the licensed premises for at least 90 days in a calendar year.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The holder of the distillery pub permit shall maintain upon the licensed premises, either physically or electronically, books and records that reflect the days in which distilled spirits manufactured on the licensed premises were available and offered for sale to patrons.  The holder of the distillery pub permit shall allow any ABRA investigator or any member of the Metropolitan Police Department a full opportunity to examine its records at any time during its business hours.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>It shall be a violation for the holder of a distillery pub permit issued pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection to not have manufacturing equipment on the licensed premises or to not be in compliance with paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>In accordance with <cite path="§25-823">§ 25-823</cite>, the Board may fine, as set forth in the schedule of civil penalties established under <cite path="§25-830">§ 25-830</cite>, and revoke or suspend a distillery pub permit if the holder of the distillery pub permit fails to comply with the terms of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A distillery pub permit issued pursuant to this subsection shall expire upon the revocation, cancellation, or transfer of the license.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The minimum annual fee of the distillery pub permit shall be $7,500.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A distillery pub permit shall be cancelled or revoked if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The restaurant, tavern, multipurpose facility, hotel, or nightclub ceases to be operated as a restaurant, tavern, multipurpose facility, hotel, or nightclub; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The licensee’s on-premises retailer’s license, class C, is revoked or cancelled.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A distillery pub permit shall be automatically suspended whenever and for the same period that the licensee’s on-premises retailer’s license, class C, is suspended.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-78" type="History">Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-78, § 2(b), 61 DCR 151</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-165" eff="2018-10-30" path="§2|(a)|(10)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-165" eff="2018-10-30" path="§2|(a)|(10)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-165" eff="2018-10-30" path="§2|(a)|(10)|(C)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>A licensee holding distillery pub permits at separate locations in the District shall be permitted to transport distilled spirits for sale and consumption manufactured at one distillery pub facility to another distillery pub facility owned by the licensee.</text>
  </para>
</section>
