<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>25-204.02</num>
  <heading>Medical marijuana program; transfer of functions of the Department of Health.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board and ABRA shall be responsible for carrying out the responsibilities assigned to them by <cite path="7|16B">[Chapter 16B of Title 7]</cite> ("Medical Marijuana Act"), and for any responsibilities of the Mayor under the <cite path="7|16B">Medical Marijuana Act</cite> that the Mayor delegates to the Board or ABRA.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, all personal property, assets, records, including both electronic and physical files, licensing agreements, and contracts, equipment, computer software, obligations, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, assets, and liabilities, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the powers, duties, functions, operations, and administration by the Department of Health of the medical marijuana program pursuant to <cite path="7|16B">[Chapter 16B of Title 7]</cite>, as of September 30, 2020, are transferred to ABRA.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>This subsection shall not apply to the personal property, assets, records, including both electronic and physical files, licensing agreements, and contracts, equipment, computer software, obligations, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, assets, and liabilities, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the powers, duties, functions, operations, and administration by the Department of Health of the medical marijuana program that are within the purview of the Board of Medicine, Board of Nursing, or Board of Dentistry.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All rules, orders, obligations, determinations, contracts, agreements, and understandings of the Department of Health pertaining to the medical marijuana program shall remain in effect until such time as they may be lawfully amended, modified, or repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>ABRA shall coordinate with the Department of Health regarding the transition of the administration of the medical marijuana program to ABRA.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The directors of ABRA and the Department of Health shall jointly determine which personnel, if any, of the Department of Health associated with the administration of the medical marijuana program shall be transferred from the Department of Health to ABRA.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Personnel who are transferred to ABRA pursuant to this subsection shall be subject to the ABRA Director's personnel authority, pursuant to <cite path="ยง1-604.06|(b)|(21)">[ยง 1-604.06(b)(21)]</cite>, including as it relates to employment classifications and pay scales.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="ยง5013|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
