<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-701</num>
  <heading>Board-approved manager required.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person designated to manage an establishment shall possess a manager’s license.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an establishment's owner or Board-approved manager shall be present on the premises at all times during the establishment's hours of sale, service, and consumption of alcoholic beverages.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The presence of an establishment's owner or Board-approved manager shall not be required when:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>There are not any alcoholic beverages on the premises;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The establishment is not open to the public;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Alcoholic beverages are secure and not accessible to the public for sale, service, or consumption; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The license is in safekeeping pursuant to <cite path="§25-791">§ 25-791</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A licensee shall notify the Board within 7 calendar days of a manager’s conviction for other than a minor traffic violation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to the holder of a wholesaler's license or off-premises retailer's license, class AI or BI, that is not open to the public or to licensees who personally superintend the establishment during licensed hours of sale.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-201" type="History">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-201, § 5(b), 55 DCR 6289</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-201">D.C. Law 17-201</cite>, in subsec. (c), substituted “the holder of a wholesaler’s license that is not open to the public or to licensees” for “licensees”.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-165" eff="2018-10-30" path="§2|(f)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-02-21" doc="D.C. Law 23-50" eff="2020-02-21" path="§2|(b)|(2)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
