<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-711</num>
  <heading>Posting and carrying of licenses.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The holder of a license to manufacture, sell, or permit the consumption of alcoholic beverages shall post the license in the licensed establishment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a settlement agreement or security plan is a part of the license, the license shall be marked "settlement agreement" or "security plan" or both.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Upon request, a licensee shall make a copy of the settlement agreement and the security plan immediately accessible to an ABRA official or an officer with the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Upon request, a licensee shall make a copy of the settlement agreement immediately accessible to a member of the public. A licensee shall not be required to disclose its security plan to anyone other than an ABRA official or an officer of the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The licensee under a retail license, manufacturer's license, or a club license, shall post, in a conspicuous place on the front window or front door of the licensee’s premises, the correct name or names of the licensee or licensees and the class and number of the license in plain and legible lettering not less than one inch nor more than 1.25 inches in height.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A licensee under a temporary license shall have the license available for inspection by any member of the Board, employee of the Board, or member of the Metropolitan Police Department during the event for which the license was issued.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A licensee under a solicitor’s license shall, while soliciting orders, carry the license upon his or her person and shall exhibit the license, upon request, to any member of the Board, employee of the Board, or member of the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A licensee under a manager’s license shall, while managing a licensed establishment, carry the license upon his or her person and shall exhibit the license, upon request, to any member of the Board, employee of the Board, or member of the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-310" type="History">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-310, § 2(x), 60 DCR 3410</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(x) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-52, April 22, 2013,  60 DCR 6372, 20 DCSTAT 1388).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of (a), see § 2(x) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-597, January 14, 2013,  60 DCR 1001).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-310">D.C. Law 19-310</cite> substituted “settlement agreement” for “voluntary agreement” throughout (a).</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-04-07" doc="D.C. Law 21-260" eff="2017-04-07" path="§2|(f)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-02-21" doc="D.C. Law 23-50" eff="2020-02-21" path="§2|(b)|(4)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-02-21" doc="D.C. Law 23-50" eff="2020-02-21" path="§2|(b)|(4)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-54" path="§2|(d)|(1)" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="2020-02-21" eff="2020-02-21"><cite doc="D.C. Law 23-54" path="§2|(d)|(1)">Section 2(d)(1) of D.C. Law 23-54</cite> attempted to amend this section, however, the language it attempted to amend was previously changed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-50" path="§2|(b)|(4)">section 2(b)(4) of D.C. Law 23-50</cite>.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-02-21" doc="D.C. Law 23-54" eff="2020-02-21" path="§2|(d)|(1)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>While managing or working at a licensed establishment, the owner or licensed manager of a retailer's, manufacturer's, or wholesaler's license shall carry a valid identification document on his or her person and shall show the identification document, upon request, to an ABRA investigator or a member of the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
  </para>
</section>
