<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-801</num>
  <heading>Authority of the Board to enforce this title; enforcement responsibilities of ABRA investigators and Metropolitan Police Department.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board shall have the authority to enforce the provisions of this title with respect to licensees and with respect to any person not holding a license and selling alcohol in violation of the provisions of this title.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (c) of this section, ABRA investigators and the Metropolitan Police Department shall issue citations for civil violations of this title that are set forth in the schedule of civil penalties established under <cite path="§25-830">§ 25-830</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A citation for any violation for which the penalty includes the suspension of a license shall be issued under the direct authority of the Board as a result of an investigation carried out by ABRA investigators.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Prosecutions for misdemeanors under this title shall be prosecuted and initiated by information filed in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia. Prosecutions for felonies under this title shall be prosecuted by the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Violations committed by an unlicensed person selling alcohol in violation of the provisions of this title shall be forwarded by the Board to the Attorney General for the District of Columbia for prosecution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>ABRA investigators may request and check the identification of a patron inside of or attempting to enter an establishment with an alcohol license. ABRA investigators may seize evidence that substantiates a violation under this title, which shall include seizing alcoholic beverages sold to minors and fake identification documents used by minors.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>ABRA investigators may seize a liquor license from an establishment if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The liquor license has been suspended, revoked, or cancelled by the Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The business is no longer in existence; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The business has been closed by another District government agency.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-187" type="History">Sept. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-187, § 101(dd), 51 DCR 6525</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-270" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-270, § 2(f)(1), 62 DCR 1866</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-270">D.C. Law 20-270</cite> added (g).</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-02-21" doc="D.C. Law 23-52" eff="2020-02-21" path="§2|(f)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-229" path="§2|(e)" codified:display="Note" app="2020-02-27" eff="2020-02-27">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-229" path="§2|(e)">§ 2(e) of Games of Skill Consumer Protection Emergency Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Act 23-229, Feb. 27, 2020, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-02-27" doc="D.C. Act 23-229" eff="2020-02-27" path="§2|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 23-93" path="§2|(e)" codified:display="Note" app="2020-05-06" eff="2020-05-06">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-93" path="§2|(e)">§ 2(e) of Games of Skill Consumer Protection Temporary Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Law 23-93, May 6, 2020, 67 DCR 3522)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-93" eff="2020-05-06" path="§2|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-479" path="§3|(e)" codified:display="Note" app="2020-10-01" eff="2020-10-01">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-479" path="§3|(e)">§ 3(e) of Revised Game of Skill Machines Consumer Protections Emergency Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Act 23-479, Oct. 1, 2020, 67 DCR 13284)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-10-01" doc="D.C. Act 23-479" eff="2020-10-01" path="§3|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-16" path="§3|(e)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-02-26" eff="2021-02-26">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-16" path="§3|(e)">§ 3(e) of Revised Game of Skill Machines Consumer Protections Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-16, Feb. 26, 2021, 68 DCR 002559)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-02-26" doc="D.C. Act 24-16" eff="2021-02-26" path="§3|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 23-257" path="§3|(e)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2021-03-16">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-257" path="§3|(e)">§ 3(e) of Revised Game of Skill Machines Consumer Protections Temporary Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Law 23-257, Mar. 16, 2021, 67 DCR 13932)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-257" eff="2021-03-16" path="§3|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-280" eff="2021-04-27" path="§8|(e)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>An ABRA investigator may request and check the identification of a person who has played, is playing, or is attempting to play a game of skill machine. An ABRA investigator may seize fake identification used by a person under 18 years of age and may seize such records related to a game of skill machine as the investigator considers appropriate to investigate the playing of a game of skill machine by a person under 18 years of age.</text>
  </para>
</section>
