<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>ยง</prefix>
  <num>28-5303</num>
  <heading>Contracts required.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Before providing an immigration service to a client, an immigration service provider shall execute a written contract with the client that includes the following information:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A detailed explanation of the immigration service to be performed;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An itemization of all fees to be charged to the client;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Statements informing the client that the client:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Has the right to consult an attorney before signing the contract;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Has the right to obtain any document provided by the client at the client's request, even in the event of a fee dispute;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Has the right to rescind the contract within 72 hours after signing; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>May report complaints relating to an immigration service provider to the Office of the Attorney General's Consumer Protection Hotline;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>An accurate phone number for the Office of the Attorney General's Consumer Protection Hotline;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The statement, "I am not an attorney licensed to practice law in the District of Columbia and may not provide legal representation. I cannot provide representation to you before the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services, the Department of Homeland Security, the Executive Office for Immigration Review, the Department of Labor, the Department of State, or any other immigration authority."; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>The statement, "I cannot accept a fee for referring a client to another person for a service that I cannot or will not perform."</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The statements required by paragraph (1)(C)(iii) and (E) of this subsection shall be placed in immediate proximity to the space reserved in the contract for the client's signature and shall be in at least 12-point, boldface type.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The statement required by paragraph (1)(F) of this subsection shall be conspicuously placed in the contract in at least 12-point type.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The written contract required under this section shall be in English and in each language in which the immigration service provider provides or offers to provide an immigration service.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The immigration service provider shall provide a copy of the contract to the client immediately upon execution.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2017-04-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-280" eff="2017-04-22" path="ยง6|(c)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
