<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1807.65</num>
  <heading>Wheelchair-accessible vehicle tax credit administration.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A taxpayer that receives approval for a wheelchair-accessible vehicle tax credit shall promptly notify the Mayor if the wheelchair-accessible vehicle for which the taxpayer received a wheelchair-accessible vehicle tax credit is sold or not used to provide vehicle-for-hire services. The approval shall be void if the taxpayer that receives approval does not use the wheelchair-accessible vehicle for vehicle-for-hire services for one year after receiving approval.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall certify, to the Office of Tax and Revenue, the following information for each applicant that the Mayor has approved for a wheelchair-accessible tax credit pursuant to this subchapter:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The taxpayer's identification number;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The effective date of eligibility for the tax credit;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A statement that funds are sufficient within an approved budget and financial plan to allow the Office of Tax and Revenue to issue a refundable wheelchair-accessible vehicle tax credit to this taxpayer; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Such other information as the Office of Tax and Revenue shall require to administer the wheelchair-accessible tax credit provided by this subchapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Chief Financial Officer may audit the accounts of a taxpayer receiving a wheelchair-accessible vehicle tax credit up to 3 years following the issuance of any credit.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2017-04-07" doc="D.C. Law 21-242" eff="2017-04-07" path="ยง3|(c)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
