<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1812.11b</num>
  <heading>Tax-Payer Support for Afterschool Programs for At-Risk Students tax check-off.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There shall be provided on the District of Columbia individual income tax return a voluntary check-off that indicates that an individual may contribute a minimum donation or gift of $1 to afterschool programs for at-risk students. The contribution shall reduce any refund owed to the individual taxpayer or increase the tax owed by the individual taxpayer on the taxpayer’s tax return. The funds generated from the tax check-off shall be used in accordance with <cite path="§2-1555.04|(h)|(1)">§ 2-1555.04(h)(1)</cite> except that any cost incurred by the Mayor in collecting, processing, accounting, or disbursing the funds generated by the tax check-off shall be reimbursed to the Mayor from the funds generated by the tax check-off.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the funds generated by the tax check-off established by subsection (a) of this section shall be transferred to the Office of Out of School Time Grants and Youth Outcomes ("Office") pursuant to rules issued by the Mayor. The rules shall establish timetables and procedures for transfer. Check-off funds shall be transferred to the Office only after reimbursement of the costs described in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Funds collected by the Office of Tax and Revenue pursuant to this section before the [October 30, 2018] shall be transferred to the Office according to the procedures established pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection to be used in accordance with <cite path="§2-1555.04|(h)|(1)">§ 2-1555.04(h)(1)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, any unpaid District tax liability on an individual income tax return shall render any voluntary tax check-off election void. Any amount paid for the purpose of contributing to afterschool programs for at-risk students shall be used first to satisfy any unpaid tax liability in whole or in part.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If there is any amount that remains after satisfaction of the unpaid tax liability, the amount shall be transferred to the Office in accordance with the procedures established pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para placeholder="Repealed">
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>[Repealed].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-236" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-236, § 2(c), 46 DCR 660</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-226" type="History">Mar. 16, 2005, D.C. Law 15-226, § 202(b), 51 DCR 10539</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 808 of Child and Youth, Safety And Health Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-310, March 26, 2002,  49 DCR 3420).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-226">D.C. Law 15-226</cite>, in the section name line, substituted “Public Fund for Drug Prevention and Children at Risk tax” for “Tax”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-1812.11b.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§47-4001">§ 47-4001</cite> and <cite path="§47-4002">§ 47-4002</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Public Fund for Drug Prevention and Children at Risk, “tax check-off” defined, see <cite path="§47-4001">§ 47-4001</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Public Fund for Drug Prevention and Children at Risk, funding and allocation, see <cite path="§47-4002">§ 47-4002</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§7283|(b)|(2)" codified:display="Note" app="2018-07-30" eff="2018-07-30">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§7283|(b)|(2)">§ 7283(b)(2) of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-434, July 30, 2018, 65 DCR 8200)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="§7283|(b)|(2)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§7283|(b)|(2)" codified:display="Note" app="2018-10-03" eff="2018-10-03">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§7283|(b)|(2)">§ 7283(b)(2) of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-458, Oct. 3, 2018, 65 DCR 11212)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" eff="2018-10-03" path="§7283|(b)|(2)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§7283|(b)|(2)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§7283|(b)|(2)|(B)|(i)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§7283|(b)|(2)|(B)|(ii)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§7283|(b)|(2)|(B)|(iii)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§7283|(b)|(2)|(C)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§7283|(b)|(2)|(D)|(i)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§7283|(b)|(2)|(D)|(ii)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§7283|(b)|(2)|(E)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
