<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>47-1808.14</num>
  <heading>Retailer property tax relief credit.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Qualified retail owned location" means a building or part of a building in the District that during the taxable year is:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The primary place of the retail business of the qualified unincorporated business;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Owned by the qualified unincorporated business; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Classified, in whole or in part, as Class 2 Property, as defined in § 47-813 and has obtained a Certificate of Occupancy for commercial use.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Qualified retail rental location" means a building or part of a building in the District that during the taxable year is:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A retail establishment as defined in § 47-2001(m);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The primary place of the retail business of the qualified unincorporated business;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Leased by the qualified unincorporated business; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Classified, in whole or in part, as Class 2 Property, as defined in § 47-813 and has obtained a Certificate of Occupancy for commercial use.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Qualified unincorporated business" means a business that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is engaged in making sales at retail and files a sales tax return pursuant to Chapter 20 of this title reflecting those sales;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Has less than $2.5 million in federal gross receipts or sales; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Is current on all District tax filings and payments.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2017, a qualified unincorporated business may claim a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A tax credit equal to 10% of the total rent paid by the qualified unincorporated business for a qualified rental retail location during the taxable year not to exceed $5,000; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A tax credit equal to the total Class 2 real property taxes, pursuant to § 47-811, paid by the qualified unincorporated business for a qualified retail owned location during the taxable year not to exceed the lesser of the real property tax paid during the taxable year or $5,000.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The credit claimed under this section in any one taxable year may exceed the qualified unincorporated business's tax liability, including any minimum tax due under § 47-1807.02(b), under this chapter for that taxable year and shall be refundable to the qualified unincorporated business claiming the credit.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply if the qualified unincorporated business is exempt from or receives any tax credits towards its real property tax or the qualified rental retail location or qualified owned retail location is otherwise exempt from real property tax.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="§7252|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§7252|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2018-07-30" eff="2018-07-30">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§7252|(c)">§ 7252(c) of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-434, July 30, 2018, 65 DCR 8200)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
