<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>47-2202.03</num>
  <heading>Additional tax on gross receipts for transient lodgings or accommodations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A tax, separate from, and in addition to, the taxes imposed pursuant to <cite path="§47-2202">§§ 47-2202</cite> and <cite path="§47-2202.01">47-2202.01</cite> is imposed at the rate of 0.3% on the use, storage, or consumption of any room or rooms, lodgings, or accommodations furnished to a transient by any hotel, inn, tourist camp, tourist cabin, or any other place in which rooms, lodgings, or accommodations are regularly furnished to transients.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Vendors engaging in the business activities listed in this section and purchasers of the vendors' tangible personal property and services shall pay the tax at the rate of 0.3% of the gross receipts for the sale or charges for any room or rooms, lodgings, or accommodations furnished to a transient by any hotel, inn, tourist camp, tourist cabin, or any other place in which rooms, lodgings, or accommodations are regularly furnished to transients.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the occupancy of a room or rooms, lodgings, or accommodations is reserved, booked, or otherwise arranged for by a room remarketer, the tax imposed by this section shall be determined based on the net charges and additional charges by the room remarketer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The tax revenue receipted pursuant to this section shall be dedicated to the Washington Convention and Sports Authority, for transfer to Destination DC for the purposes of marketing and promoting the District of Columbia as a destination.  Any tax revenue dedicated pursuant to this subsection shall be in addition to the funds dedicated to Destination DC pursuant to <cite path="§10-1202.08a">§ 10-1202.08a</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-124" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2018-07-03" eff="2018-07-03" path="§301"><cite doc="D.C. Law 22-124" path="§301">Section 301 of D.C. Law 22-124</cite> provided that the changes made to this section by D.C. Law 22-124 shall apply as of October 1, 2017.
      </annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-07-03" doc="D.C. Law 22-124" eff="2018-07-03" path="§301" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-07-03" doc="D.C. Law 22-124" eff="2018-07-03" path="§108|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-124" path="§108|(b)" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2018-07-03" eff="2018-07-03">
          For temporary (90-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-163" path="§103|(b)">§ 103(b) of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2017, effective Oct. 23, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-163; 64 DCR 10778)</cite>.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-07-03" doc="D.C. Law 22-124" eff="2018-07-03" path="§108|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-124" path="§108|(b)" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2018-07-03" eff="2018-07-03">
          For temporary (90-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-213" path="§106|(b)">§ 106(b) of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2017, effective Dec. 20, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-213; 64 DCR 13422)</cite>.
        </annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-124" path="§108|(b)" type="Temporary Legislation" history="false" app="2018-07-03" eff="2018-07-03">
          For temporary (225-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-44" path="§106|(b)">§ 106(b) of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2017, effective Jan. 25, 2018 (D.C. Law 22-44; 64 DCR 12387)</cite>.
        </annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
