<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2853.133</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on September 15, 2021. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite path="§47-2853.133(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Certain representations prohibited.</heading>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 1002, 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2853.133.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-06-17" doc="D.C. Act 24-105" eff="2021-06-17" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-06-17" doc="D.C. Act 24-105" eff="2021-06-17" path="§2|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-06-17" doc="D.C. Act 24-105" eff="2021-06-17" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-105" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-06-17" eff="2021-06-17">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-105" path="§2|(b)">§ 2(b) of Engineering Licensure Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-105, June 17, 2021, 68 DCR 006461)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Unless licensed to practice engineering under this subchapter, no person shall engage directly or indirectly in the practice of engineering in the District or use the title “engineer”, “registered engineer”, “engineering design”, “professional engineer” or display or use any words or letters, figures, titles, signs, cards, advertisement or any other symbols or devices indicating or tending to indicate that the person is an engineer or is practicing engineering.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to persons acting as a consultant, officer, or employee of the government or an independent agency of the District of Columbia under the supervision of a professional engineer. The supervising professional engineer shall verify that any engineering work done by such persons is in compliance with all applicable laws and rules of the District.</text>
  </para>
</section>
