<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <num>47-2886.13</num>
  <heading>Fees; Professional Engineers’ Fund; expenses of Board; audit.</heading>
  <text>[Repealed].</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Sept. 19, 1950, 64 Stat. 864, ch. 953, § 13</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 1063(a), 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 302, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(69) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.11">§ 1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.14|(a)">§ 1-207.14(a)</cite>), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Board of Registration for Professional Engineers abolished: See note to <cite path="§47-2886.05">§ 47-2886.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> enacted this subchapter into law.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite>, in subsec. (d), substituted “For the purpose of any contemplated investigation or audit by the Inspector General,” for “It shall be the duty of the Office of the Inspector General of the District of Columbia to audit annually the accounts of the Board and make a report thereof to the Mayor. For the purpose of performance of such duty”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 2-1813.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-2313.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§1-301.74">§ 1-301.74</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Licensing and registration fees, see <cite path="§1-301.74">§ 1-301.74</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-04-15" doc="D.C. Law 21-272" eff="2017-04-15" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
