<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-369.02</num>
  <heading>Increases to appropriations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning in fiscal year 2009 and each fiscal year thereafter, consistent with revenue collections, the amount appropriated as District of Columbia Funds may be increased—</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>by an aggregate amount of not more than 25 percent, in the case of amounts proposed to be allocated as “Other-Type Funds” in the annual Proposed Budget and Financial Plan submitted to Congress by the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>by an aggregate amount of not more than 6 percent, in the case of any other amounts proposed to be allocated in such Proposed Budget and Financial Plan.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia may obligate and expend any increase in the amount of funds authorized under this section only in accordance with the following conditions:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia shall certify—</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>the increase in revenue; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>that the use of the amounts is not anticipated to have a negative impact on the long-term financial, fiscal, or economic health of the District.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The amounts shall be obligated and expended in accordance with laws enacted by the Council of the District of Columbia in support of each such obligation and expenditure, consistent with the requirements of this subchapter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The amounts may not be used to fund any agencies of the District government operating under court-ordered receivership.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The amounts may not be obligated or expended unless the Mayor has notified the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate not fewer than 30 days in advance of the obligation or expenditure.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 111-8" type="History">Mar. 11, 2009, 123 Stat. 699, Pub. L. 111-8, § 817</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 301, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 301 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> enacted this subchapter into law.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Budget Legislation">For temporary (90 days) FY 2013 Revised Budget Request adjustment, see § 2 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Revised Budget Request Emergency Adjustment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-74, May 23, 2013,  60 DCR 7592, 20 DCSTAT 1424).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2 of Housing Production Trust Fund Dedicated Tax Appropriations Authorization Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-66, May 13, 2011,  58 DCR 4250).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Budget Legislation">For temporary (225 days) FY 2013 Revised Budget Request adjustment, see § 2 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Revised Budget Request Temporary Adjustment Act of 2013 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-14">D.C. Law 20-14</cite>, September 19, 2013,  60 DCR 9554, 20 DCSTAT 1764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) increase in dedicated tax appropriations for the Housing Production Trust Fund, see § 2 of the Housing Production Trust Fund Dedicated Tax Appropriations Authorization Temporary Act of 2011 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 19-14">D.C. Law 19-14</cite>, Aug. 17, 2011,  58 DCR 5383).</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Act 21-153" path="§3" type="Budget Legislation" history="false" app="2015-10-06" eff="2015-10-06">
    For an temporary (90-day) adjustment to certain allocations requested in the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Request Act of 2014, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 21-153">the Fiscal Year 2015 and Fiscal Year 2016 Revised Budget Request Adjustment Emergency Act of 2015, D.C. Act 21-153, October 6, 2015, 62 DCR 13178</cite>.
  </annotation>
    <annotation app="2015-10-06" doc="D.C. Act 21-153" eff="2015-10-06" path="§3" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Act 21-478" path="§2" type="Budget Legislation" history="false" app="2016-07-21" eff="2016-07-21">
      For an emergency (90-day) adjustment to certain allocations in the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Request Act of 2015 pursuant to the Omnibus Appropriations Act, 2009, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 21-478">D.C. Act 21-478, July 21, 2016, 63 DCR 10188</cite>.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-07-21" doc="D.C. Act 21-478" eff="2016-07-21" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Act 22-96" path="§2" type="Budget Legislation" history="false" app="2017-07-10" eff="2017-07-10">
      For an emergency (90-day) adjustment to certain allocations in the Fiscal Year 2017 Local Budget Act of 2016, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-96">the Fiscal Year 2017 Revised Local Budget Emergency Adjustment Act of 2017, D.C. Act 22-96, July 10, 2017, 64 DCR 6560</cite>.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-07-10" doc="D.C. Act 22-96" eff="2017-07-10" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-15" path="§2" type="Budget Legislation" history="false" app="2017-08-25" eff="2017-08-25">
      For an temporary (225-day) adjustment to certain allocations requested in the Fiscal Year 2017 Local Budget Act of 2016, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-15">the Fiscal Year 2017 Revised Local Budget Temporary Adjustment Act of 2017, D.C. Law 22-15, August 25, 2017, 64 DCR 6568</cite>.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-08-25" doc="D.C. Law 22-15" eff="2017-08-25" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Act 22-394" path="§2" type="Budget Legislation" history="false" app="2018-07-02" eff="2018-07-02">
      For an emergency (90-day) adjustment to certain allocations requested in the Fiscal Year 2018 Local Budget Act of 2017, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-394">D.C. Act 22-394, July 2, 2018, 65 DCR 7151</cite>.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-07-02" doc="D.C. Act 22-394" eff="2018-07-02" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Act 22-457" path="§2" type="Budget Legislation" history="false" app="2018-10-03" eff="2018-10-03">
      For an emergency (90-day) adjustment to certain allocations requested in the Fiscal Year 2018 Local Budget Act of 2017, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-457">D.C. Act 22-457, October 3, 2018, 65 DCR 11204</cite>.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-457" eff="2018-10-03" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-169" path="§2" type="Budget Legislation" history="false" app="2018-10-30" eff="2018-10-30">
      For an temporary (225-day) adjustment to certain allocations requested in the Fiscal Year 2018 Local Budget Act of 2017, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-169">the Fiscal Year 2018 Revised Local Budget Temporary Adjustment Act of 2018, D.C. Law 22-169, September 5, 2018, 65 DCR 9528</cite>.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-169" eff="2018-10-30" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Act 23-75" path="§2" type="Budget Legislation" history="false" app="2019-07-08" eff="2019-07-08">
      For an emergency (90-day) adjustment to certain allocations requested in the Fiscal Year 2019 Local Budget Act of 2018, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-75">D.C. Act 23-75, July 8, 2019, 66 DCR 8078</cite>.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-07-08" doc="D.C. Act 23-75" eff="2019-07-08" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-10" path="§2" type="Budget Legislation" history="false" app="2019-08-24" eff="2019-08-24">
      For an temporary (225-day) adjustment to certain allocations requested in the Fiscal Year 2019 Local Budget Act of 2018, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-10">the Fiscal Year 2019 Revised Local Budget Temporary Adjustment Act of 2019, D.C. Law 23-10, August 24, 2019, 66 DCR 8069</cite>.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-08-24" doc="D.C. Law 23-10" eff="2019-08-24" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
