<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-355.04</num>
  <heading>Reporting requirements of agency heads and chief financial officers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>By October 1 of each year, an agency head and agency fiscal officer shall jointly submit to the Chief Financial Officer a monthly spending plan and a Schedule A, each by source of funds, based on the finally enacted annual budget. If an agency’s budget is changed after final enactment, a revised spending plan and a revised Schedule A, each by source of funds, must be submitted to the Chief Financial Officer within one month of final approval of the budget.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>By October 20 of each year, an agency head and agency fiscal officer shall jointly submit to the Chief Financial Officer a monthly spending plan for each capital project based on the finally enacted annual budget.  If a project's budget is changed after final enactment of the annual budget, the agency head and agency fiscal officer shall submit a revised project spending plan to the Chief Financial Officer within one month of final approval of the changes to the project's budget.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any revision to an agency’s approved operating budget or approved budget for a capital project during a fiscal year shall be reflected in a revised spending plan submitted to the Chief Financial Officer within one month of the approval of the revised budget.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-285" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-285, § 2, 50 DCR 940</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-293" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-293, § 2(c), 54 DCR 1083</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-293">D.C. Law 16-293</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “agency fiscal officer” for “agency chief financial officer” and “one month” for “15 days”; and in subsec. (b), substituted “one month” for “10 days”.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§8022|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-07-20" eff="2017-07-20">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§8022|(b)">§ 8022(b) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104, July 20, 2017, 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-07-20" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" eff="2017-07-20" path="§8022|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§8022|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-10-24" eff="2017-10-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§8022|(b)">§ 8022(b) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167, Oct. 24, 2017, 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-10-24" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" eff="2017-10-24" path="§8022|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§8022|(b)|(1)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§8022|(b)|(1)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§8022|(b)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§8022|(b)|(3)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
