<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-308.02</num>
  <heading>Relevant performance measures.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each relevant performance measure must be linked to spending on the relevant activity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each relevant performance measure shall represent a significant and realistic challenge for expected performance of the activity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each agency shall have at least one relevant performance measure for each activity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Relevant performance measures for each fiscal year, shall be established by the Mayor or his designee, after consultation with the agency’s stakeholders.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Beginning with fiscal year 2007, and for each subsequent fiscal year, all relevant performance measures for the prior fiscal year shall be provided to the Council in January along with the performance accountability reports submitted pursuant to <cite path="§1-614.13">§ 1-614.13</cite>, and beginning with fiscal year 2008, and for each following fiscal year, all relevant cost drivers shall be provided with the relevant performance measures in accordance with <cite path="§47-308.03|(e)">§ 47-308.03(e)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Beginning with fiscal year 2008, and for each subsequent fiscal year, the Mayor, or his designee, shall, in consultation with an agency’s stakeholders, establish relevant performance measures and utilize these performance measures in the agency’s strategic business plan.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 1006(c), 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 5(a), 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 1006(c) of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</cite>, in subsec. (e), substituted “<cite path="§1-614.13">§ 1-614.13</cite>” for “ <cite path="§1-614.13">§ 1-614.13</cite> ”.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-521" path="§202|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2020-12-07" eff="2020-12-07">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-521" path="§202|(b)">§ 202(b) of Racial Equity Achieves Results (REACH) Emergency Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Act 23-521, Dec. 7, 2020, 67 DCR 14433)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-07" doc="D.C. Act 23-521" eff="2020-12-07" path="§202|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-181" eff="2021-03-16" path="§202|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-44" path="§202|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-24" eff="2021-03-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-44" path="§202|(b)">§ 202(b) of Racial Equity Achieves Results (REACH) Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-44, Mar. 24, 2021, 68 DCR 003448)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-24" doc="D.C. Act 24-44" eff="2021-03-24" path="§202|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Beginning no later than Fiscal Year 2022, and for each subsequent fiscal year, the Mayor shall establish at least one relevant performance measure related to an agency's progress toward achieving racial equity.</text>
  </para>
</section>
