<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>47-4626</num>
  <heading>Randall School development project tax exemption.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Property, known as the Randall School development project, owned by the Trustees of the Corcoran Gallery of Art, a nonprofit corporation, shall be exempt from the tax imposed by<cite path="47|8"> Chapter 8 of this title</cite>, beginning October 1, 2008, for so long as the Trustees of the Corcoran Gallery of Art, or qualified successor, own the real property; provided, that the exemption provided by this section shall cease upon the commencement of the abatement provided under <cite path="§47-4626.01">§ 47-4626.01</cite>.  The exemption provided by this section shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other tax relief or assistance from any other source applicable to the Randall School development project.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Property" means the real property described as Lot 801, Square 643, Suffix S and any improvements on that real property.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Qualified successor" means an entity that develops, or transfers for development, the Property pursuant to <cite path="§47-4626.01">§ 47-4626.01</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 7171(b), 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 131, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 7170 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle O of title VII of the act may be cited as the “Randall School Development Project Tax Relief Act of 2009”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2 of Randall School Disposition Restatement Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-2, February 2, 2011,  58 DCR 1238).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Randall School Disposition Restatement Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-540, October 5, 2010,  57 DCR 9612).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 7171(b) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 7171(b) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Randall School Development Project Tax Exemption Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-23, February 25, 2009,  56 DCR 1954).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-6">D.C. Law 18-6</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-6">D.C. Law 18-6</cite> added a section to read as follows: “<cite path="§47-4620">§ 47-4620</cite>. Randall School development project tax exemption. The real property described as Lot 801, Square 643S, known as the Randall School development project, owned by the Trustees of the Corcoran Gallery of Art, a nonprofit corporation, shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 8 of this title, beginning October 1, 2008, and for so long as the Trustees of the Corcoran Gallery of Art own the real property; provided, that the exemption shall cease once a certificate of occupancy issues for any part of the Randall School development project. The exemption shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other tax relief or assistance from any other source applicable to the Randall School development project.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-06-04" doc="D.C. Law 23-6" eff="2019-06-04" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
