<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>47-5103</num>
  <heading>District of Columbia shared responsibility payments.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a taxpayer who is an applicable individual, or an applicable individual for whom the taxpayer is liable under subsection (b) of this section, fails to meet the requirement of <cite path="§47-5102|(a)">§ 47-5102(a)</cite> for one or more months, the taxpayer shall pay a District shared responsibility payment for tax years beginning after December 31, 2018. Subject to subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the District shared responsibility payment shall be the same as the Federal shared responsibility payment under section 5000A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (26 U.S.C. § 5000A) as in effect on December 15, 2017, and its implementing regulations as in effect on December 15, 2017.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a District shared responsibility payment is imposed for any month on an individual who is a dependent of a taxpayer during the taxable year, the taxpayer shall be liable for the shared responsibility payment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a District shared responsibility payment is imposed for any month on an individual who files a joint return for the taxable year, the individual and the spouse of the individual shall be jointly liable for the shared responsibility payment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The rules for determining the District shared responsibility payment shall be determined under <cite path="47|51">this chapter</cite> and rules issued or incorporated pursuant to <cite path="§47-5109">§ 47-5109</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The maximum amount of the District shared responsibility payment shall be determined using the District's average premium for bronze-level plans rather than the national average premium for bronze-level plans.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Authority shall annually publish on its website the District shared responsibility maximum payment amount before September 30 of the taxable year.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If a taxpayer is subject to both the District shared responsibility payment and the federal shared responsibility payment under section 5000A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (26 U.S.C. § 5000A) for a taxable year, the amount of the taxpayer's District shared responsibility payment shall be reduced, but not below zero, by the amount of the taxpayer's federal shared responsibility payment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="V|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="§5002|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§5002" codified:display="Note" app="2018-07-30" eff="2018-07-30">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§5002">§ 5002 of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-434, July 30, 2018, 65 DCR 8200)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="§5002" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" eff="2018-10-03" path="§5002|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§5002" codified:display="Note" app="2018-10-03" eff="2018-10-03">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§5002">§ 5002 of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-458, Oct. 3, 2018, 65 DCR 11212)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" eff="2018-10-03" path="§5002" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§5002|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
