<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <prefix>§</prefix>
  <num>47-5105</num>
  <heading>Reporting of health insurance coverage.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An applicable entity that provides minimum essential coverage to an individual during a calendar year shall submit a return at a time determined by the Chief Financial Officer, which shall include the information contained in a return described in section 6055 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (26 U.S.C. § 6055) and its implementing regulations, as that section and implementing regulations were in effect on December 15, 2017, and any such information required by the Chief Financial Officer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, an applicable entity required to submit a return pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall furnish to each individual whose name is required to be on the return a written statement showing the:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Name and address of the entity required to make the return;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The phone number of the information contact for such applicable entity or their delegee; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Information required regarding the individual.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The requirements of this subsection may be satisfied by a written statement provided to an individual that is consistent with the requirements of section 6055 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (26 U.S.C. § 6055) and its implementing regulations, as that section and implementing regulations were in effect on December 15, 2017.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In the case of coverage provided by an entity that is a governmental unit or an agency or instrumentality of a governmental unit, the officer or employee who enters into the agreement to provide such coverage shall be responsible for the returns required by this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An entity may contract with a third-party service provider, including an insurance carrier, to provide the returns required by this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="V|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="§5002|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§5002" codified:display="Note" app="2018-07-30" eff="2018-07-30">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§5002">§ 5002 of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-434, July 30, 2018, 65 DCR 8200)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="§5002" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" eff="2018-10-03" path="§5002|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§5002" codified:display="Note" app="2018-10-03" eff="2018-10-03">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§5002">§ 5002 of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-458, Oct. 3, 2018, 65 DCR 11212)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" eff="2018-10-03" path="§5002" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§5002|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
