<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-171.02</num>
  <heading>Public Recreational Space Master List.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>By June 1, 2019, DGS, with assistance from DPR and DCPS, shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Create the Public Recreational Space Master List, which shall include for each public recreational space:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The address of the public recreational space;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The District agency or agencies that own or maintain the public recreational space;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A list of the synthetic materials of which any improvements to the public recreational space are composed;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The date of installation or construction of any improvements to the public recreational space;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The natural life, according to manufacturer specifications or, where the manufacturer specifications are not available, industry standards, of any improvements to the public recreational space;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>The results of tests conducted pursuant to <cite path="§10-171.04">§ 10-171.04</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>The anticipated date of the next tests to be conducted pursuant to <cite path="§10-171.04">§ 10-171.04</cite> at the public recreational space; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Publish the Public Recreational Space Master List on the DGS website.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>DGS shall update the Public Recreational Space Master List within 30 days after the completion of a construction project or receipt of final results from testing at a public recreational space conducted pursuant to <cite path="§10-171.04">§ 10-171.04</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-293" eff="2019-04-11" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-293" eff="2019-04-11" path="§3" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
