<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-171.04</num>
  <heading>Annual testing.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Department of General Services ("DGS") shall conduct an annual g-max test on all fields and sport surfaces in a public recreational space with surfaces composed of synthetic materials, with tests occurring at least once in June or July of each year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 90 days after april 11, 2019, DGS shall establish protocols for the testing of a field or sport surface in a public recreational space as described in subsection (a) of this section. Under these protocols, a field or sport surface in a public recreational space shall be considered failing if the synthetic material would be prohibited under <cite path="ยง10-171.03|(b)|(1)|(B)">ยง 10-171.03(b)(1)(B)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>DGS shall conduct tests under subsection (a) of this section using the testing practices and equipment recommended by ASTM International. If ASTM International updates its recommendations for testing equipment, DGS shall procure the equipment within one year after the date when ASTM International publishes the update on its website.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>DGS shall conduct tests on a field or sport surface in a public recreational space with a surface composed of synthetic materials under subsection (a) in a manner that the tests will minimize interruption of DCPS, DPR, or permitted activities.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If any portion of a field or sport surface in a public recreational space, in whole or in part, fails a test conducted pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, DGS shall take remedial action within 24 hours after receiving the failing test results. If the remedial action is not completed within 24 hours after receiving the failing test result, DGS shall close the affected field or sport surface of the public recreational space to the public. DGS shall not reopen the field or sport surface until the remedial action is completed and the field or sport surface passes a subsequent g-max test.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Within 24 hours after DGS receives a test result resulting in the closure of a public recreational space under this section, DGS shall send the test results and a remediation plan to the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Chief Operating Officer of DCPS, if the public recreational space is owned or maintained by DCPS; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Director of DPR, if the public recreational space is owned or maintained by DPR.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Within 2 business days of receiving a test result resulting in the closure of a public recreational space under this section, DGS shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Publish notice on the DGS website; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Post a conspicuous sign at the public recreational space that clearly communicates information about the closure of the space, including:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The reason for the closure,</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The date and nature of any planned remediation efforts, and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Contact information for a DGS employee responsible for addressing questions about the remediation.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-293" eff="2019-04-11" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-293" eff="2019-04-11" path="ยง5" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
