<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-1202.16</num>
  <heading>Merit personnel system inapplicable.</heading>
  <text><cite path="1|6">Chapter 6 of Title 1</cite> shall not apply to employees of the Authority; except, that:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Subchapters V and XVII of <cite path="1|6">Chapter 6 of Title 1</cite> shall apply.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of <cite path="2|14|A">Unit A of Chapter 14 of Title 2</cite>, the Authority shall use a ranking system based on a scale of 100 points for all employment decisions for positions within the Authority.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>An individual who is a District resident at the time of application shall be awarded a 10-point hiring preference over a nonresident applicant; provided, that the individual claims the preference. This 10-point preference shall be in addition to any points awarded on the 100-point scale.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>At the time of appointment, an individual who claimed the 10-point residency preference shall agree, in writing, to maintain District residency for a period of 7 consecutive years from the effective date of appointment into the position for which the individual claimed the residency preference and shall provide proof of residency annually to the Authority for the first 7 years of employment.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>An individual who claimed the residency preference and who fails to maintain District residency for 7 consecutive years from the individual's effective date of appointment shall forfeit the individual's District government employment.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(v)</num>
        <text>Each applicant for a position covered by this subparagraph shall be informed in writing of the provisions of this subparagraph at the time of application.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>All persons hired after February 6, 2008, shall submit proof of residency upon employment in a manner determined by the Authority.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>By November 1 of each year and pursuant to <cite path="§1-515.06">§ 1-515.06</cite>, the Authority shall submit to the Mayor an annual report detailing, for the previous fiscal year, compliance with residency requirements.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-188" type="History" path="§216">Sept. 28, 1994, D.C. Law 10-188, § 216, 41 DCR 5333</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-22" type="History">Sept. 23, 1997, D.C. Law 12-22, § 2, 44 DCR 4168</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-108" type="History">Feb. 6, 2008, D.C. Law 17-108, § 210(b), 54 DCR 10993</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 223(e)(2), 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the Washington Convention Center Authority Collective Bargaining Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-78, June 4, 1997,  44 DCR 3351).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite>, in the lead-in language, substituted “except” for “provided”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-108">D.C. Law 17-108</cite> rewrote the section which had read as follows: “<cite path="1|6">Chapter 6 of Title 1</cite> shall not apply to employees of the Authority, except that subchapters V and XVII of <cite path="1|6">Chapter 6 of Title 1</cite>, shall apply.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 9-817.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-05-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-315" eff="2019-05-23" path="§9" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
