<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-551.07d</num>
  <heading>Renewable energy generation at District-owned properties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to the availability of funding, the Department shall initiate or expand renewable energy generation at every District-owned property under the control of the Mayor where doing so is found feasible by the analysis required by <cite path="§10-551.05|(c-1)">§ 10-551.05(c-1)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding <cite path="2|2|IX-A">subchapter IX-A of Chapter 2 of Title 2</cite>, or any other provision of District law or regulation, any contract entered into to implement this section, absent a waiver pursuant to <cite path="§2-218.51">§ 2-218.51</cite>, shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be awarded to a qualified small business enterprise; provided, that if the Department determines that there are not at least 2 qualified small business enterprises that can provide the services or goods that are the subject of the contract, the Department may use any qualified certified business enterprise; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Require that at least 50% of the dollar volume of the contract shall be subcontracted to qualified small business enterprises; provided, that if there are insufficient qualified small business enterprises to meet the requirement and best efforts are made to ensure that qualified small business enterprises are significant participants in the overall subcontracting work, then the subcontracting requirement may be satisfied by subcontracting 50% of the dollar volume to any qualified certified business enterprise.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History" path="§1028d">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 1028d</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="§1042|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
