<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-551.07c</num>
  <heading>Prevention of lead in drinking water at recreation facilities.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>"Drinking water source" means a source of water from which a person can reasonably be expected to consume or cook with the water originating from the source.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>"Drinking water source" shall not include a source of water for which the Department of General Services posts a conspicuous sign pursuant to subsection (b)(3) of this section.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Recreation facility" means a Department of Parks and Recreation ("DPR") public facility regularly used by children.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Remediation steps" means, at a minimum, actions to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Decrease the elevated lead concentration in a drinking water source to 5 parts per billion or less; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Preclude people from consuming or cooking with water from a drinking water source.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department of General Services ("Department") shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Locate all drinking water sources at each recreation facility and install a barcode on each of the drinking water sources;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Install a filter that reduces lead in drinking water on each drinking water source in each recreation facility and maintain the filters, at a minimum, in a manner consistent with the manufacturer's recommendations. Filters or all of the filter's component parts shall be certified for lead reduction to the National Sanitation Foundation ("NSF")/American National Standards Institute ("ANSI") Standard 53 for Health Effects or NSF/ANSI Standard 61 for Health Effects;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Post a conspicuous sign near each water source at recreation facilities that is not a drinking water source, which includes an image that clearly communicates that water from the water source should not be used for cooking, where applicable, or consumed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Test all drinking water sources at each recreation facility for lead annually;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>If a test conducted pursuant to paragraph (4) of this subsection shows a lead concentration over 5 parts per billion:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Shut off the drinking water source as soon as possible but no later than 24 hours after receiving the test result and keep the drinking water source shut off until a subsequent test shows that the lead concentration level is not over 5 parts per billion;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Determine, in writing, which remediation steps should be implemented to address the elevated lead concentration level;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Send the test results and remediation steps to the Director of DPR within 5 business days of receiving the test result;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Update the list described in paragraph (6) of this subsection within 5 business days of receiving the test result to reflect the test result and remediation steps; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Notify the Director of DPR and update the list described in paragraph (6) of this subsection within 5 business days of completion of the remediation steps required by subparagraph (B) of this paragraph; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Publish on the Department's website a list of drinking water sources in each recreation facility that describes, for each drinking water source:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The date and results of the most recent lead test performed;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The date the current filter was installed;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The date when the filter will next be replaced;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The barcode identification number; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Any remediation steps that will be or have been taken.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Within 120 days of September 23, 2017, the Mayor, pursuant to <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>, shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section is intended to, or does, create a private right of action against any person or entity based upon compliance or noncompliance with its provisions. No person or entity may assert any claim or right as a beneficiary or protected class under this section in any civil, criminal, or administrative action against the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-551.07c" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§10-551.07c">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="">D.C. Law 22-21</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="§11">§ 11 of D.C. Law 22-21</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 22-21</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History" path="§1028c">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 1028c</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-09-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-21" eff="2017-09-23" path="§4" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="§4" codified:display="Note" app="2017-09-23" eff="2017-09-23">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="">D.C. Law 22-21</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="§11">§ 11 of D.C. Law 22-21</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 22-21</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-09-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-21" eff="2017-09-23" path="§4" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="§9" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="2017-09-23" eff="2017-09-23"><cite doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="§9">Section 9 of D.C. Law 22-21</cite> provided that within one year after September 23, 2017, the Mayor shall host 4 community meetings open to the public on the implementation of D.C. Law 22-21 and notify the public about each meeting on the Department of General Services website at least one month before the meeting is held.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-09-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-21" eff="2017-09-23" path="§9" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-168" path="§7019|(a)" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2018-10-30" eff="2018-10-30"><cite doc="D.C. Law 22-168" path="§7019">Section 7019 of D.C. Law 22-168</cite> amendeded <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="§11">section 11 of D.C. Law 22-21</cite> removing the applicability restriction impacting this section. Therefore the amendments made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-21">D.C. Law 22-21</cite> have been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§7019|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
