<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-801.02</num>
  <heading>Email notifications regarding the surplus and disposition of real property.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 180 days after December 13, 2017, the Department of General Services ("DGS"), in coordination with the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development ("DMPED"), shall allow individuals to sign up, on the DGS website, to receive email notifications, pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, relating to the surplus and disposition of real property, within Advisory Neighborhood Commissions ("ANC") selected by the individual.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>DGS shall send an email notification to individuals who sign up under subsection (a) of this section within 2 days after the following events:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor publishes notice of a surplus hearing pursuant to <cite path="§10-801|(a-1)|(4)">§ 10-801(a-1)(4)</cite>, which shall describe:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The date, time, and location of the hearing; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>How a person who cannot attend the hearing can comment on the finding that the real property is no longer required for public purposes;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The introduction of a proposed resolution pursuant to <cite path="§10-801|(a-1)">§ 10-801(a-1)</cite>, which shall include a link to the website on the Council's Legislative Information Management System about the proposed resolution;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Council publishes notice of a hearing on a proposed resolution submitted by the Mayor pursuant to <cite path="§10-801|(a-1)">§ 10-801(a-1)</cite>, which shall describe:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The date, time, and location of the hearing; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>How a person who cannot attend the hearing can comment on the finding that the real property is no longer required for public purposes;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Council's approval, disapproval, or passive disapproval of a proposed resolution pursuant to<cite path="§10-801|(a-1)|(3)">§ 10-801(a-1)(3)</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Mayor publishes notice of a public hearing pursuant to <cite path="§10-801|(b-2)">§ 10-801(b-2)</cite> on a proposed disposition of District-owned property, which shall describe:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The date, time, and location of the hearing; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>How a person who cannot attend the hearing can comment on the finding that the real property is no longer required for public purposes;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The introduction of a proposed resolution pursuant to <cite path="§10-801|(b)">§ 10-801(b)</cite>, which shall include a link to the website on the Council's Legislative Information Management System about the proposed resolution;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The Council publishes notice of a hearing on a proposed resolution submitted by the Mayor pursuant to <cite path="§10-801|(b)">§ 10-801(b)</cite>, which shall describe:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The date, time, and location of the hearing; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>How a person who cannot attend the hearing can comment on the finding that the real property is no longer required for public purposes;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The Council's approval or disapproval, in whole or in part, or passive disapproval of a proposed resolution pursuant to <cite path="§10-801|(c)">§ 10-801(c)</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The introduction of a resolution seeking additional time for the disposition of a property pursuant to <cite path="§10-801|(d)">§ 10-801(d)</cite>, which shall include a link to the website on the Council's Legislative Information Management System about the resolution; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The Council's approval, disapproval, or passive disapproval of a resolution seeking additional time for the disposition of a property pursuant to <cite path="§10-801|(d)">§ 10-801(d)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All e-mail notifications issued pursuant to this section shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The address of the District-owned property that is the subject of the event listed in subsection (b) of this section; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The contact information for the DMPED Project Manager managing the District-owned property that is the subject of the event listed in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§2162">Aug. 5, 1939, 53 Stat. 1211, ch. 449, § 1b</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§2162" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§2162" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2017-12-13" eff="2017-12-13">
          For temporary (90-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§2162">§ 2162 of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017, effective July 20, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104; 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§2162" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-33" path="§2162" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2017-12-13" eff="2017-12-13">
          For temporary (90-day) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§2162">§ 2162 of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017, effective October 24, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167; 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.
        </annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
