<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-1853.06</num>
  <heading>Priorities.</heading>
  <text>In awarding grants under <cite path="§38-1853.04|(a)">§ 38-1853.04(a)</cite>, the Secretary shall give priority to applications from eligible entities that will most effectively—</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>in awarding scholarships under <cite path="§38-1853.07|(a)">§ 38-1853.07(a)</cite>, give priority to—</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>eligible students who, in the school year preceding the school year for which the eligible students are seeking a scholarship, attended an elementary school or secondary school identified as one of the lowest-performing schools under the District of Columbia's accountability system; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>students whose household includes a sibling or other child who is already participating in the program of the eligible entity under <cite path="38|18N">this chapter</cite>, regardless of whether such students have, in the past, been assigned as members of a control study group for the purposes of an evaluation under <cite path="§38-1853.09|(a)">§ 38-1853.09(a)</cite> or whether such students have, in the past, attended a private school;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>target resources to students and families that lack the financial resources to take advantage of available educational options; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>provide students and families with the widest range of educational options.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 112-10" type="History" path="§3006">Apr. 15, 2011, 125 Stat. 202, Pub. L. 112-10, Div. C, § 3006</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 114-95" type="History">Dec. 10, 2015, 129 Stat. 1802, Pub. L. 114-95, § 9215(ppp)(2)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Section 9215(ppp)(2) of Public Law 114-95 substituted “implementing comprehensive support and improvement activities or targeted support and improvement activities under section 1111(d) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965” for “identified for improvement, corrective action, or restructuring under section 1116 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 6316)” in (1)(A).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§38-1853.05">§ 38-1853.05</cite> and <cite path="§38-1853.09">§ 38-1853.09</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-05-05" doc="Pub. L. 115-31" eff="2017-05-05" path="§906|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-05-05" doc="Pub. L. 115-31" eff="2017-05-05" path="§906|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-05-05" doc="Pub. L. 115-31" eff="2017-05-05" path="§906|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 115-31" path="§901|(a)|(b)" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="2017-05-05" eff="2017-05-05">
           Section 901(b) of Div. E, Title IX, of Public Law 115-31 provided that: "Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this title an amendment is expressed in terms of an amendment to or repeal of a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to that section or other provision of the Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Act (division C of Public Law 112-10; sec. 38-1853.01 et seq., D.C. Official Code)."
          </annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-05-05" doc="Pub. L. 115-31" eff="2017-05-05" path="§901|(a)|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
