<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-1831.01</num>
  <heading>Utilization of space in District of Columbia public schools by public charter schools.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Public Schools system may allow existing public charter schools that are chartered pursuant to <cite path="38|18">Chapter 18 of this title</cite>,  to utilize space in DCPS facilities, for a period not greater than 15 years, where such facilities are currently or are projected to be underutilized.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para codify:path="(1)">
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>As payment for the space allocation, the public charter school shall pay to DCPS an amount agreeable to the charter school and DCPS.</text>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="(2)">
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The amount of payment shall be agreed upon before relocation of any public charter school into a DCPS facility.</text>
    </para>
    <para placeholder="Repealed">
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may promulgate rules to implement the provision of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History" path="§3422">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 3422, 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§4012|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§4012|(b)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§4012|(b)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§4012|(c)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§4012|(d)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§4012|(e)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is established as a special fund the DCPS School Facility Colocation Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by DCPS in accordance with paragraph (3) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>All payments received from public charter schools under this section shall be deposited in the Fund.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Money in the Fund shall be used for the following purposes:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>To fund additional school programming, supplemental staff, special initiatives, and other activities and programs at DCPS schools in which charter schools are colocated; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For maintenance of, or improvements to, DCPS schools in which charter schools are colocated.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The money deposited into the Fund but not expended in a fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Any funds received by a DCPS school pursuant to this section shall be supplemental to any funds budgeted for the school from the Uniform Per Student Funding Formula or other fund source. A school's school-based budget shall not be reduced based on funds received pursuant to this section.</text>
  </para>
</section>
