<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-1853.03</num>
  <heading>Purpose.</heading>
  <text>The purpose of this chapter is to provide low-income parents residing in the District of Columbia, particularly parents of students who attend an elementary school or secondary school identified as one of the lowest-performing schools under the District of Columbia's accountability system, with expanded opportunities for enrolling their children in other schools in the District of Columbia, at least until the public schools in the District of Columbia have adequately addressed shortfalls in health, safety, and security, and the students in the District of Columbia public schools are testing in mathematics and reading at or above the national average.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 112-10" type="History" path="§3003">Apr. 15, 2011, 125 Stat. 200, Pub. L. 112-10, Div. C, § 3003</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 114-95" type="History">Dec. 10, 2015, 129 Stat. 1802, Pub. L. 114-95, § 9215(ppp)(1)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">Section 9215(ppp)(1) of Public Law 114-95 substituted “implementing comprehensive support and improvement activities or targeted support and improvement activities under section 1111(d) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965” for “identified for improvement, corrective action, or restructuring under section 1116 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 6316).”</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 115-31" path="§901|(a)|(b)" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="2017-05-05" eff="2017-05-05">
           Section 901(b) of Div. E, Title IX, of Public Law 115-31 provided that: "Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this title an amendment is expressed in terms of an amendment to or repeal of a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to that section or other provision of the Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Act (division C of Public Law 112-10; sec. 38-1853.01 et seq., D.C. Official Code)."
          </annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-05-05" doc="Pub. L. 115-31" eff="2017-05-05" path="§901|(a)|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 115-31" path="§901|(a)|(b)" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="2017-05-05" eff="2017-05-05">
           Section 902 of Div. E, Title IX, of Public Law 115-31 provided that: "Section 817 of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (Public Law 114-113) is repealed, and any provision of law amended or repealed by such section is restored or revived as if such section had not been enacted into law."
          </annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-05-05" doc="Pub. L. 115-31" eff="2017-05-05" path="§903" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 115-31" path="§913" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="2017-05-05" eff="2017-05-05">
        Section 3014 of Div. E, Title IX, of Public Law 115-31 provided that:        
        Except as otherwise provided, the amendments made by this title   
        shall apply with respect to school year 2018-2019 and each succeeding school year.
      </annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-05-05" doc="Pub. L. 115-31" eff="2017-05-05" path="§913" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
