<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-2252</num>
  <text>
                *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
                </text>
  <heading>"Grow Your Own" Teacher Preparation Support Program establishment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>OSSE shall establish, in collaboration with UDC, District university grantees, and the District's LEAs, a dual pathway "Grow Your Own" Teacher Preparation Support Program for the purpose of educating, training, and providing financial support to public high school dual enrollment students, public high school graduates, and paraprofessionals to become licensed teachers at DCPS schools or certified teachers at District public charter schools.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Through UDC and District university grantees, the Program shall provide:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Education and training to District residents that will lead to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The successful completion of coursework for a baccalaureate or a master's degree in education or teaching needed to become a teacher licensed by OSSE or a certified teacher at a District public charter school;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Passage of examinations required by OSSE or an LEA to become a teacher licensed by OSSE or a certified teacher at a District public charter school; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Hiring by an LEA as a licensed or certified teacher.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Two pathways to teacher licensure or certification, which shall be:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The baccalaureate degree pathway, which shall be available to District residents who:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Enroll as or are public high school dual enrollment students that intend to continue to pursue a baccalaureate or master's degree in education or teaching to become a teacher licensed by OSSE or a certified teacher at a District public charter school; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Are public high school graduates who are pursuing a baccalaureate or master's degree in education or teaching to become a teacher licensed by OSSE or a certified teacher at a District public charter school; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The paraprofessional pathway, which shall be available to District residents who are paraprofessionals currently employed by an LEA and who need to complete additional coursework or obtain a baccalaureate or master's degree in education or teaching to become a teacher licensed by OSSE or a certified teacher at a District public charter school; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Financial assistance to Program participants for payment of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Tuition and fees at UDC or a District university grantee, to the extent charged;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Academic costs, including books and supplies; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Testing fees associated with examinations required by OSSE or an LEA to become a licensed or certified teacher.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>UDC shall select individuals to enroll or who are enrolled in UDC to participate in the Program, consistent with the eligibility criteria established pursuant to section 4196.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>District university grantees shall select individuals to enroll or who are enrolled in their institutions to participate in the Program consistent with the eligibility criteria established pursuant to section 4196 and their grant agreements with OSSE.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>OSSE and UDC shall coordinate to ensure that Program participants do not receive Program financial assistance from more than one post-secondary institution at the same time.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2239" expire="2021-08-23" codified:display="Note">For temporary (90 days) creation of § 38-2252, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4193">§ 4193 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2252" applicability="2021-08-23" delay="50" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§38-2252">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4193">§ 4193 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2252" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§38-2252">
    <text>
                *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
                </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="IV" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§4193" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§4193" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4193" codified:display="Note" app="2021-08-23" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4193">§ 4193 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
