<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-2973.05</num>
  <heading>Audit of capital improvement projects.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No later than September 30, 2020, and every 3 years thereafter until the completion of all school modernization projects in the Capital Improvement Plan, the District of Columbia Auditor shall prepare a report to the public on the use of the capital funds by the District of Columbia Public Schools during the preceding fiscal years. The report shall include a school- and project-specific audit of all expenditures for school facility capital improvements, maintenance, repairs, and operating costs, and an assessment of whether the District has met the process, quality, schedule, and cost objectives of the Capital Improvement Plan and Budget.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No later than September 30, 2017, and each year thereafter until the completion of all school modernization projects in the Capital Improvement Plan, except in a year where a report is issued pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the District of Columbia Auditor shall examine not less than a sample of capital projects related to school modernizations and shall determine whether the District has met the process, quality, schedule and cost objectives of sampled projects, and provide a report to the Council and the public on the findings.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-123" type="History" path="§205">June 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-123, § 205, 53 DCR 2843</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 21-403" path="§11" codified:display="Note" app="2016-05-21" eff="2016-05-21">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 21-403" path="§11">§ 11 of Repeal of Outdated and Unnecessary Audit Mandates Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-403, May 21, 2016, 63 DCR 7925)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-05-21" doc="D.C. Act 21-403" eff="2016-05-21" path="§11" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-08-17" doc="D.C. Law 21-143" eff="2016-08-17" path="§12" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
