<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-2255</num>
  <text>
                *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
                </text>
  <heading>Conditions of Program eligibility and participation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To be eligible for Program participation through the baccalaureate degree pathway described in <cite path="§38-2252|(b)|(2)|(A)">§ 38-2252(b)(2)(A)</cite>, an individual shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Meet the relevant enrollment requirements for UDC or the District university grantee in which the individual enrolls;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be a resident of the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Become or be a dual enrollment student; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Be a graduate of a public high school; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Be enrolled in UDC or a District university grantee with an intent to pursue a baccalaureate or master's degree in education or teaching; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>In exchange for Program financial assistance and professional support, commit to teaching at an LEA for a minimum of 3 years after receiving a baccalaureate or master's degree in education or teaching and earning the appropriate licensure or certification needed to teach at an LEA.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To be eligible for Program participation through the paraprofessional degree pathway described in <cite path="§38-2252|(b)|(2)|(B)">§ 38-2252(b)(2)(B)</cite>, an individual shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Meet the relevant enrollment requirements for UDC or District university grantee in which the individual enrolls;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be a resident of the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be currently employed by an LEA as a paraprofessional;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Enroll in a UDC or District university grantee to complete coursework or with the intent to pursue a baccalaureate or master's degree in education or teaching necessary to be a teacher licensed by OSSE or a certified teacher at a public charter school; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>In exchange for Program financial assistance and support, commit to teaching at an LEA for a minimum of 3 years after completing the necessary coursework or receiving a baccalaureate or master's degree in education or teaching and earning the appropriate licensure or certification needed to teach at an LEA.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>To maintain eligibility for Program assistance, a Program participant shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Maintain the requisite cumulative grade point average to maintain satisfactory academic progress, as determined by UDC or the District university grantee; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If participating in the Program through the baccalaureate degree pathway described in <cite path="§38-2252|(b)|(2)|(A)">§ 38-2252(b)(2)(A)</cite>, be consecutively enrolled as a full-time student in the Program at UDC or a District university grantee to pursue a baccalaureate or master's degree in education or teaching;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Remain a District resident throughout participation in the Program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If pursuing teacher licensure or certification through the paraprofessional pathway described in <cite path="§38-2252|(b)|(2)|(B)">§ 38-2252(b)(2)(B)</cite>, remain employed by an LEA as a paraprofessional while participating in the Program; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Meet any other requirement determined by UDC or OSSE to be necessary or appropriate for Program participation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2239" expire="2021-08-23" codified:display="Note">For temporary (90 days) creation of § 38-2255, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4196">§ 4196 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2255" applicability="2021-08-23" delay="50" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§38-2255">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4196">§ 4196 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2255" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§38-2255">
    <text>
                *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
                </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="IV" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§4196" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§4196" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4196" codified:display="Note" app="2021-08-23" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§4196">§ 4196 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
