<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-236.04</num>
  <heading>Limitations on exclusion as a disciplinary action.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise required by federal or District law:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Beginning in school year 2019-2020, for students in grades kindergarten through 5, and school year 2020-2021 for students in grades 6 through 8, no student may be subject to an out-of-school suspension or disciplinary unenrollment, unless a school administrator determines, consistent with school policy, that the student has willfully caused, attempted to cause, or threatened to cause bodily injury or emotional distress to another person, including behavior that happens off school grounds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Beginning in school year 2020-2021, no student in grades 9 through 12, except a student over 18 years of age at a school where more than 1/2 of the students are over 18 years of age, may be subject to an out-of-school suspension or disciplinary unenrollment for:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Violating local education agency or school dress code or uniform rules;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Willful defiance; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Behavior that happens off school grounds and not as part of a school-sponsored activity, unless the student has willfully caused, attempted to cause, or threatened to cause bodily injury or emotional distress to another person.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No student, except a student over 18 years of age at a school where more than 1/2 of the students are over 18 years of age, may be subject to an out-of-school suspension for longer than:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Five consecutive school days for any individual incident in grades kindergarten through 5;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Ten consecutive school days for any individual incident in grades 6 through 12; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Twenty cumulative school days during an academic year regardless of grade, unless:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The head of a local education agency provides a written justification to the student and parent describing why exceeding the 20-day limit is a more appropriate disciplinary action than alternative responses; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The student's conduct necessitated an emergency removal, and the head of the local education agency provides a written justification for the emergency removal to the student and parent.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No student, except a student over 18 years of age at a school where more than 1/2 of the students are over 18 years of age, may be subject to an out-of-school suspension or disciplinary unenrollment for an unexcused absence or a late arrival to school; provided, that a student may be unenrolled from a local education agency if the student has accumulated 20 or more consecutive full-school-day unexcused absences.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No student subject to a suspension may be denied the right to continue to access and complete appropriate academic work or to earn credit toward promotion or graduation during a suspension.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The return of a student to school upon conclusion of an out-of-school suspension shall not be made contingent on a parent accompanying the student, attending a conference, or otherwise being present at the school.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding whether a school or local education agency states the reasoning for the removal from school or prohibition from returning to school, no student may be removed from school or prohibited from returning to school for disciplinary reasons, unless the student is subject to an out-of-school suspension or disciplinary unenrollment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>For purposes of due process, a suspension of 6 school days or more shall be considered a long-term suspension.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-236.04" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§38-236.04">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-157" path="">D.C. Law 22-157</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-157" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 22-157</cite> provided that the creation of subsections (a) and (b) of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-157" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of D.C. Law 22-157</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-236.04" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§38-236.04">
          For temporary (90-day) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§4062|(a)">§ 4062(a) of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2018, effective July 30, 2018 (D.C. Act 22-434; 65 DCR 8200)</cite>.
					</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-17" type="History" path="§204">September 19, 2013, D.C. Law 20-17, § 204</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-08-25" doc="D.C. Law 22-157" eff="2018-08-25" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-08-25" doc="D.C. Law 22-157" eff="2018-08-25" path="§2|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 22-157" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2018-08-25" eff="2018-08-25">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-157" path="">D.C. Law 22-157</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-157" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 22-157</cite> provided that the creation of subsections (a) and (b) of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-157" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of D.C. Law 22-157</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-08-25" doc="D.C. Law 22-157" eff="2018-08-25" path="§2|(c)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-157" path="§2|(c)" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" display-template="" app="2018-08-25" eff="2018-08-25">
          For temporary (90-day) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§4062|(a)">§ 4062(a) of the Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2018, effective July 30, 2018 (D.C. Act 22-434; 65 DCR 8200)</cite>.
					</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-08-25" doc="D.C. Law 22-157" eff="2018-08-25" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§4062|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§4062|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-16" path="§7151" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-09-11">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-157">D.C. Law 22-157</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-16" path="§7151">§ 7151 of D.C. Law 23-16</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-157" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 22-157</cite>. Therefore the creation of subsections (a) and (b) of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-157">D.C. Law 22-157</cite> has been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§7151" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
