<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-356</num>
  <heading>Complaint resolution services.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Office of Ombudsman shall provide complaint resolution services, which shall be available to current and prospective public school students and their parents or guardians.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Participation in complaint resolution services provided by the Office of Ombudsman shall be voluntary.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Before submitting a complaint to the Office of Ombudsman, the complainant shall make reasonable efforts to resolve the issue at the school level.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Complainants may submit complaints by phone, in writing, or electronically.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, the Office of Ombudsman shall review and investigate each complaint and shall do one or more of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Resolve the complaint;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Refer the complainant to another agency or department;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Require the complainant to submit documentation to support the complaint;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Provide an opportunity for the complainant to meet with the subject of the complaint;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Conduct mediation proceedings;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Dismiss the complaint as unfounded; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Take any other action determined necessary and appropriate by the Ombudsman.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-9" type="History" path="§606a">June 12, 2007, D.C. Law 17-9, § 606a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-76" type="History">as added Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-76, § 102(e), 61 DCR 39</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-76">D.C. Law 20-76</cite> added this section.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-04-07" doc="D.C. Law 21-252" eff="2017-04-07" path="§3|(e)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-04-07" doc="D.C. Law 21-252" eff="2017-04-07" path="§3|(e)|(2)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Ombudsman may refrain from investigating a complaint if the Ombudsman reasonably believes one or more of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>It is plain from the face of the complaint that an adequate remedy is presently available, such that investigation is unwarranted;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The complaint relates to a matter that is outside the jurisdiction of the Ombudsman;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The complaint relates to an act of which the complainant has had knowledge for an unreasonable length of time before the complaint was submitted;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The complainant does not have a sufficient personal interest in the subject matter of the complaint;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Investigation of the complaint would not facilitate an action authorized pursuant to subsection (e) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The complaint is made in bad faith; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The resources of the Ombudsman are insufficient for adequate investigation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
</section>
