<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-435</num>
  <heading>Community Use of School Facilities Task Force.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Community Use of School Facilities Task Force ("Task Force"). The Task Force shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Identify the frequency and timing of community use;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Identify existing barriers to community use;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Identify, in coordination with the Department of General Services and the Office of the Chief Financial Officer, how any changes to the District's permitting processes as it relates to tax-exempt bond financed property might jeopardize the tax-exempt status of the District's bonds; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Develop recommendations to increase community use, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>When and for how long school facilities should be reserved for community use;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Permissible types of community use;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>How to address existing barriers to community use; provided, that the Task Force shall not recommend shifting liability away from the District government for loss or injury resulting from community use;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A list of any regulatory or statutory changes necessary to increase community use; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>A list of all District property financed by tax-exempt bonds, an explanation of how proposed permitted uses of each property could violate Internal Revenue Service rules regarding tax-exempt bond financed property, and recommendations for how the Department of General Services and DCPS can ensure that the Department of General Services does not grant permits for proposed uses that could jeopardize the tax-exempt status of the District's bonds.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall consult with organizations and individuals with experience in the fields of obesity, community health, personal or group liability insurance, and tort liability.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall be composed of the following members:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Department of General Services, or the Director's designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Chancellor of District of Columbia Public Schools, or the Chancellor's designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Department of Parks and Recreation, or the Director's designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Executive Director of the Office on Aging, or the Executive Director's designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer, or the Chief Financial Officer's designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Five community representatives appointed by the Mayor as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Three representatives from parent-teacher associations or organizations;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>One representative from a community-based recreational program serving high-need communities; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>One representative from a District organization that provides recreational programming for children</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>By October 1, 2019, the Task Force shall transmit a report to the Council that details the Task Force's findings and recommendations described in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-02-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-210" eff="2019-02-22" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-02-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-210" eff="2019-02-22" path="ยง6" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
