<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-410</num>
  <heading>Use of a public school building by a civic association.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a civic association may enter into a use agreement to use a District of Columbia Public Schools school building for a regularly scheduled meeting at no charge; provided, that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The use of the school building does not impose a cost on the District, except for the costs of custodial and security services; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A civic association shall not enter into a use agreement to use a District of Columbia Public Schools school building for more than 12 regularly scheduled meetings in a calendar year.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department of General Services shall reimburse a civic association for the costs of obtaining the liability insurance required under its use agreement if that insurance is purchased through a District-approved insurance partnership program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "civic association" means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A nonprofit association, corporation, or other organization that is:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Comprised primarily of residents of the community within which the school to be used is located;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Operated for the promotion of social welfare and general neighborhood improvement and enhancement; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Exempt from taxation under section 501(c)(3) or (4) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved August 16, 1954 (68A Stat. 163; 26 U.S.C. § 501(c)(3), (4)), or a member of the D.C. Federation of Civic Associations or the Federation of Citizens Associations of the District of Columbia; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A nonprofit association, corporation, or other organization that is:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Comprised primarily of residents of a contiguous community that is defined by specific geographic boundaries, within which the school to be used is located; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Operated for the promotion of the welfare, improvement, and enhancement of that community.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="§1092" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§1092" codified:display="Note" app="2018-07-30" eff="2018-07-30">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§1092">§ 1092 of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-434, July 30, 2018, 65 DCR 8200)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" eff="2018-10-03" path="§1092" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§1092" codified:display="Note" app="2018-10-03" eff="2018-10-03">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§1092">§ 1092 of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-458, Oct. 3, 2018, 65 DCR 11212)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§1092" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
