<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-822.03a</num>
  <heading>Self-operated school food service pilot program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>During the 2020-2021 and the 2021-2022 school years, the Mayor shall operate a self-operated school food service pilot program ("pilot") in 10 public schools or the maximum number of schools that the funding appropriated will support.</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By July 30, 2020, the Mayor shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Retrofit the selected school kitchens to accommodate self-operated school food service.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Prepare for in-house food operations, including hiring and training staff, marketing the food services program, and stocking initial supplies in advance of the 2020-2021 school year.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>At least twice during the 2020-2021 school year and twice during the 2021-2022 school year, the Mayor shall administer a student satisfaction survey regarding meals provided through the pilot.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Within 3 months after the last day of the 2020-2021 and 2021-2022 school years, the Mayor shall provide to the Council a report on food services at all public schools, which shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Results from student satisfaction surveys conducted at pilot and non-pilot schools, including a comparison of the level of student satisfaction with meals provided under the pilot and meals not provided under the pilot;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A description of the costs of the pilot, including a comparison of the costs of food services provided under the pilot and the costs of the food services provided at non-pilot public schools;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The cost savings created by the pilot due to changes to existing food service contracts entered into by the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>An estimate of any federal reimbursements or other federal funding made available to the District through the implementation of a self-operated school food service model at participating schools;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A breakdown by each school of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Meal type name;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Quantity of each meal type;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Unit cost of each meal type;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Total cost of each meal type;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Number of each meal type served at free, reduced, or paid; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Total revenues, by revenue type, applied to each meal type;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>An analysis of whether meals served through the pilot and meals served by non-pilot public schools complied with federal and local school meals nutrition standards and requirements; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>An analysis of what infrastructure and operating enhancements would be necessary for the District of Columbia Public School system to successfully administer self-operated school food services in all public schools, including whether the District should fund the central kitchen required to be established by <cite path="§38-822.04">§ 38-822.04</cite> [repealed];</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall assist all eligible local educational agencies in deciding whether to elect the community eligibility provision described in 7 C.F.R. § 245.9(f) for the local educational agency or for a school or group of schools within the local educational agency.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the terms "local educational agency" and "school" shall have the same meaning as provided in 7 C.F.R. § 245.2.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-209" type="History" path="§203a">July 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-209, § 203a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§4102|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
