<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-825.01a</num>
  <heading>Prevention of lead in drinking water in schools.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Department of General Services ("DGS") shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Locate all drinking water sources at each public school and install a barcode on each of the drinking water sources;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Install a filter that reduces lead in drinking water on each drinking water source in each public school and maintain the filters, at a minimum, in a manner consistent with the manufacturer's recommendations. Filters or all of the filter's component parts shall be certified for lead reduction to the National Sanitation Foundation ("NSF")/American National Standards Institute ("ANSI") Standard 53 for Health Effects or NSF/ANSI Standard 61 for Health Effects;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Post a conspicuous sign near each water source at public schools that is not a drinking water source, which includes an image that clearly communicates that water from the water source should not be used for cooking, where applicable, or consumed;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Provide an annual schedule for testing drinking water sources at each public school to the Chief Operating Officer of the District of Columbia Public Schools ("COO") for distribution to parents or guardians of children at each public school at the start of each school year;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Test all drinking water sources at each public school for lead annually;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>If a test conducted pursuant to subparagraph (E) of this paragraph shows a lead concentration over 5 parts per billion:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Shut off the drinking water source as soon as possible but no later than 24 hours after receiving the test result and keep the drinking water source shut off until a subsequent test shows that the lead concentration level is not over 5 parts per billion;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Determine, in writing, which remediation steps should be implemented to address the elevated lead concentration level;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Send the test result and remediation steps to the COO within 5 business days of receiving the test result;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Update the list described in subparagraph (G) of this paragraph within 5 business days of receiving the test result to reflect the test result and remediation steps; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Notify the COO and update the list described in subparagraph(G) of this paragraph within 5 business days of completion of the remediation steps required by sub-subparagraph (ii) of this subparagraph; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Publish on the DGS website a list of drinking water sources in each public school that describes, for each drinking water source:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The date and results of the most recent lead test performed;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The date the current filter was installed;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>The date when the filter will next be replaced;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>The barcode identification number; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Any remediation steps that will be or have been taken.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>When the COO receives a test result, pursuant to paragraph (1)(e)(iii) of this subsection, or a notice of completion of remediation steps, pursuant to paragraph (1)(e)(v) of this subsection, the COO shall, within 2 business days of receiving such information, publish the information on the District of Columbia Public Schools website and send the information to parents or guardians of children attending the public school through email or other written communication.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Not Funded.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section is intended to, or does, create a private right of action against any person or entity based upon compliance or noncompliance with its provisions. No person or entity may assert any claim or right as a beneficiary or protected class under this section in any civil, criminal, or administrative action against the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Within 120 days of the September 23, 2017, the Mayor, pursuant to <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>, shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this section, including rules by which the Department of General Services shall reimburse public charter schools for the reasonable costs incurred in complying with subsection (b)(2) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-209" type="History" path="§501a">July 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-209, § 501a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-09-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-21" eff="2017-09-23" path="§2|(c)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-09-23" eff="2017-09-23">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="">D.C. Law 22-21</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="§11">§ 11 of D.C. Law 22-21</cite> provided that the addition of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of D.C. Law 22-21</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-09-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-21" eff="2017-09-23" path="§2|(c)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="§9" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="2017-09-23" eff="2017-09-23"><cite doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="§9">Section 9 of D.C. Law 22-21</cite> provided that within one year after September 23, 2017, the Mayor shall host 4 community meetings open to the public on the implementation of D.C. Law 22-21 and notify the public about each meeting on the Department of General Services website at least one month before the meeting is held.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-09-23" doc="D.C. Law 22-21" eff="2017-09-23" path="§9" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§7019|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-168" path="§7019|(a)" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2018-10-30" eff="2018-10-30"><cite doc="D.C. Law 22-168" path="§7019">Section 7019 of D.C. Law 22-168</cite> amendeded <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-21" path="§11">section 11 of D.C. Law 22-21</cite> removing the applicability restriction impacting this section. Therefore the amendments made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-21">D.C. Law 22-21</cite> have been implemented, except for subsection (b) of section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
