<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-952.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of <cite path="38|9B">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Dating partner" means any person who is involved in a relationship with another person that is primarily characterized by social interaction of a sexual, romantic, or intimate nature, whether casual, serious, or long-term.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Dating violence" means abusive or coercive behavior where a dating partner uses threats of, or actually uses, physical, emotional, economic, technological, or sexual abuse to exert power or control over a current or former dating partner.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"School" means a public, public charter, independent, private, or parochial school organized or authorized to operate under the laws of the District that offers instruction at any level or grade from pre-kindergarten through 12.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Sexual assault" means any of the following offenses: §§ <cite path="§22-3002">22-3002</cite> (first degree sexual abuse); <cite path="§22-3003">22-3003</cite> (second degree sexual abuse); <cite path="§22-3004">22-3004</cite> (third degree sexual abuse); <cite path="§22-3005">22-3005</cite> (fourth degree sexual abuse); <cite path="§22-3006">22-3006</cite> (misdemeanor sexual abuse); or <cite path="§22-3018">22-3018</cite>(attempts to commit sexual offenses).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Sexual harassment" means any unwelcome or uninvited sexual advances, requests for sexual favors, sexually motivated physical conduct, stalking, or other verbal or physical conduct of a sexual nature that can be reasonably predicted to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Place the victim in reasonable fear of physical harm to his or her person;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Cause a substantial detrimental effect to the victim's physical or mental health;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Substantially interfere with the victim's academic performance or attendance at school; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Substantially interfere with the victim's ability to participate in, or benefit from, the services, activities, or privileges provided by a school.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-294" eff="2019-04-11" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-294" eff="2019-04-11" path="§301" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
