<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1271.07</num>
  <heading>Renewal and continued participation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A physician seeking to renew an expedited license granted in a member state shall complete a renewal process with the interstate commission if the physician:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Maintains a full and unrestricted license in a state of principal license;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has not been convicted, received adjudication, deferred adjudication, community supervision, or deferred disposition for any offense by a court of appropriate jurisdiction;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Has not had a license authorizing the practice of medicine subject to discipline by a licensing agency in any state, federal, or foreign jurisdiction, excluding any action related to nonpayment of fees related to a license; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Has not had a controlled substance license or permit suspended or revoked by a state or the United States Drug Enforcement Administration.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Physicians shall comply with all continuing professional development or continuing medical education requirements for renewal of a license issued by a member state.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The interstate commission shall collect any renewal fees charged for the renewal of a license and distribute the fees to the applicable member board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of any renewal fees collected in subsection (c) of this section, a member board shall renew the physician's license.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Physician information collected by the interstate commission during the renewal process will be distributed to all member boards.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The interstate commission is authorized to develop rules to address renewal of licenses obtained through the Compact.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-06-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-109" eff="2018-06-05" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-06-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-109" eff="2018-06-05" path="ยง2" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
