<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1271.02</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>In this Compact:</text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Bylaws" means those bylaws established by the interstate commission pursuant to <cite path="§3-1271.11">§ 3-1271.11</cite> for its governance, or for directing and controlling its actions and conduct.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Commissioner" means the voting representative appointed by each member board pursuant to <cite path="§3-1271.11">§ 3-1271.11</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Conviction" means a finding by a court that an individual is guilty of a criminal offense through adjudication, or entry of a plea of guilt or no contest to the charge by the offender.  Evidence of an entry of a conviction of a criminal offense by the court shall be considered final for purposes of disciplinary action by a member board.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Expedited license" means a full and unrestricted medical license granted by a member state to an eligible physician through the process set forth in the Compact.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Interstate commission" means the interstate commission created pursuant to <cite path="§3-1271.11">§ 3-1271.11</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"License" means authorization by a state for a physician to engage in the practice of medicine, which would be unlawful without the authorization.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"Medical practice act" means laws and regulations governing the practice of allopathic and osteopathic medicine within a member state.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"Member board" means a state agency in a member state that acts in the sovereign interests of the state by protecting the public through licensure, regulation, and education of physicians as directed by the state government.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Member state" means a state that has enacted the Compact.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Practice of medicine" means the clinical prevention, diagnosis, or treatment of human disease, injury, or condition requiring a physician to obtain and maintain a license in compliance with the medical practice act of a member state.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Physician" means any person who:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is a graduate of a medical school accredited by the Liaison Committee on Medical Education, the Commission on Osteopathic College Accreditation, or a medical school listed in the International Medical Education Directory or its equivalent;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Passed each component of the United States Medical Licensing Examination ("USMLE") or the Comprehensive Osteopathic Medical Licensing Examination ("COMLEX-USA") within 3 attempts, or any of its predecessor examinations accepted by a state medical board as an equivalent examination for licensure purposes;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Successfully completed graduate medical education approved by the Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education or the American Osteopathic Association;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Holds specialty certification or a time-unlimited specialty certificate recognized by the American Board of Medical Specialties or the American Osteopathic Association's Bureau of Osteopathic Specialists;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Possesses a full and unrestricted license to engage in the practice of medicine issued by a member board;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Has never been convicted, received adjudication, deferred adjudication, community supervision, or deferred disposition for any offense by a court of appropriate jurisdiction;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Has never held a license authorizing the practice of medicine subjected to discipline by a licensing agency in any state, federal, or foreign jurisdiction, excluding any action related to non-payment of fees related to a license;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Has never had a controlled substance license or permit suspended or revoked by a state or the United States Drug Enforcement Administration; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>Is not under active investigation by a licensing agency or law enforcement authority in any state, federal, or foreign jurisdiction.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>"Offense" means a felony, gross misdemeanor, or crime of moral turpitude.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>"Rule" means a written statement by the interstate commission promulgated pursuant to <cite path="§3-1271.12">§ 3-1271.12</cite> that is of general applicability, implements, interprets, or prescribes a policy or provision of the Compact, or an organizational, procedural, or practice requirement of the interstate commission, and has the force and effect of statutory law in a member state, and includes the amendment, repeal, or suspension of an existing rule.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>"State" means any state, commonwealth, district, or territory of the United States.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>"State of principal license" means a member state where a physician holds a license to practice medicine and which has been designated as such by the physician for purposes of registration and participation in the Compact.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-06-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-109" eff="2018-06-05" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-06-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-109" eff="2018-06-05" path="§2" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
