<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1271.05</num>
  <heading>Application and issuance of expedited licensure.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A physician seeking licensure through the Compact shall file an application for an expedited license with the member board of the state selected by the physician as the state of principal license.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Upon receipt of an application for an expedited license, the member board within the state selected as the state of principal license shall evaluate whether the physician is eligible for expedited licensure and issue a letter of qualification, verifying or denying the physician's eligibility, to the interstate commission.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Static qualifications, which include verification of medical education, graduate medical education, results of any medical or licensing examination, and other qualifications as determined by the interstate commission through rule, shall not be subject to additional primary source verification where already primary source verified by the state of principal license.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The member board within the state selected as the state of principal license shall, in the course of verifying eligibility, perform a criminal background check of an applicant, including the use of the results of fingerprint or other biometric data checks compliant with the requirements of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, with the exception of federal employees who have suitability determination in accordance with 5 C.F.R. ยง 731.202.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Appeal on the determination of eligibility shall be made to the member state where the application was filed and shall be subject to the laws of that state.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Upon verification in subsection (b) of this section, physicians eligible for an expedited license shall complete the registration process established by the interstate commission to receive a license in a member state selected pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, including the payment of any applicable fees.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>After receiving verification of eligibility under subsection (b) of this section and any fees under subsection (c) of this section, a member board shall issue an expedited license to the physician.  This license shall authorize the physician to practice medicine in the issuing state consistent with the medical practice act and all applicable laws and regulations of the issuing member board and member state.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An expedited license shall be valid for a period consistent with the licensure period in the member state and in the same manner as required for other physicians holding a full and unrestricted license within the member state.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>An expedited license obtained though the Compact shall be terminated if a physician fails to maintain a license in the state of principal licensure for a nondisciplinary reason, without redesignation of a new state of principal licensure.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The interstate commission is authorized to develop rules regarding the application process, including payment of any applicable fees, and the issuance of an expedited license.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-06-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-109" eff="2018-06-05" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-06-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-109" eff="2018-06-05" path="ยง2" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
