<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1206.62</num>
  <heading>Certification of maternity centers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of satisfactory proof from the applicant, the Mayor shall certify that the following services will be provided at a maternity center by or under the supervision of a certified nurse-midwife or a certified professional midwife that has a licensed physician is available at all times:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Diagnostic services for screening at-risk maternity patient-clients and newborn infants;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Referral for care of at-risk maternity patient-clients and newborn infants; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Midwifery services for the care of at-risk maternity patient-clients and newborn infants.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An individual or entity shall be appointed by the maternity center to develop and maintain a written organizational plan and be responsible for the appointment of a certified nurse-midwife or a CPM as director of the maternity center and a qualified physician as Director of Medical Affairs.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A maternity center shall not be required to employ a director of medical affairs if the maternity center is able to produce demonstrative evidence that the maternity center has access to appropriate consultation and transfer of care with an obstetrician within an appropriate distance from the birthing center.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If midwifery services are provided by a maternity center, a certified nurse midwife, CPM, or the director of a maternity center shall be appointed director of midwifery services.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History" path="ยง662">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, ยง 662</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-03-31" doc="D.C. Act 23-267" eff="2020-03-31" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-03-31" doc="D.C. Act 23-267" eff="2020-03-31" path="ยง2|(e)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
