<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1271.11</num>
  <heading>Interstate medical licensure compact commission.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The member states hereby create the 'Interstate Medical Licensure Compact Commission.'</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The purpose of the interstate commission is the administration of the Compact, which is a discretionary state function.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The interstate commission shall be a body corporate and joint agency of the member states and shall have all the responsibilities, powers, and duties set forth in the Compact, and such additional powers as may be conferred upon it by a subsequent concurrent action of the respective legislatures of the member states in accordance with the terms of the Compact.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The interstate commission shall consist of 2 voting representatives appointed by each member state who shall serve as Commissioners.  In states where allopathic and osteopathic physicians are regulated by separate member boards, or if the licensing and disciplinary authority is split between multiple member boards within a member state, the member state shall appoint one representative from each member board.  A Commissioner shall be:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An allopathic or osteopathic physician appointed to a member board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An executive director, executive secretary, or similar executive of a member board; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A member of the public appointed to a member board.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The interstate commission shall meet at least once each calendar year.  A portion of this meeting shall be a business meeting to address such matters as may properly come before the commission, including the election of officers.  The chairperson may call additional meetings and shall call for a meeting upon the request of a majority of the member states.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The bylaws may provide for meetings of the interstate commission to be conducted by telecommunication or electronic communication.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Each commissioner participating at a meeting of the interstate commission is entitled to one vote.  A majority of commissioners shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, unless a larger quorum is required by the bylaws of the interstate commission.  A commissioner shall not delegate a vote to another commissioner.  In the absence of its commissioner, a member state may delegate voting authority for a specified meeting to another person from that state who shall meet the requirements of subsection (d) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The interstate commission shall provide public notice of all meetings and all meetings shall be open to the public.  The interstate commission may close a meeting, in full or in portion, where it determines by a two-thirds vote of the commissioners present that an open meeting would be likely to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Relate solely to the internal personnel practices and procedures of the interstate commission;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Discuss matters specifically exempted from disclosure by federal statute;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Discuss trade secrets, commercial, or financial information that is privileged or confidential;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Involve accusing a person of a crime, or formally censuring a person;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Discuss information of a personal nature where disclosure would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Discuss investigative records compiled for law enforcement purposes; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Specifically relate to the participation in a civil action or other legal proceeding.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>The interstate commission shall keep minutes which shall fully describe all matters discussed in a meeting and shall provide a full and accurate summary of actions taken, including record of any roll call votes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>The interstate commission shall make its information and official records, to the extent not otherwise designated in the Compact or by its rules, available to the public for inspection.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(k)</num>
    <text>The interstate commission shall establish an executive committee, which shall include officers, members, and others as determined by the bylaws.  The executive committee shall have the power to act on behalf of the interstate commission, with the exception of rulemaking, during periods when the interstate commission is not in session.  When acting on behalf of the interstate commission, the executive committee shall oversee the administration of the Compact including enforcement and compliance with the provisions of the Compact, its bylaws and rules, and other such duties as necessary.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(l)</num>
    <text>The interstate commission may establish other committees for governance and administration of the Compact.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-06-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-109" eff="2018-06-05" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-06-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-109" eff="2018-06-05" path="ยง2" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
