<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1271.08</num>
  <heading>Coordinated information system.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The interstate commission shall establish a database of all physicians licensed, or who have applied for licensure, under <cite path="ยง3-1271.05">ยง 3-1271.05</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, member boards shall report to the interstate commission any public action or complaints against a licensed physician who has applied or received an expedited license through the Compact.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Member boards shall report disciplinary or investigatory information determined as necessary and proper by rule of the interstate commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Member boards may report any nonpublic complaint, disciplinary, or investigatory information not required by subsection (c) of this section to the interstate commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Member boards shall share complaint or disciplinary information about a physician upon request of another member board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>All information provided to the interstate commission or distributed by member boards shall be confidential, filed under seal, and used only for investigatory or disciplinary matters.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The interstate commission is authorized to develop rules for mandated or discretionary sharing of information by member boards.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-06-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-109" eff="2018-06-05" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-06-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-109" eff="2018-06-05" path="ยง2" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
