<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1271.10</num>
  <heading>Disciplinary actions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any disciplinary action taken by any member board against a physician licensed through the Compact shall be deemed unprofessional conduct which may be subject to discipline by other member boards, in addition to any violation of the medical practice act or regulations in that state.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a license granted to a physician by the member board in the state of principal license is revoked, surrendered or relinquished in lieu of discipline, or suspended, then all licenses issued to the physician by member boards shall automatically be placed, without further action necessary by any member board, on the same status.  If the member board in the state of principal license subsequently reinstates the physician's license, a license issued to the physician by any other member board shall remain encumbered until that respective member board takes action to reinstate the license in a manner consistent with the medical practice act of that state.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If disciplinary action is taken against a physician by a member board not in the state of principal license, any other member board may deem the action conclusive as to matter of law and fact decided, and:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Impose the same or lesser sanction(s) against the physician so long as such sanctions are consistent with the medical practice act of that state; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Pursue separate disciplinary action against the physician under its respective medical practice act, regardless of the action taken in other member states.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a license granted to a physician by a member board is revoked, surrendered or relinquished in lieu of discipline, or suspended, then any license(s) issued to the physician by any other member board(s) shall be suspended, automatically and immediately without further action necessary by the other member board(s), for 90 days upon entry of the order by the disciplining board, to permit the member board(s) to investigate the basis for the action under the medical practice act of that state.  A member board may terminate the automatic suspension of the license it issued prior to the completion of the 90-day suspension period in a manner consistent with the medical practice act of that state.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-06-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-109" eff="2018-06-05" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-06-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-109" eff="2018-06-05" path="ยง2" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
