<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-420</num>
  <heading>Fees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The SHPDA shall collect application fees from persons that request a certificate of need. The fee required for an application shall be the greater of 3% of the proposed capital expenditure or $5,000, with a maximum of $300,000. The SHPDA is authorized to establish a fee schedule for certain data, analyses and reports published by the SHPDA from the HPDS. The annual user fee for private hospitals shall be $4 per inpatient admission and increase to $4.50 per inpatient admission beginning in the 2021 fiscal year, based on the previous calendar year’s admission data, to be paid to the SHPDA on a quarterly basis, in lieu of a certificate of need application fee. The certificate of need application fee for any project receiving funds through the Medical Homes DC initiative, as operated by the District of Columbia Primary Care Association, shall be $5,000. User fees may also be established for other classes of facilities by regulation. SHPDA may adjust a user fee periodically to reflect the change in the Consumer Price Index issued by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, United States Department of Labor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the maximum application fee that may be collected from Specialty Hospitals of America, LLC, or certain of its subsidiary entities, for facilities located in Lots 3 and 4, Square 5919, related to the acquisition of Greater Southeast Community Hospital shall be $300,000.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the maximum application fee that may be collected from either a federally qualified health center or a federally qualified health center look-alike for a new institutional health service located in Ward 7 or Ward 8 shall be $5,000.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>"Federally qualified health center" shall have the same meaning as provided in section 1861(aa)(4) of the Social Security Act, approved August 14, 1935 (79 Stat. 313; 42 U.S.C. § 1395x(aa)(4)).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>"Federally qualified health center look-alike" means an entity that has been determined by the Health Resources and Services Administration of the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services to meet the definition of a federally qualified health center, but does not receive funding under section 330 of the Public Health Service Act, approved June 12, 2002 (117 Stat. 2020; 42 U.S.C. § 254b).</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-191" type="History" path="§21">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-191, § 21, 43 DCR 4535</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-307" type="History">June 5, 2003, D.C. Law 14-307, § 2002(d), 49 DCR 11664</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-149" type="History">Apr. 22, 2004, D.C. Law 15-149, § 2(h), 51 DCR 2802</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-116" type="History">Mar. 20, 2008, D.C. Law 17-116, § 2, 55 DCR 1280</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-167" type="History">June 5, 2008, D.C. Law 17-167, § 3, 55 DCR 5178</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Health Services Planning Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-319, March 19, 2008,  55 DCR 3430).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of East of the River Hospital Revitalization Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-249, January 23, 2008,  55 DCR 1255).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Health Services Planning Program Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-234, December 27, 2007,  55 DCR 238).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of East of the River Hospital Revitalization Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-168, October 19, 2007,  54 DCR 10978).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(g) of Health Services Planning and Development Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-322, January 28, 2004,  51 DCR 1581).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2002(d) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-103, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5499).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(g) of Health Services Planning and Development Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-87, May 19, 2003,  50 DCR 4325).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(g) of Health Services Planning and Development Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-49, March 28, 2003,  50 DCR 2943).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2002(d) of the Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-27, February 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2151).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2002(d) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-544, December 4, 2002,  49 DCR 11700).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-71">D.C. Law 17-71</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-71">D.C. Law 17-71</cite> designated the existing text as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b) to read as follows: “(b) Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the maximum application fee that may be collected from Specialty Hospitals of America, LLC, or certain of its subsidiary entities, for facilities located in Lots 3 and 4, Square 5919, related to the acquisition of Greater Southeast Community Hospital shall be $300,000.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(g) of Health Services Planning and Development Temporary Amendment Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-19">D.C. Law 15-19</cite>, June 21, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 5463).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-167">D.C. Law 17-167</cite> designated the existing text as subsec. (a); and added subsec. (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-116">D.C. Law 17-116</cite> inserted “The certificate of need application fee for any project receiving funds through the Medical Homes DC initiative, as operated by the District of Columbia Primary Care Association, shall be $5,000.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-149">D.C. Law 15-149</cite> added three new sentences at the end to read: “The annual user fee for private hospitals shall be $4 per inpatient admission, based on the previous calendar year’s admission data, to be paid to the SHPDA on a quarterly basis, in lieu of a certificate of need application fee. User fees may also be established for other classes of facilities by regulation. SHPDA may adjust a user fee periodically to reflect the change in the Consumer Price Index issued by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, United States Department of Labor.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-307">D.C. Law 14-307</cite> substituted “3% of the proposed capital expenditure or $5,000, with a maximum of $300,000” for “1% of the proposed capital expenditure or $2, 000, with a maximum of $25,000”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 32-370.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§44-402">§ 44-402</cite> and <cite path="§44-420.01">§ 44-420.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-110" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2017-07-28" eff="2017-07-28">For temporary (90 days) , see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-110" path="§2">§ 2 of Unity Health Care, Inc. Certificate of Need Maximum Fee Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-110, July 28, 2017, 64 DCR 7396)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-07-28" doc="D.C. Act 22-110" eff="2017-07-28" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 22-28" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2017-12-01" eff="2017-12-01">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-28" path="§2">§ 2 of Unity Health Care, Inc. Certificate of Need Maximum Fee Establishment Temporary Amendment Act of 2017 (D.C. Law 22-28, Dec. 1, 2017, 64 DCR 10166)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-12-01" doc="D.C. Law 22-28" eff="2017-12-01" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-176" eff="2018-10-30" path="§2" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 22-176" path="§2" codified:display="Note" app="2018-10-30" eff="2018-10-30">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-176" path="">D.C. Law 22-176</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-176" path="§3">§ 3 of D.C. Law 22-176</cite> provided that the change made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-176" path="§2">§ 2 of D.C. Law 22-176</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 23-60" eff="2020-03-10" path="§2|(d)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-03-10" doc="D.C. Law 23-60" eff="2020-03-10" path="§2|(d)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 23-60" path="§2|(d)|(2)" codified:display="Note" app="2020-03-10" eff="2020-03-10">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-60" path="">D.C. Law 23-60</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-60" path="§3">§ 3 of D.C. Law 23-60</cite> provided that the change made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-60" path="§2|(d)|(2)">§ 2(d)(2) of D.C. Law 23-60</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" path="§7063" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2020-12-03" eff="2020-12-03"><cite doc="D.C. Law 23-149" path="§7063">Section 7063 of D.C. Law 23-149</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-176" path="§3">section 3 of D.C. Law 22-176</cite> removing the applicability provision impacting this section.  Therefore, the amendment of this section by section 2 of Law 22-176 has been implemented.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="§7063" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" path="§7072" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2020-12-03" eff="2020-12-03"><cite doc="D.C. Law 23-149" path="§7072">Section 7072 of D.C. Law 23-149</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-60" path="§3">section 3 of D.C. Law 23-60</cite> removing the applicability provision impacting this section.  Therefore, the creation of subsections (d) and (e) of this section by section 2 of Law 23-60 has been implemented.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="§7072" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the $52,050 application fee paid by Iona Senior Services for a project located at 3303 Stanton Road, S.E., Washington, D.C., 20020, shall be waived and refunded.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the maximum application fee that may be collected from Community of Hope for a project located at 2120 Bladensburg Road, N.E., Washington, D.C., 20018, shall be $5,000, and any application fees paid prior to March 3, 2020 shall be refunded.</text>
  </para>
</section>
