<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-534.02</num>
  <heading>Environmental health standards.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Persons responsible for maintenance of the physical plant, including housekeeping, shall be specifically identified.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Treatment rooms shall have a minimum clear floor area sufficient to permit removal of a patient by stretcher. A lavatory or sink with handwashing facility with controls appropriate for mode sterility technique used by the facility shall be provided.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Illumination shall provide at least the equivalent of 100 foot candles of light at the examining table, as well as in the surgical area.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>There shall be a preventive maintenance program for mechanical equipment and medical devices. This program of prevention maintenance should include, but is not limited to, regularly scheduled inspection of medical equipment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>There shall be convenient handwashing facilities and/or necessary control valves to minimize the potential of cross contamination.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>An environmental monitoring program, which shall include environmental surveillance and infection surveillance, shall be established and followed routinely.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-66" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="1978-04-06" eff="1978-04-06" path="" display="false">
        This section was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-26">section 4 of D.C. Law 6-26</cite>; however, pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-26">section 6(b)</cite> of D.C. Law 6-26, the repeal will not apply until the Mayor issues rules for ambulatory surgical facilities. As of this date, the Mayor has not issued such rules. 
  </annotation>
    <annotation app="1978-04-06" doc="D.C. Law 2-66" eff="1978-04-06" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-66" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="1978-04-06" eff="1978-04-06" path="">
        This section was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-26">section 4 of D.C. Law 6-26</cite>; however, pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-26">section 6(b)</cite> of D.C. Law 6-26, the repeal will not apply until the Mayor issues rules for ambulatory surgical facilities. As of this date, the Mayor has not issued such rules. 
  </annotation>
    <annotation app="1978-04-06" doc="D.C. Law 2-66" eff="1978-04-06" path="ยง402" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
