<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-533.05</num>
  <heading>Post-operative requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each center shall establish a program to ensure post surgical treatment for each individual treated in the center and shall include (but is not limited to) the following written instructions to be issued to all patients:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Symptoms of complications to be looked for;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Activities to be avoided, if any;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Specific telephone number to be used by the patient should any complication occur or question arise;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Reminder to make arrangements with the center or the patient's personal physician for a post-operative check-up.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Following the surgical procedure, patients shall be observed in the center for a period of time sufficient to ensure that no immediate post-operative complications are present following the administration of anesthetics.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Patients in whom any adverse condition exists or in whom complication is known or suspected to have occurred during or after the performance of the surgical procedure shall be transferred and admitted to a hospital, if good medical practice so indicates.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-66" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="1978-04-06" eff="1978-04-06" path="" display="false">
        This section was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-26">section 4 of D.C. Law 6-26</cite>; however, pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-26">section 6(b)</cite> of D.C. Law 6-26, the repeal will not apply until the Mayor issues rules for ambulatory surgical facilities. As of this date, the Mayor has not issued such rules. 
  </annotation>
    <annotation app="1978-04-06" doc="D.C. Law 2-66" eff="1978-04-06" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-66" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="1978-04-06" eff="1978-04-06" path="">
        This section was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-26">section 4 of D.C. Law 6-26</cite>; however, pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-26">section 6(b)</cite> of D.C. Law 6-26, the repeal will not apply until the Mayor issues rules for ambulatory surgical facilities. As of this date, the Mayor has not issued such rules. 
  </annotation>
    <annotation app="1978-04-06" doc="D.C. Law 2-66" eff="1978-04-06" path="ยง305" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
