<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-533.01</num>
  <heading>Organization of center.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each surgical center shall have a governing board formally organized in accordance with written by-laws. Such by-laws shall establish procedures for the appointment of the center administrator and medical director, for the admission of physicians to practice at the center, for revocation or suspension of a physician's center privileges, and for patient admissions and discharge. A copy of the by-laws shall be available for public inspection at all times.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A center owned by a sole proprietorship, partnership or professional medical corporation shall not be required to have a governing board, but the center shall have written procedures, available for public inspection at all times, governing the admission for physicians to practice at the center, for revocation or suspension of a physician's center privileges, and for patient admissions and discharge.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-66" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="1978-04-06" eff="1978-04-06" path="" display="false">
        This section was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-26">section 4 of D.C. Law 6-26</cite>; however, pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-26">section 6(b)</cite> of D.C. Law 6-26, the repeal will not apply until the Mayor issues rules for ambulatory surgical facilities. As of this date, the Mayor has not issued such rules. 
  </annotation>
    <annotation app="1978-04-06" doc="D.C. Law 2-66" eff="1978-04-06" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-66" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="1978-04-06" eff="1978-04-06" path="">
        This section was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-26">section 4 of D.C. Law 6-26</cite>; however, pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-26">section 6(b)</cite> of D.C. Law 6-26, the repeal will not apply until the Mayor issues rules for ambulatory surgical facilities. As of this date, the Mayor has not issued such rules. 
  </annotation>
    <annotation app="1978-04-06" doc="D.C. Law 2-66" eff="1978-04-06" path="ยง301" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
