<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-532.02</num>
  <heading>Application.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>Application for license to operate a center shall be made to the Mayor on forms furnished by him and shall include, but not be limited to, the following information:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the facility;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The names and addresses of the owners of the facility. If the owner is a corporation, the application shall include the names and addresses of all officers of the corporation and all persons having a 10% or more ownership interest;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The medical and surgical procedures for which the center is to be licensed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The names and addresses of the center's administrator and medical director;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Evidence of capacity to provide emergency care or secure appropriate emergency care expeditiously for a patient. Such evidence shall include, at a minimum:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Provision of appropriately trained staff, space, equipment and supplies to stabilize the condition of a patient prior to transport to a hospital; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Agreement(s) between the center and a hospital not more than 20 minutes ambulance driving time from the center that the hospital will admit all center patients needing emergency care, or proof that all physicians using the center have, or a center staff physician is always available who has, admitting privileges at a hospital not more than 20 minutes ambulance time from the center.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-66" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="1978-04-06" eff="1978-04-06" path="" display="false">
        This section was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-26">section 4 of D.C. Law 6-26</cite>; however, pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-26">section 6(b)</cite> of D.C. Law 6-26, the repeal will not apply until the Mayor issues rules for ambulatory surgical facilities. As of this date, the Mayor has not issued such rules. 
  </annotation>
    <annotation app="1978-04-06" doc="D.C. Law 2-66" eff="1978-04-06" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-66" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="1978-04-06" eff="1978-04-06" path="">
        This section was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-26">section 4 of D.C. Law 6-26</cite>; however, pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-26">section 6(b)</cite> of D.C. Law 6-26, the repeal will not apply until the Mayor issues rules for ambulatory surgical facilities. As of this date, the Mayor has not issued such rules. 
  </annotation>
    <annotation app="1978-04-06" doc="D.C. Law 2-66" eff="1978-04-06" path="ยง202" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
