<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-663.05</num>
  <heading>Medicaid outpatient hospital access payments.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For visits and services beginning October 1, 2016, quarterly Medicaid outpatient hospital access payments shall be made to each private hospital.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each payment will be equal to the hospital's DFY 2014 outpatient Medicaid payments divided by the total in District private hospital DFY 2014 outpatient Medicaid payments multiplied by 1/4 of the total outpatient private hospital access payment pool.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The total outpatient private hospital access payment pool is equal to the total available spending room under the private hospital outpatient Medicaid upper payment limit for DFY 2017.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For visits and services beginning October 1, 2016, outpatient hospital access payments shall be made to the United Medical Center.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each payment will be equal to one quarter of the total outpatient public hospital access payment pool.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The total outpatient public hospital access payment pool is equal to the total available spending room under the District-operated hospital outpatient Medicaid upper payment limit for DFY 2017.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The quarterly Medicaid outpatient hospital access payments shall be made within 15 business days after the end of each DFY quarter for the Medicaid visits and services rendered during that quarter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No payments shall be made under this section until such time that the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services approves the Medicaid State Plan amendment authorizing the Medicaid payments described in <cite path="44|6A|V">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Medicaid payment methodologies authorized under <cite path="44|6A|V">this subchapter</cite> shall not be altered in any way unless such alteration is necessary to gain federal approval from the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="Expiration of Law">
          Section 5070 of D.C. Law 21-160 provided that this section shall expire on September 30, 2017.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="V" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="ยง5066" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
