<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-663.03</num>
  <heading>Hospital provider fee.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning October 1, 2016, and subject to <cite path="§44-663.04">§ 44-663.04</cite>, the District may charge each hospital a fee based on its outpatient gross patient revenue. The fee shall be charged at a uniform rate necessary to generate the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An amount equal to the non-federal share of the total available spending room under the Medicaid upper payment limit for private hospitals applicable to District Fiscal Year ("DFY") 2017 consistent with the federal approval of the authorizing Medicaid State Plan amendment; plus</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An amount equal to the non-federal share of the total available spending room under the Medicaid upper payment limit for District-operated hospitals applicable to DFY 2017 consistent with the federal approval of the authorizing Medicaid State Plan amendment; plus</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An amount equal to the Department's administrative expenses as described in <cite path="§44-663.02|(c)|(2)">§ 44-663.02(c)(2)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A psychiatric hospital that is an agency or a unit of the District government is exempt from the fee imposed under subsection (a) of this section, unless the exemption is adjudged to be unconstitutional or otherwise invalid, in which case a psychiatric hospital that is an agency or a unit of the District government shall pay the fee imposed by subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="Expiration of Law">
          Section 5070 of D.C. Law 21-160 provided that this section shall expire on September 30, 2017.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="V" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§5064" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
