<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-663.14</num>
  <heading>Quarterly notice and collection.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The fee imposed under <cite path="§44-663.13">§ 44-663.13</cite> shall be due and payable by the 15th of the last month of each DFY quarter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The fee imposed under <cite path="§44-663.13">§ 44-663.13</cite> shall be calculated, due, and payable on a quarterly basis, but shall not be due and payable until the District issues written notice to each hospital informing the hospital of its fee rate, inpatient net patient revenue subject to the fee, and the fee amount owed on a quarterly basis, including, in the initial written notice from the District to the hospital, all fee amounts owed beginning with the period October 1, 2016, to ensure all applicable fee obligations have been identified.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a hospital fails to pay the full amount of its fee by the date required, the unpaid balance shall accrue interest at the rate of 1.5% per month or any fraction thereof, which shall be added to the unpaid balance.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer may arrange a payment plan for the amount of the fee and interest in arrears.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The payment by the hospital of the fee created in <cite path="44|6A|VI">this subchapter</cite> shall be reported as an allowable cost for purposes of Medicaid hospital reimbursement.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="Expiration of Law">
          Section 5079 of D.C. Law 21-160 provided that this section shall expire on September 30, 2017.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="V" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§5075" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
