<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1227.07</num>
  <heading>Additional Walter Reed Site acquisition and procurement authority.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may acquire by purchase, exchange, donation, assignment, bequest, or other means, real property located on the Walter Reed Site.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The provisions of <cite path="50|26|I">subchapter I of Chapter 26 of Title 50</cite> shall not apply to the acquisition by the Mayor of property located on the Walter Reed Site or the use of such property as a parking facility.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding <cite path="2|3A">Chapter 3A of this title</cite>, and consistent with <cite path="§1-204.51">§ 1-204.51</cite>, the Mayor may enter into a contract with Children's National at Walter Reed, LLC, or an affiliate thereof, for the operation and maintenance of property acquired pursuant to this section; provided, that the entity that contracts with the Mayor shall agree to be subject to the contracting and procurement requirements set forth in <cite path="2|2|IX-A|D|2">subpart 2 of part D of subchapter IX-A of Chapter 2 of this title</cite> and the employment and job creation requirements set forth in <cite path="§2-219.03">§ 2-219.03</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The contract entered into pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection shall require Children's National at Walter Reed, LLC or its affiliate to give priority when subcontracting to businesses certified as small business enterprises pursuant to <cite path="§2-218.32">§ 2-218.32</cite> or as disadvantaged business enterprises pursuant to <cite path="§2-218.33">§ 2-218.33</cite>, and to do so in a manner to be negotiated between the Mayor and Children's National at Walter Reed, LLC or its affiliate.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-119" type="History" path="§7a">May 18, 2016, D.C. Law 21-119, § 7a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-05-18" doc="D.C. Law 21-119" eff="2016-05-18" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation codify:doc="D.C. Code" path="§2162|(b)" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91">
          For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="2162|(b)">§ 2162(b) of the Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019</cite>, 66 DCR 8497).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§2162|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation codify:doc="D.C. Code" path="§2162|(b)" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112">
          For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="2162|(b)">§ 2162(b) of the Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019</cite>, 66 DCR 11964).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§2162|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§2162|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
