<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1217.37d</num>
  <heading>Bond authorization.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Council approves and authorizes the issuance of one or more series of Bonds in an aggregate principal amount not to exceed $24 million to fund the project. The Bonds, which may be issued from time to time, in one or more series, shall be tax-exempt or taxable as the Mayor shall determine and shall be payable and secured as provided in <cite path="§2-1217.37e">§ 2-1217.37e</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The proceeds of the Bonds shall be used as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An amount not to exceed $18 million shall be used to pay Development Costs of the project; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The balance of the proceeds may be used to pay the financing costs incurred by the District and to fund capitalized interest and required reserves.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may pay from the proceeds of the Bonds the financing costs and expenses of issuing and delivering the Bonds, including, but not limited to, underwriting, legal, accounting, financial advisory, credit enhancement, marketing, sale, and printing costs and expenses.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Bonds also may be issued as a TIF note to the Development Sponsor and may be held and used as security for debt incurred or to be incurred by the Development Sponsor, an agent of the Development Sponsor, or another party selected by the Development Sponsor and approved by the District.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2017-04-07" doc="D.C. Law 21-262" eff="2017-04-07" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-04-07" doc="D.C. Law 21-262" eff="2017-04-07" path="§5" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-13" path="§2|(d)" codified:display="Note" app="2019-02-25" eff="2019-02-25">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-13" path="§2|(d)">§ 2(d) of Bryant Street Tax Increment Financing Emergency Amendment Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-13, Feb. 25, 2019, 66 DCR 2467)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-02-25" doc="D.C. Act 23-13" eff="2019-02-25" path="§2|(d)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 23-5" path="§2|(d)" codified:display="Note" app="2019-04-18" eff="2019-04-18">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-5" path="§2|(d)">§ 2(d) of Bryant Street Tax Increment Financing Temporary Amendment Act of 2019 (D.C. Law 23-5, Apr. 18, 2019, 66 DCR 2696)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-04-18" doc="D.C. Law 23-5" eff="2019-04-18" path="§2|(d)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
