<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1217.40j</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by temporary legislation that will expire on June 2, 2021. For reference, click link to D.C. Law 23-146 below.*
      </text>
  <heading>Limited liability.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The bonds shall be special obligations of the District. The bonds shall be without recourse to the District. The bonds shall not be general obligations of the District, shall not be a pledge of, or involve, the faith and credit or the taxing power of the District (other than the Available Tax Increment, the Available Increment, and any other taxes or fees allocated to the Reunion Square TIF Fund), shall not constitute a debt of the District, and shall not constitute lending of the public credit for private undertakings as prohibited in section 602(a)(2) of the Home Rule Act.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The bonds shall not give rise to any pecuniary liability of the District, and the District shall have no obligation with respect to the purchase of the bonds.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No person, including, but not limited to, any bond owner, shall have any claims against the District or any of its elected or appointed officials, officers, employees, or agents for monetary damages suffered as a result of the failure of the District to perform any covenant, undertaking, or obligation under this act, the bonds, the Financing Documents, or the Closing Documents, or as a result of the incorrectness of any representation in or omission from the Financing Documents or the Closing Documents, unless the District or its elected or appointed officials, officers, employees, or agents have acted in a willful and fraudulent manner.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1217.40j" action="creation of this section" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§2-1217.40j" codified:display="Note"/>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1217.40j" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§2-1217.40j">
    <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by temporary legislation that will expire on June 2, 2021. For reference, click link to D.C. Law 23-146 below.*
      </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-10-20" doc="D.C. Law 23-146" eff="2020-10-20" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-20" doc="D.C. Law 23-146" eff="2020-10-20" path="§11" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-20" doc="D.C. Law 23-146" eff="2020-10-20" path="§11" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 23-146" path="§11" codified:display="Note" app="2020-10-20" eff="2020-10-20">For temporary (225 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-146" path="§11">§ 11 of Reunion Square Tax Increment Financing Temporary Amendment Act of 2020 (D.C. Law 23-146, Oct. 20, 2020, 67 DCR 9941)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
