<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1208.32</num>
  <heading>Made in DC program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established within the Department a Made in DC program, which shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Promote products created, manufactured, or assembled in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Develop and promote the Made in DC brand name as an identifier of products created, manufactured, or assembled in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Develop a logo for the Made in DC brand name to aid District-based businesses in marketing their products and to promote public recognition of the logo;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Raise awareness of and pride in products created, manufactured, or assembled in the District that carry the Made in DC logo;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Conduct a public awareness campaign, including producing public service announcements and distributing marketing materials, such as stickers, flyers, and digital logos, to promote the Made in DC brand name;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Coordinate with Events DC and Destination DC to market the Made in DC brand name and products created, manufactured, or assembled in the District to conventions, tourists, and major events;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Establish and maintain an online resource listing of products branded Made in DC;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Establish an application process to approve an eligible product created, manufactured, or assembled in the District; provided, that the Department shall review each approval every 3 years to confirm a product's continued eligibility and revoke its approval for use of the Made in DC brand name of any product or DBB that no longer meets the requirements of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Provide technical assistance and other support to help eligible makers utilize the Made in DC brand name, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Coordinating with the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs to market the Program to eligible makers; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Developing an interactive network to enable designers and makers to connect to spur local product innovation and partnerships;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Monitor the use of the Made in DC brand name to identify and stop the unauthorized use of the brand name and its logo; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Develop criteria to evaluate on an ongoing basis the effectiveness of the Program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department may engage a non-governmental organization with specific expertise in the District maker community to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Assist the Department with the duties listed in subsection (a) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Identify makers who may be eligible to participate in the Program; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Assess obstacles, if any, to the viability of the District maker community and make recommendations to address those obstacles.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-07-01" doc="D.C. Law 21-135" eff="2016-07-01" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-07-01" doc="D.C. Law 21-135" eff="2016-07-01" path="§3" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" codified:display="Note" app="2016-07-01" eff="2016-07-01" doc="D.C. Law 21-135" path="§3">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-135" path="">D.C. Law 21-135</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-135" path="§7">§ 7 of D.C. Law 21-135</cite> provided that the addition of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-135" path="§3">§ 3 of D.C. Law 21-135</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§7007" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2016-10-08" eff="2016-10-08"><cite doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§7007">Section 7007 of D.C. Law 21-160</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-135" path="§7">§ 7 of D.C. Law 21-135</cite>. Therefore the changes made to this section by D.C. Law 21-113 have been given effect.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§7007" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
