<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1215.81</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on January 31, 2021.*
      </text>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation and amended by emergency legislation that will expire on January 31, 2021.*
      </text>
  <heading>BID public space maintenance agreements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding <cite path="2|3A">Chapter 3A of this title</cite>, and <cite path="§9-401.06|(c)">§ 9-401.06(c)</cite>, the Mayor may enter into an agreement, excluding grant agreements, with a BID corporation, as defined in <cite path="§2-1215.02|(4)">§ 2-1215.02(4)</cite>, to maintain or improve a District-owned asset or public space, including sidewalks, streets, parks, plazas, signage, and public art, within or partially within the boundaries of the BID, as defined in <cite path="§2-1215.02|(7)">§ 2-1215.02(7)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall pay or reimburse to a BID corporation the reasonably incurred expenses for maintaining or improving a District-owned asset or public space or for engaging in planning activity under this section for services customarily provided by the District to any similar geographic area pursuant to <cite path="§2-1215.20|(a)">§ 2-1215.20(a)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An agreement with a BID corporation made pursuant to this section to complete work on a District-owned asset or in public space shall contain provisions requiring adequate insurance and indemnification, and such work on a District-owned asset or in public space shall be subject to applicable permits.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>An agreement with a BID corporation made pursuant to this section shall not exceed $800,000 for a single fiscal year; provided, that a multiyear agreement shall be allowed, subject to annual appropriation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>This section shall apply during a period of time for which the Mayor has declared a public health emergency pursuant to <cite path="§7-2304.01">§ 7-2304.01</cite> and for 30 days thereafter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-11-02" doc="D.C. Act 23-475" eff="2020-11-02" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-11-02" doc="D.C. Act 23-475" eff="2020-11-02" path="§4" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-11-02" doc="D.C. Act 23-475" eff="2020-11-02" path="§2" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-07" doc="D.C. Act 23-520" eff="2020-12-07" path="§2" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-07" doc="D.C. Act 23-520" eff="2020-12-07" path="§2|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-07" doc="D.C. Act 23-520" eff="2020-12-07" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-07" doc="D.C. Act 23-520" eff="2020-12-07" path="§2|(c)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
