<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<section xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify">
  <num>2-1210.52</num>
  <heading>Incarceration to Incorporation Entrepreneurship Program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established within the Department of Employment Services the Incarceration to Incorporation Entrepreneurship Program, a business development program for returning citizens, which shall be operated by DOES, in conjunction with the Department of Small and Local Business Development, to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Invest in for-profit and nonprofit businesses owned, operated, or managed by returning citizens;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide a program to assist a returning citizen in obtaining a general education development diploma;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide classes to improve math, reading, and writing abilities; 					(4) Provide business and microenterprise development training to include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Accounting;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Finance;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Administration;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Business planning;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Budgeting;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Marketing;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Business law;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Accessing startup capital, and other business startup topics as identified by the U.S. Small Business Administration and Certified Community Development Financial Institutions;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>Training and guidance on the certification process for becoming a certified business enterprise pursuant to the Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 2-1801.01
              <em>et seq</em>.); and
            </text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>Technology training;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Provide educational workshops and seminars on financial literacy;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Provide ongoing mentorship and support;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Place participants in apprenticeships at established businesses;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Provide monthly networking meetings with business leaders, such as:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Business owners;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Angel investors; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Heads of venture capital and investment firms; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Provide scholarships or grants for returning citizens to enroll in business classes at the University of the District of Columbia or the University of the District of Columbia Community College.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>DOES shall confer with other agencies, organizations, and individuals such as:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Office of the Deputy Mayor for Greater Economic Opportunity;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Workforce Investment Council;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Mayor's Office on Returning Citizen Affairs; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any other relevant agency or organization that DOES and DSLBD consider necessary to meet the objectives of this act.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "returning citizen" means a resident who was previously incarcerated.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-159" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3" type="History" />
  </annotations>
</section>