<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1403.16a</num>
  <heading>Civil actions by the Attorney General.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>During a period of time for which the Mayor has declared a public health emergency ("PHE") pursuant to <cite path="§7-2304.01">§ 7-2304.01</cite>, in a civil action initiated by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia ("Attorney General") for violations of this act, or a civil action arising in connection with the public health emergency, other than an action brought pursuant to section 307:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General may obtain:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Injunctive relief, as described in section 307;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Civil penalties, up to the amounts described in section 313(a)(1)(E-1), for each action or practice in violation of this act, and, in the context of a discriminatory advertisement, for each day the advertisement was posted; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any other form of relief described in section 313(a)(1); and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General may seek subpoenas for the production of documents and materials or for the attendance and testimony of witnesses under oath, or both, which shall contain the information described in section 110a(b) of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia Clarification and Elected Term Amendment Act of 2010, effective October 22, 2015 (D.C. Law 21-36; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.88d(b)) ("Act"), and shall follow the procedures described in section 110a(c), (d), and (e) of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 1-301.88d(c), (d), and (e)); provided, that the subpoenas are not directed to a District government official or entity.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-04-10" doc="D.C. Act 23-286" eff="2020-04-10" path="§303" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
