<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1599.04</num>
  <heading>The Director of the Coordinating Committee.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Coordinating Committee shall be appointed to the Excepted Service as a statutory officeholder pursuant to <cite path="§1-609.08">§ 1-609.08</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Director shall report to the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>At minimum, the Director shall meet the following qualifications:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be familiar with the District public education system and member agencies;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Have project management experience; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Possess expertise providing guidance and best practices for educating youth involved in the foster care and criminal justice systems.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor is encouraged to consult with the Coordinating Committee on the specific qualifications and job description for this position.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Director shall have the following duties:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be responsible for and oversee the daily operations of the Coordinating Committee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Supervise Coordinating Committee staff;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Recommend and institute internal policies, procedures, and processes for the Coordinating Committee to ensure efficient operations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Lead and coordinate the Coordinating Committee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Provide ongoing technical assistance to members of the Coordinating Committee in carrying out the recommendations in accordance with best practices, local laws, and federal laws;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Be responsible for drafting the annual report mandated pursuant to <cite path="§2-1599.06|(c)">§ 2-1599.06(c)</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Share best practices from around the country and facilitate knowledge sharing with other states and jurisdictions to increase knowledge of best practices and intervention strategies; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Work with executive agencies, community stakeholders, and the Coordinating Committee to create, coordinate, and implement the strategic plan created pursuant to <cite path="§2-1599.06|(d)">§ 2-1599.06(d)</cite> to improve educational outcomes for students in the care of D.C.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-303" eff="2019-04-11" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-303" eff="2019-04-11" path="§5" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
