<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1599.06</num>
  <heading>Duties and responsibilities of the Coordinating Committee.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Coordinating Committee shall provide leadership in the development of strategies and policies that guide the implementation of the District's policies and programs to improve educational outcomes for students in the care of D.C.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To accomplish the goals of subsection (a) of this section, the Coordinating Committee shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Assess current efforts in place to educate students in the care of D.C.;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Cooperate with and support members in fully implementing all relevant agreements and memorandum of understanding;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Review existing data collection and sharing efforts within and across agencies and make recommendations regarding the exchange and sharing of data for students in the care of D.C.; provided, that all such recommendations comply with local and federal law;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Establish an effective system for monitoring the progress of general education and special education for students in the care of D.C.;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Determine educational outcomes for students in the care of D.C., build capacity to track and measure outcomes, and implement strategies in accordance with the strategic plan created pursuant to subsection (d) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Foster collaborative relationships with agency counterparts in Maryland and Virginia for students in the care of D.C. who are placed outside of the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Make recommendations concerning the coordination of the activities, implementation of practices, strategies, or programs, and the mobilization of the resources of member agencies to improve educational outcomes for students in the care of D.C.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Coordinating Committee shall report, within 24 months following October 1, 2019, and on an annual basis thereafter, on the status and progress of each member agency on fulfilling the goal in subsection (a) of this section and the strategic plan referenced in subsection (d) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Coordinating Committee shall transmit a publicly-available report to the Mayor and the Council.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Within 12 months after October 1, 2019, and every 4 years thereafter, the Coordinating Committee shall draft and approve a strategic plan that encourages interagency and community coordination and improves educational outcomes for students in the care of D.C. At minimum, the plan required by this subsection shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Clearly articulate a vision statement for students in the care of D.C.;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>State the goals and operational priorities of member agencies for improving educational outcomes for students in the care of D.C.;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Include a District-wide needs assessment that takes into account existing data;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Establish a timeline for implementing the strategic plan;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Include an analysis of strategies that have been successful in improving educational outcomes for students in custody of the government;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Be developed pursuant to a process that will identify, prioritize, and target needs for services for students in the care of D.C.;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Provide estimates of the costs of carrying out various components of the plan; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Recommend policy and legislative changes, if needed, to improve educational outcomes for students in the care of D.C.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1599.06" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§2-1599.06">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-303" path="">D.C. Law 22-303</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-303" path="§9">§ 9 of D.C. Law 22-303</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-303" path="§7">§ 7 of D.C. Law 22-303</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-303" eff="2019-04-11" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-303" eff="2019-04-11" path="§7" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 22-303" path="§7" codified:display="Note" app="2019-04-11" eff="2019-04-11">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-303" path="">D.C. Law 22-303</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-303" path="§9">§ 9 of D.C. Law 22-303</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-303" path="§7">§ 7 of D.C. Law 22-303</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-16" path="§7176" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-09-11">
          Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-303">D.C. Law 22-303</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-16" path="§7176">§ 7176 of D.C. Law 23-16</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-303" path="§9">§ 9 of D.C. Law 22-303</cite>. Therefore the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-303">D.C. Law 22-303</cite> has been implemented.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§7176" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
