<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1831.12</num>
  <heading>Chief Operating Officer and other personnel.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There shall be a Chief Operating Officer of the Office. The Chief Operating Officer shall be responsible for the administration of the Office subject to the supervision of the Chief Administrative Law Judge.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Chief Operating Officer shall be appointed by the Chief Administrative Law Judge to the Management Supervisory Service, and shall serve at the pleasure of the Chief Administrative Law Judge pursuant to <cite path="§1-609.54">§ 1-609.54</cite>. In making the appointment, the Chief Administrative Law Judge shall consider experience in administrative hearing procedures and operations. The Chief Operating Officer need not be an attorney and may not concurrently hold an appointment as an Administrative Law Judge appointed under the authority of <cite path="§2-1831.08|(b)">§ 2-1831.08(b)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If at the time of application the Chief Operating Officer claimed a hiring preference as a bona fide resident of the District of the Columbia, the Chief Operating Officer shall agree to maintain bona fide District residency for 7 consecutive years from the effective date of hire, pursuant to <cite path="§1-609.57">§ 1-609.57</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Office shall have a Clerk and may have deputy clerks who shall perform such duties as may be assigned to them. The Clerk and deputy clerks may be authorized to administer oaths, issue subpoenas, and perform other appropriate duties.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>With the approval of the Chief Administrative Law Judge, the Chief Operating Officer may appoint and fix the salary of any attorney and non-attorney personnel appointed pursuant to the authority of <cite path="2|18A">this chapter</cite>, other than Administrative Law Judges. Law clerks and attorneys employed by the office in a capacity other than as an Administrative Law Judge shall be appointed to the Legal Service or Senior Executive Attorney Service.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Chief Operating Officer shall not have supervisory authority over any person appointed as an Administrative Law Judge.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-76" type="History" path="§15">Mar. 6, 2002, D.C. Law 14-76, § 15, 48 DCR 11442</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§1022|(e)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-07-20" eff="2017-07-20">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§1022|(e)">§ 1022(e) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104, July 20, 2017, 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-07-20" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" eff="2017-07-20" path="§1022|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§1022|(e)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-10-24" eff="2017-10-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§1022|(e)">§ 1022(e) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167, Oct. 24, 2017, 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-10-24" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" eff="2017-10-24" path="§1022|(e)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§1022|(e)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
