<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-218.15</num>
  <heading>Living Wage Certification Program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Living Wage Certification Program ("program") within the Department, which shall be administered by an organization selected in accordance with subsection (b) of this section ("administrator") and funded by a grant from the Department, that will certify employers that meet the requirements of the program established by this section and pursuant to this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Select the administrator through the competitive bid process;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Establish the criteria to be eligible for the grant and the selection as administrator; provided, that the administrator shall be a nonprofit organization located in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Issue a request for proposals no later than December 31, 2018; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Enter into a grant agreement with the bid awardee to serve as administrator in accordance with the requirements of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Under the program, the administrator shall certify an employer that applies for certification and that shows, to the satisfaction of the administrator, that the employer:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Pays its employees, including independent contractors, a living wage;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Commits to paying its employees and independent contractors a living wage for the duration of the certification;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Maintains its primary office in the District;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Possesses a current license pursuant to <cite path="47|28">Chapter 28 of Title 47</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Certifies that at least a majority of its owners are District residents or that at least a majority of its employees are District residents.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The administrator shall develop criteria to verify that the employer meets each criterion set forth in this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Certification shall be valid for 3 years.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To maintain certification and obtain recertification, a certified employer must demonstrate that it continues to meet the criteria set forth in subsection (c) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A certified employer shall have 3 months to increase its employees' wages to match an increase in the living wage mandated under <cite path="2|2|X-A">subchapter X-A of this chapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The administrator shall maintain a public list of all certified employers.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The administrator shall create a unique logo to designate an employer as certified under this section and shall provide the employer with digital and physical copies of the logo for display and promotional purposes.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Department may consider combining the list maintained pursuant to subsection (e)(1) of this section with any similar list created under the Made in DC program, established in <cite path="2|12|IV-B">subchapter IV-B of Chapter 12 of this title</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "living wage" shall have the same meaning as provided in <cite path="§2-220.02|(4)">§ 2-220.02(4)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History" path="§2315">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 2315</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="§2182|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§2182|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2018-07-30" eff="2018-07-30">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§2182|(b)">§ 2182(b) of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-434, July 30, 2018, 65 DCR 8200)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" eff="2018-10-03" path="§2182|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§2182|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2018-10-03" eff="2018-10-03">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§2182|(b)">§ 2182(b) of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-458, Oct. 3, 2018, 65 DCR 11212)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§2182|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-22" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2019-03-27" eff="2019-03-27">For temporary (90 days) creation of § 2-218.16, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-22" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Emergency Amendment Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-22, Mar. 27, 2019, 66 DCR 3991)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-03-27" doc="D.C. Act 23-22" eff="2019-03-27" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 23-7" path="§2|(c)" codified:display="Note" app="2019-06-04" eff="2019-06-04">For temporary (225 days) creation of § 2-218.16, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-7" path="§2|(c)">§ 2(c) of Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 2019 (D.C. Law 23-7, June 4, 2019, 66 DCR 5250)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-06-04" doc="D.C. Law 23-7" eff="2019-06-04" path="§2|(c)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
