<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-222.02</num>
  <heading>Indirect cost compensation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise provided for by law, nonprofit organizations shall be compensated for indirect costs incurred in provision of goods or performance of services within the terms of any grant or contract with the District pursuant to the nonprofit organization's unexpired NICRA. If a nonprofit organization does not have an unexpired NICRA, the nonprofit organization may elect to be compensated for indirect costs:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>As calculated using a de minimis rate of 10% of all direct costs under the grant or contract;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By negotiating a new percentage indirect cost rate with the awarding agency;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>As calculated with the same percentage indirect cost rate as the nonprofit organization negotiated with any District agency within the past 2 years; however nonprofit organizations may request to renegotiate indirect cost rates pursuant to subsection (c) [(b)] of this section; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>As calculated with a percentage rate and base amount, determined by a certified public accountant using the nonprofit organization's audited financial statements from the immediately preceding fiscal year, pursuant to the OMB Uniform Guidance, and certified in writing by the certified public accountant.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the funding for a grant or contract comes from a federal agency, indirect costs shall be compensated consistent with the requirements for pass-through entities in 2 C.F.R. ยง 200.331, or any successor regulations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each contract and grant awarded by the District shall include an indirect cost compensation clause that obligates the contractor or grantee to pay indirect costs to any nonprofit organization subcontractor or subgrantee at the same rate as the nonprofit organization would receive as a contractor or grantee with the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to foundations, hospitals, colleges, or universities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of this title</cite>[,] may issue rules to implement the provisions of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-185" eff="2021-03-16" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-185" eff="2021-03-16" path="ยง3" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
