<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-281.02</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by temporary legislation that will expire on March 10, 2022. To view the text of this section after the expiration of the temporary legislation, click this link: <cite path="§2-281.02(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Establishment of the Equity Impact Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall select a Fund Manager to establish and manage a fund outside the District of Columbia government to be known as the Equity Impact Fund ("Fund").</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development shall provide, upon selection of the Fund Manager, a grant of $1.25 million in the aggregate in Fiscal Year 2021 to the Fund Manager for deposit by the Fund Manager into the Fund ("District's initial grant").</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be funded by money appropriated for the purposes of the Fund and granted by the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development to the Fund Manager, other amounts, if any, received by the District or Fund Manager for deposit into the Fund, and any monies received as gifts, grants, donations, and awards.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used for the following purposes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To facilitate investment in eligible businesses that lack access to capital;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To make investments into eligible businesses based on an investment strategy determined by the Fund Manager; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To administer the Fund, including the provision of technical assistance to eligible businesses; provided, that no more than 15% of the District's initial investment may be used annually for this purpose.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="II" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-149" eff="2020-12-03" path="§2163" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-61" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-05-03" eff="2021-05-03">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-61" path="§2|(b)">§ 2(b) of Equitable Impact Assistance for Local Businesses Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-61, May 3, 2021, 68 DCR 004821)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-05-03" doc="D.C. Act 24-61" eff="2021-05-03" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-07-28" doc="D.C. Law 24-11" eff="2021-07-28" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-07-28" doc="D.C. Law 24-11" eff="2021-07-28" path="§2|(b)|(1)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-07-28" doc="D.C. Law 24-11" eff="2021-07-28" path="§2|(b)|(1)|(B)|(i)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-07-28" doc="D.C. Law 24-11" eff="2021-07-28" path="§2|(b)|(1)|(B)|(ii)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-07-28" doc="D.C. Law 24-11" eff="2021-07-28" path="§2|(b)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-07-28" doc="D.C. Law 24-11" eff="2021-07-28" path="§2|(b)|(c)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Temporary Legislation" doc="D.C. Law 24-11" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-07-28" eff="2021-07-28">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-11" path="§2|(b)">§ 2(b) of Equitable Impact Assistance for Local Businesses Temporary Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Law 24-11, July 28, 2021, 68 DCR 005829)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
