<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-356.05</num>
  <heading>Estimate of construction costs.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An estimate of costs shall be prepared by the contracting officer for each proposed contract, contract modification, or change order to be issued in connection with a construction project and anticipated to exceed $100,000.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The estimate shall be prepared in detail, as though the District were competing for the contract, and shall not be based solely on the estimates or actual costs of similar construction projects.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The estimate shall be made available to the contracting officer for use in preparation of the contract solicitation and in the determination of price reasonableness in awarding a contract.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Access to materials gathered or created for the estimate, and the overall amount of the estimate, shall be limited to District personnel or agents of the District whose official duties require knowledge regarding the estimate.  These materials and the overall amount of the estimate shall not be disclosed, except as otherwise permitted by law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Within 90 days of October 8, 2016, the Mayor, pursuant to <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of this title</cite>, shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this section.
            </text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-371" type="History" path="§605">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-371, § 605</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-158" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3|(l)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 21-504" path="§3|(l)" codified:display="Note" app="2016-10-13" eff="2016-10-13">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 21-504" path="§3|(l)">§ 3(l) of Procurement Integrity, Transparency, and Accountability Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-504, Oct. 13, 2016, 63 DCR 12942)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-13" doc="D.C. Act 21-504" eff="2016-10-13" path="§3|(l)" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
