<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-361.04</num>
  <heading>Transparency in contracting.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The CPO shall establish and maintain on the Internet a website containing publicly available information regarding District procurement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The website established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall contain, at a minimum, the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Information regarding the statutes and rules that govern procurement for all District agencies, including those exempt from the authority of the CPO.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A webpage with links to each District government website containing active solicitations for goods or services in an amount in excess of $100,000, including websites maintained by District agencies exempt from the authority of the CPO.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Each website linked to by the webpage provided for in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall provide clear instructions on how to respond electronically to each solicitation, unless a solicitation cannot be responded to electronically, in which case the website shall provide clear instructions on how to respond to the solicitation through non-electronic means.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A database containing information regarding each contract executed by the District for an amount equal to or greater than $100,000, including each such contract made by a District agency exempt from the authority of the CPO pursuant to <cite path="§2-351.05">§ 2-351.05</cite>.  For each contract contained in the database, the database shall include a unique identifier and, at a minimum, the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A copy of the executed contract;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>All determinations and findings related to the contract;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>All contract modifications, change orders, or amendments associated with the contract;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>All solicitation documents for the contract, including all requests for proposals and invitations for bids, and any amendments of such documents; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The contract summary documents for the contract that are submitted to the Council for its review.</text>
      </para>
      <para placeholder="Not Funded">
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Not Funded.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Placeholders identifying any portions of the items set forth in paragraph (3) of this subsection withheld as confidential by the CPO pursuant to <cite path="§2-354.17">§ 2-354.17</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A list of each contract executed by the District for an amount less than $100,000, which shall include, for each contract, the vendor name, a description of the goods or services purchased, and the dollar amount of the contract.</text>
    </para>
    <para placeholder="Repealed">
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Agencies not subject to the authority of the CPO shall transmit the information required by this section to the CPO for posting on the Internet.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-371" type="History" path="§1104">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-371, § 1104, 58 DCR 1185</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-158" eff="2016-10-08" path="§3|(q)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 21-504" path="§3|(p)" codified:display="Note" app="2016-10-13" eff="2016-10-13">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 21-504" path="§3|(p)">§ 3(p) of Procurement Integrity, Transparency, and Accountability Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-504, Oct. 13, 2016, 63 DCR 12942)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-13" doc="D.C. Act 21-504" eff="2016-10-13" path="§3|(p)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-07-03" doc="D.C. Law 22-121" eff="2018-07-03" path="§3|(b)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-07-03" doc="D.C. Law 22-121" eff="2018-07-03" path="§3|(b)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2019-03-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" eff="2019-03-13" path="§10|(a)|(1)|(A)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="notfunded" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" eff="2019-03-13" path="§8|(b)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="notfunded" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" eff="2019-03-13" path="§8|(b)|(2)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="notfunded" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" eff="2019-03-13" path="§8|(b)|(2)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="notfunded" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" eff="2019-03-13" path="§8|(b)|(2)|(C)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§10" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2019-03-13" eff="2019-03-13"><cite doc="D.C. Law 22-250" path="§10|(b)">Section 10(b) of D.C. Law 22-250</cite> required that the amendments made to this section by D.C. Law 22-250, (1) Apply as of November 4, 2020; and (2) Not apply to contracts, as defined in D.C. Official Code § 1-1161.01(10C)(A)(ii)), including those contracts' option periods or similar contract extensions or modifications, sought, entered into, or executed before November 4, 2020.
            </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-03-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-250" eff="2019-03-13" path="§10" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§1043|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§1104" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
