<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-578</num>
  <heading>Record of meetings.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All meetings of public bodies, whether open or closed, shall be recorded by electronic means, and the recording shall be preserved for a minimum of 5 years; provided, that if a recording is not feasible, detailed minutes of the meeting shall be taken and preserved for a minimum of 5 years.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Copies of records shall be made available for public inspection according to the following schedule; provided, that a record, or a portion of a record, may be withheld under the standard established for closed meetings pursuant to <cite path="§2-575|(b)">§ 2-575(b)</cite>:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A copy of the minutes of a meeting shall be made available for public inspection as soon as practicable, but no later than 3 business days after the meeting, or in the case of a board of trustees for a public charter school, no later than 30 business days after the meeting.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A copy of the full record, including any recording or transcript, shall be made available for public inspection as soon as practicable, but no later than 7 business days after the meeting.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-614" type="History" path="§408">Oct. 21, 1968, Pub. L. 90-614, title IV, § 408</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-350" type="History">as added Mar. 31, 2011, D.C. Law 18-350, § 2, 58 DCR 734</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-05-10" doc="D.C. Law 22-313" eff="2019-05-10" path="§4" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-404" eff="2020-08-19" path="§4057|(d)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-405" path="§809|(d)" codified:display="Note" app="2020-08-19" eff="2020-08-19">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-405" path="§809|(d)">§ 809(d) of Coronavirus Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2020 [Effective August 19, 2020 through October 8, 2020] (D.C. Act 23-405, Aug. 19, 2020, 67 DCR 10235)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-405" eff="2020-08-19" path="§809|(d)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-09" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" eff="2020-10-09" path="§809|(d)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The schedule provided in paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection shall be tolled during a period for which a public health emergency has been declared pursuant to <cite path="§7-2304.01">§ 7-2304.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
</section>
