<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-651.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of <cite path="2|6|V">this subchapter</cite>, the term:
    </text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>"Electronic" means relating to technology having electrical, digital, magnetic, wireless, optical, electromagnetic, or similar capabilities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>"Legal material" means, whether or not in effect:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The acts and resolutions of the Council;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia Official Code;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia Municipal Regulations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Other legal materials designated by the Mayor by rule; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Other legal materials designated by the Council by resolution.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>"Official publisher" means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>For the acts and resolutions of the Council, the Secretary to the Council;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>For the District of Columbia Official Code, the General Counsel to the Council;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>For the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, the Administrator of the District of Columbia Office of Documents, established by <cite path="ยง2-611">ยง 2-611</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>For other legal material designated by the Mayor pursuant to paragraph (2)(D) of this section, the Mayor; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>For other legal material designated by the Council pursuant to paragraph (2)(E) of this section, the Secretary to the Council.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>"Publish" means to display, present, or release to the public, or cause to be displayed, presented, or released to the public, by the official publisher.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>"Record" means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>"State" means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2017-04-07" doc="D.C. Law 21-251" eff="2017-04-07" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-04-07" doc="D.C. Law 21-251" eff="2017-04-07" path="ยง2" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
