<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<section xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify">
  <num>4</num>
  <heading>Incarceration to Incorporation Entrepreneurship Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Incarceration to Incorporation Entrepreneurship Fund, which shall be administered by the Office of the Deputy Mayor for Greater Economic Opportunity in accordance with subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Up to $10 million from the following sources shall be deposited into the Fund:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Funds appropriated for the purposes of this act;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Donations from the public;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Donations from private entities; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Funds provided through a sponsorship agreement.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used to implement, operate, and administer IIEP.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall not be used for any other purpose other than for the purposes of this act.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund, and interested earned, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be subject to a yearly audit by the Office of the District of Columbia Auditor and the Office of the Chief Financial Officer.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-159" eff="2016-10-08" path="" type="History" />
  </annotations>
</section>