<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>26-510.04</num>
  <heading>Involuntary merger of credit union.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if the Commissioner determines that an emergency requiring expeditious action exists with respect to a District credit union, other alternatives are not reasonably available, and the public interest, including the interests of the members of the District credit union, would best be served by taking the following action, the Commissioner may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Initiate the involuntary merger of a District credit union that is insolvent or is in danger of insolvency with any other District credit union;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If authorized under, and to the extent consistent with, applicable federal or state law:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Initiate actions designed to result in the involuntary merger of a District credit union that is insolvent or is in danger of insolvency with any federal or foreign credit union; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Authorize a District credit union, federal credit union, or foreign credit union to purchase any of the assets of, or assume any of the liabilities of, a District credit union that is insolvent or in danger of insolvency; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Authorize a financial institution whose deposits or accounts are insured to purchase any of the assets of, or to assume any of the liabilities of, a District credit union that is insolvent or in danger of insolvency; except, that before exercising this authority, the Commissioner shall attempt to effect a merger with, or purchase and assumption, by another District credit union, federal credit union, or foreign credit union as provided in paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For purposes of the authority contained in this section, insured share and deposit accounts of the District credit union undergoing an involuntary merger may, upon consummation of the purchase and assumption, be converted to insured deposits or other comparable accounts in the acquiring institution.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-86" eff="2020-05-06" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-86" eff="2020-05-06" path="ยง1004" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
