<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>26-510.09</num>
  <heading>Records of the Department.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Information from the records of the Department related to District credit unions shall only be disclosed as required by law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A copy of any document on file with the Department that is certified by the Commissioner as being a true copy may be introduced as evidence in any court in the District as if it were the original.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The following documents are confidential and privileged and not subject to public disclosure:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Examination reports, as defined in <cite path="ยง26-510.07">ยง 26-510.07</cite>, and related information from insurers or other regulators;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Business plans and other proprietary information of a District credit union, and its subsidiaries or affiliates;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Reports of investigations; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Notices related to enforcement actions and consent orders.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Examination reports furnished by the Commissioner remain the property of the Department. No person to whom an examination report is furnished, or any officer, director, or employee thereof may disclose or make public the examination report or information contained in the examination report except information that is already in the public domain. Violation of this subsection constitutes a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of not more than $1,000 for each violation, by imprisonment for not more than one year, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Upon notice to the Commission, a party in a civil action in which an examination report or information discussed in this section is sought to be discovered or used as evidence may petition the court for an in-camera review of the examination report or information. The court may permit discovery and introduction of only those portions of the examination report or information that are relevant and otherwise unobtainable by the requesting party.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-86" eff="2020-05-06" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-86" eff="2020-05-06" path="ยง1009" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
