<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>26-509.02</num>
  <heading>Voluntary merger of credit unions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A District credit union may, with the written approval of the Commissioner and subject to all applicable local and federal laws and regulations, merge with one or more other District credit unions, foreign credit unions, or federal credit unions. A District credit union merging with another District credit union may do so regardless of whether the credit unions serve the same field of membership.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>When a District credit union merges with one or more other District credit unions, the entities shall either designate one of them as the continuing credit union, or they shall structure a new credit union and designate it as the new credit union. All participating credit unions, other than the continuing or new credit union, shall be designated as merging credit unions.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>When a District credit union merges with one or more foreign credit unions or federal credit unions, the District credit union shall be subject to all applicable local and federal laws and regulations governing the chartering jurisdiction.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>To merge, participating credit unions shall prepare a merger plan. The merger plan which has been approved by a majority of the directors of all of the participating credit unions shall be submitted to the appropriate regulatory authorities for preliminary approval by the regulatory authority. If the merger plan includes the creation of a new credit union, all documents required by <cite path="26|5|I">this subchapter</cite> for the chartering of a new District credit union shall be submitted as part of the merger plan. Each participating credit union, except the continuing credit union, shall also submit in writing to the Commissioner:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The time and place of the meeting of the board of directors at which the merger plan was agreed upon;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The vote of directors in favor of the adoption of the merger plan; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A copy of the resolution or other action by which the merger plan was agreed upon.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Each merging District credit union shall conduct a membership vote on its participation in the plan at a special meeting called for that purpose, by mail ballot, or by electronic means. Members shall be provided written notice of the meeting, which shall state the purpose of the meeting, at least 10 days but not more than 30 days prior to the meeting.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a majority of the voting members approve the merger plan, the District credit union shall submit a record of that fact to the Commissioner, indicating the vote by which the members approved the merger plan and copies of the notices provided to members, including copies of the membership meeting notice and mail or electronic ballot if the vote was conducted by mail or electronic means.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner shall approve a merger plan after determining that the requirements of subsection (d) of this section have been met. If the merger plan includes the creation of a new District credit union, the new District credit union shall be approved pursuant to <cite path="26|5|I|B">part B of this subchapter</cite>. The Commissioner shall notify all participating credit unions of the Commissioner's action on the merger plan.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Each merging credit union shall cease operations within 90 days of approval of a merger plan by the Commissioner. All property, property rights, and members' interests in each merging credit union shall vest in the continuing or new credit union, as applicable, without deed, endorsement, or other instrument of transfer. All debts, obligations, and liabilities of each merging credit union shall be deemed to have been assumed by the continuing or new credit union. The rights and privileges of the members of each merging credit union shall remain intact. If a person is a member of more than one of the participating credit unions that person shall be entitled to only one set of membership rights in the continuing or new credit union.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>If the continuing or new credit union is chartered by another state or territory of the United States, it shall be subject to the requirements of <cite path="ยง26-502.10">ยง 26-502.10</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-86" eff="2020-05-06" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-86" eff="2020-05-06" path="ยง902" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
