<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>26-510.06</num>
  <heading>Conservatorship.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the Commissioner determines that a District credit union is engaging in a materially unsafe or unsound practice, the Commissioner may, at the Commissioner's sole discretion and without advance notice:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Appoint an insuring organization or any other person as conservator, that shall immediately take possession and control of the business and assets of the District credit union, represent the best interests of the District credit union members, and be vested with the full power of management of the District credit union.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Petition the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to appoint a receiver for the District credit union, in accordance with <cite path="§26-1401.19">§ 26-1401.19</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "materially unsafe and unsound practice" means a practice where:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Immediate action is necessary to conserve the assets of a District credit union or to protect the interests of the members of the District credit union; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>A District credit union, by resolution of its board of directors, has consented to the Commissioner's action; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The Commissioner receives written notification from the appropriate authority that a director or an officer of the District credit union has been convicted of a criminal offense under 18 U.S.C. § 1956 or 1957;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>There is a willful violation by a District credit union or a director or officer of the District credit union of a cease and desist order issued by the Commissioner; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>A District credit union or a director or officer of the District credit union has engaged in the concealment of books, papers, records, or assets of the District credit union, or has refused to submit books, papers, records, or other sources of information relating to the affairs of the District credit union for inspection to any examiner or lawful agent of the Commissioner.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A District credit union may apply to the appropriate court for an order requiring the Commissioner to show cause why the Commissioner or the conservator designee should not be enjoined from continuing possession and control not later than 15 days after the date on which the conservator takes possession and control of the business and assets of a District credit union pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the conservator may maintain possession and control of the business and assets of the District credit union and may operate the District credit union until:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Commissioner permits the District credit union's officials to continue business, subject to terms and conditions the Commissioner imposes; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The District credit union is involuntarily merged or involuntarily liquidated in accordance with <cite path="§26-510.05">§ 26-510.05</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may appoint any person that the Commissioner considers necessary to assist the conservator in carrying out the duties of the conservator under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A conservator or receiver may terminate or adopt any executory contract to which the credit union may be a party, including leases of real or personal property, within 6 months after obtaining knowledge of the existence of the contract or lease. Any provision in the contract or lease that provides for damages, other than actual direct compensatory damages determined as of the date of appointment of the conservator or receiver, shall not be binding on the conservator, receiver, or District credit union.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>All expenses incurred by a conservator in exercising the authority of that office under this section with respect to any District credit union shall be paid out of the assets of the District credit union; except, that the Commissioner may waive all or a part of these expenses.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-86" eff="2020-05-06" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-86" eff="2020-05-06" path="§1006" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
