<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>26-509.01</num>
  <heading>Voluntary Liquidation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A District credit union may, by a 2/3 vote of the board of directors and in the manner described in this section, elect to voluntarily dissolve and liquidate its affairs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The board shall notify the Commissioner of its vote to voluntarily dissolve and liquidate its affairs no later than 10 days after the vote. The notification shall be in writing and set forth the reasons for the proposed liquidation and a plan for liquidation, including any suspension of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Payments on accounts;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Withdrawals of funds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Transfers to loan accounts;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Investments;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>New loans; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Other similar financial transactions.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Upon documentation that the District credit union has complied with this section, the Commissioner shall certify that the District credit union has complied with this section and shall forward a copy of the certification to the District credit union.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The terms and conditions of a liquidation plan approved under this section shall go into effect immediately upon approval by the District credit union's members, pursuant to subsection (e) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Voluntary liquidation requires approval by a vote of 2/3 of the members present, either in person, by mail ballot, or by electronic means, at a regular meeting that specifically included the liquidation issue on the notice or by a special meeting called specifically to vote on the liquidation issue with a minimum of 25% of the total membership voting. When authorization for liquidation is to be obtained at a meeting of the members, notice in writing shall be given to each member, by first-class mail, at least 10 days, but not more than 30 days, prior to the meeting.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If liquidation is approved, the board of directors shall appoint a liquidating agent or committee for the purpose of conserving and collecting the assets, closing the affairs of the District credit union, and distributing the assets as required by <cite path="26|5|I">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A liquidating District credit union shall continue in existence for the purpose of discharging its debts, collecting on loans, distributing its assets, and doing all acts necessary to terminate operations. The liquidating District credit union may sue and be sued for the purpose of enforcing debts and obligations until the liquidating District credit union's affairs are fully concluded.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The liquidating agent or committee shall distribute the assets of the District credit union or the proceeds of any disposition of the assets in the sequence described in <cite path="ยง26-510.05|(b)">ยง 26-510.05(b)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The liquidating agent shall execute a certificate of dissolution when the liquidating agent or committee determines that all assets from which there is a reasonable expectancy of recovery have been liquidated and distributed as set forth in this section. The certificate of dissolution shall be executed on a form prescribed by the Commissioner and filed, together with all pertinent books and records of the liquidating District credit union, with the Commissioner.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The liquidating agent or committee shall, within 3 years after issuance of a certificate of dissolution, discharge the debts of the District credit union, collect and distribute its assets, and do all other acts required to windup its business.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Commissioner may issue a cease and desist order against the liquidating agent or committee and appoint a new liquidating agent to complete the liquidation under the Commissioner's direction and control if the Commissioner determines that the liquidating agent or committee has failed to make reasonable progress toward liquidating the District credit union's affairs and distributing its assets, or has violated <cite path="26|5|I">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Commissioner shall fill any vacancy caused by the resignation, death, illness, removal, desertion, or incapacity to function of the Commissioner's appointed liquidating agent.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(k)</num>
    <text>Any funds that represent unclaimed dividends and shares in liquidation at the end of the liquidation shall remain in the hands of the board of directors, the liquidating agent, or committee, and shall be deposited by them, together with all the District credit union's books and papers, with the Commissioner. The Commissioner shall deposit the funds with the D.C. Treasurer.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-86" eff="2020-05-06" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-86" eff="2020-05-06" path="ยง901" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
