<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>26-506.12</num>
  <heading>Share and deposit insurance.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A District credit union shall apply for and obtain insurance on its members' share and deposit accounts as provided by NCUA or comparable insurance approved by the Commissioner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No District credit union shall be granted a charter by the Commissioner unless the District credit union has applied for and obtained insurance of its members' share and deposit accounts as provided by this section or received a written commitment to insure or guarantee member accounts.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A District credit union with debt and equity capital consisting primarily of funds received from other credit unions and any membership share issued by a District credit union shall not be subject to the requirements of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A District credit union that has been denied a commitment of insurance or guarantee of its members' share and deposit accounts or that has had that insurance or guarantee revoked, cancelled, or terminated shall, within 30 days of the effective date of the revocation, cancellation, or termination, commence steps to liquidate, merge with an insured credit union, or apply in writing to the Commissioner for an extension of time to obtain an insurance commitment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may grant one or more extensions of time in which to obtain the insurance commitment upon satisfactory evidence that the District credit union has made, or is making, a substantial effort to satisfy the conditions precedent to the issuance of an insurance commitment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>To permit NCUA or an authorized share guaranty corporation to assess the financial condition and performance of a District credit union, the Commissioner may provide NCUA or an authorized share guaranty corporation with any and all reports of examination conducted by the Commissioner, and copies of orders and notices issued by the Commissioner, regarding any District credit union under the Commissioner's supervision.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>NCUA or an authorized share guaranty corporation shall provide to the Commissioner copies of any reports of examinations conducted by NCUA or the authorized share guaranty corporation on a District credit union.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>In addition to the primary guaranteed amount, an authorized share guaranty corporation or other insurance company may provide an excess coverage guarantee for the benefit of those District credit unions that voluntarily elect to obtain an additional guarantee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may appoint NCUA or any official of an authorized share guaranty corporation as the liquidating agent of a District credit union. This appointment is limited to actions arising under §§ <cite path="§26-509.01">26-509.01</cite> and <cite path="§26-510.05">26-510.05</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-86" eff="2020-05-06" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-86" eff="2020-05-06" path="§612" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
