<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>26-505.03</num>
  <heading>Appointment of committees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The board of directors shall appoint an audit committee of no fewer than 3 members of the District credit union, who may, but need be, members of the board of directors. The board shall appoint the audit committee at an organizational meeting held within 30 days of each annual election of directors for the terms provided in the bylaws.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The board of directors may appoint other committees necessary or convenient to the operation of the District credit union.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Unless specifically prohibited by the bylaws, committee members may participate in and act at any meeting of the committee through the use of communications equipment; provided, that all persons participating in the meeting can speak with and hear each other at the same time. Participation in a meeting in this manner shall constitute attendance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Unless specifically prohibited by the bylaws, any action required by <cite path="26|5|I">this subchapter</cite> to be taken at a committee meeting, or any other action that may be taken at a committee meeting, may be taken without a meeting if all members of the committee sign a consent to the action in a writing that sets forth the action. Consent shall be evidenced by one or more written approvals, which describe the action taken and bear the signature of one or more committee members.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-86" eff="2020-05-06" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-86" eff="2020-05-06" path="ยง503" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
