<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>26-510.05</num>
  <heading>Involuntary liquidation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the Commissioner determines that a District credit union is bankrupt or insolvent, the Commissioner may issue a notice of involuntary liquidation, revoke the District credit union's charter, and appoint a liquidating agent.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The District credit union may request the appropriate court to stay execution of the action authorized by this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In the event of liquidation, the assets of the District credit union or the proceeds from any disposition of assets shall be applied and distributed in the following priority:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Secured creditors up to the value of their collateral;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Costs and expenses of liquidation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Wages due the employees of the District credit union;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Taxes owed to any government unit;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Debts, other than taxes, owed to the United States;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>General creditors, and secured creditors to the extent their claims exceed the value of their collateral;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Costs and expenses incurred by creditors in successfully opposing the release of the District credit union from certain debts as allowed by the Commissioner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Shareholders or depositors, to the extent of uninsured share or deposit accounts; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Members, to the extent of membership shares.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-86" eff="2020-05-06" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-05-06" doc="D.C. Law 23-86" eff="2020-05-06" path="ยง1005" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
