<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>23-1907</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"DC SANE Program" means the DC Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner Program that provides comprehensive medical forensic care to sexual assault victims, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The DC Forensic Nurse Examiners;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Child and Adolescent Protection Center; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any other entity within the District that is a member of the SART, or the multidisciplinary investigation team, described in <cite path="§4-1301.51">§ 4-1301.51</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Forensic nurse examiner" means a nurse with specialized training in medical forensic evidence collection who provides comprehensive medical forensic care to sexual assault victims and participates in the DC SANE Program.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Hospital" means a facility that provides 24-hour inpatient care, including diagnostic, therapeutic, and other health-related services, for a variety of physical or mental conditions, and may, in addition, provide outpatient services, particularly emergency care.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Interview" means any interview conducted by the MPD or other District agency with a sexual assault victim relating to the alleged sexual assault.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"MPD" means the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"OVSJG" means the Office of Victim Services and Justice Grants, established pursuant to Mayor's Order 2016-171.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>"PERK" means a Physical Evidence Recovery Kit used to collect and preserve physical evidence related to a sexual assault or alleged sexual assault.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>"SART" shall have the same meaning as provided in<cite path="§4-561.01|(11)"> § 4-561.01(11)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>"Sexual assault" means any of the following offenses: §§ <cite path="§22-1834">22-1834</cite> (sex trafficking of children); <cite path="§22-2704">22-2704</cite> (abducting or enticing child from his or her home for the purposes of prostitution; harboring such child); <cite path="§22-2705">22-2705</cite> (pandering; inducing or compelling an individual to engage in prostitution); <cite path="§22-2706">22-2706</cite> (compelling an individual to live life of prostitution against his or her will); <cite path="§22-2708">22-2708</cite> (causing spouse or domestic partner to live in prostitution); <cite path="§22-2709">22-2709</cite> (detaining an individual in disorderly house for debt there contracted); <cite path="§22-1901">22-1901</cite> (incest); <cite path="§22-3002">22-3002</cite> (first degree sexual abuse); <cite path="§22-3003">22-3003</cite> (second degree sexual abuse); <cite path="§22-3004">22-3004</cite> (third degree sexual abuse); <cite path="§22-3005">22-3005</cite> (fourth degree sexual abuse); <cite path="§22-3006">22-3006</cite> (misdemeanor sexual abuse); <cite path="§22-3008">22-3008</cite> (first degree child sexual abuse); <cite path="§22-3009">22-3009</cite> (second degree child sexual abuse); <cite path="§22-3009.01">22-3009.01</cite> (first degree sexual abuse of a minor); <cite path="§22-3009.02">22-3009.02</cite> (second degree sexual abuse of a minor); <cite path="§22-3009.03">22-3009.03</cite> (first degree sexual abuse of a secondary education student); <cite path="§22-3009.04">22-3009.04</cite> (second degree sexual abuse of a secondary education student); <cite path="§22-3010">22-3010</cite> (enticing a child or minor); <cite path="§22-3010.01">22-3010.01</cite> (misdemeanor sexual abuse of a child or minor); <cite path="§22-3010.02">22-3010.02</cite> (arranging for sexual contact with a real or fictitious child); <cite path="§22-3013">22-3013</cite> (first degree sexual abuse of a ward, patient, client, or prisoner); <cite path="§22-3014">22-3014</cite> (second degree sexual abuse of a ward, patient, client, or prisoner); <cite path="§22-3015">22-3015</cite> (first degree sexual abuse of a patient or client); <cite path="§22-3016">22-3016</cite> (second degree sexual abuse of a patient or client); <cite path="§22-3018">22-3018</cite> (attempts to commit sexual offenses); or <cite path="§22-3102">22-3102</cite> (knowingly using a minor in a sexual performance or promoting a sexual performance by a minor).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>"Sexual assault counselor" means an employee, contractor, or volunteer of a community-based organization serving sexual assault victims 13 years of age or older who:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Renders support, counseling, or assistance to a sexual assault victim;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Has undergone at least 40 hours of training related to sexual assault counseling using a curriculum approved by the OVSJG that includes instruction on:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The dynamics and history of sexual assault and gender-based violence;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Sex trafficking and other forms of commercial sexual exploitation;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Trauma resulting from sexual assault, gender-based violence, and commercial sexual exploitation;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Responding to the specific needs of youth sexual assault victims;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Responding to the specific needs of sexual assault victims with respect to their sexual orientation, gender identity, or gender expression;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>Trauma-informed care, crisis intervention, personal safety, and risk management; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vii)</num>
          <text>Cultural humility;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(viii)</num>
          <text>The sexual assault victim advocate dispatch system, developed by OVSJG and approved by the SART, pursuant to <cite path="§23-1909|(e)">§ 23-1909(e)</cite>; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ix)</num>
          <text>Services available to sexual assault victims, including how to access medical forensic care services available through the DC SANE Programs; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Is supervised by an individual who has a minimum of:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>5 years of experience rendering support, counseling, or assistance to sexual assault victims; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>3 years of experience rendering support, counseling, or assistance to sexual assault victims and an advanced degree in a related field.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>"Sexual assault victim" means any individual against whom a sexual assault has been committed or is alleged to have been committed, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Deceased individuals; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Representatives appointed by the court to exercise the rights and receive services on behalf of sexual assault victims who are under 18 years of age, incompetent, incapacitated, or deceased.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>"Sexual assault victim advocate" means an employee or contractor of a community-based organization whose director or their director's designee is a member of the SART and who:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is a sexual assault counselor; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Has undergone an additional 20 hours of training related to sexual assault victim advocacy using a curriculum approved by the OVSJG that includes instruction on:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The District's criminal justice system;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Crime victims' rights; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Avoiding the unauthorized practice of law.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>"Sexual Assault Victim's Rights Card" means a document, published by OVSJG in consultation with the SART, printed in the most widely spoken languages in the District, that advises sexual assault victims of their rights under <cite path="23|19|II">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>"Sexual assault youth victim advocate" means an employee or contractor of a community-based organization whose director or the director's designee is a member of the SART and who:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Qualifies as a sexual assault victim advocate; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Has undergone an additional 20 hours of training related to youth sexual assault victim advocacy using a curriculum approved by the OVSJG that includes instruction on:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Providing services to sexual assault victims under the age of 18, including the different needs of children and adolescents;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Navigating family dynamics in the context of providing services to children and adolescents who have experienced sexual assault;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>The co-occurrence of child abuse in children and adolescents who have experienced sexual assault; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Children's susceptibility to suggestive questioning, the impact suggestive questions have on criminal investigations and prosecutions, and techniques for minimizing the potential for suggestibility.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-139" type="History">Nov. 20, 2014, D.C. Law 20-139, § 101(c), 61 DCR 5913</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-57" path="§9|(a)" type="Applicability" history="false" display-template="" app="2020-03-03" eff="2020-03-03"><cite doc="D.C. Law 23-57" path="§9|(a)">Section 9(a) of D.C. Law 23-57</cite> provided that the amendments made to this section by Law 23-57 shall apply as of October 1, 2020.  Therefore those amendments shall be implemented for this section on October 1, 2020.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-03-03" doc="D.C. Law 23-57" eff="2020-03-03" path="§9|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-12-20" doc="D.C. Law 23-57" eff="2020-03-03" path="§8|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-14" doc="D.C. Act 23-412" eff="2020-10-14" path="§3" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Act 23-412" path="§3" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2020-10-14" eff="2020-10-14"><cite doc="D.C. Act 23-412" path="§3">Section 3 of D.C. Act 23-412</cite> provided that the amendments made to this section by Law 23-57 shall apply as of January 1, 2021.  Therefore those amendments shall be implemented for this section on January 1, 2021.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-552" eff="2020-12-22" path="§3" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Act 23-552" path="§3" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2020-12-22" eff="2020-12-22"><cite doc="D.C. Act 23-552" path="§3">Section 3 of D.C. Act 23-552</cite> provided that the amendments made to this section by Law 23-57 shall apply as of January 1, 2021.  Therefore those amendments shall be implemented for this section on January 1, 2021.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-274" eff="2021-04-27" path="§402" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-274" path="§402" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2021-04-27" eff="2021-04-27"><cite doc="D.C. Law 23-274" path="§402">Section 402 of D.C. Law 23-274</cite> provided that the amendments made to this section by Law 23-57 shall apply as of January 1, 2021.
    </annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
