<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<section xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify">
  <num>103</num>
  <heading>Publication of moving infraction data.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To the extent available, the Mayor shall publish online, at least once per month, the following information related to all notices of infractions issued for moving infractions in the preceding month:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The date and time of the moving infraction;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The location, by ward, block or intersection, and coordinates, where the moving infraction occurred;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Police Service Area in which the moving infraction occurred;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The agency that issued the notice of infraction;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Whether the notice of infraction was issued in person or by use of the automated traffic enforcement program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The provision of law violated;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The age of the driver of the motor vehicle;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The jurisdiction from which the driver's license was issued;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The jurisdiction in which the motor vehicle involved in the moving infraction is registered; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The year, make, model, and type of the motor vehicle that committed the moving infraction.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If complete data about a notice of infraction is not available at the time of publication, the Mayor shall publish the information that is available at the time of publication, and update the data as additional information becomes available.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-155" eff="2016-10-08" path="" type="History" />
  </annotations>
</section>