<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-1951.04</num>
  <heading>Publication of information relating to permits for the occupation of public space, public rights of way, and public structures.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>DDOT shall publish on its website, at least once per week, the following information related to permits for the occupation of public space, public rights of way, and public structures issued pursuant to <cite path="§10-1141.03">§ 10-1141.03</cite> ("permit"), in the preceding week that would block a sidewalk, bicycle lane, or other public pedestrian or bicycle path:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The location of the public space, public right of way, or public structure affected by the issuance of the permit, by ward and block or intersection;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A description of the public space, public right of way, or public structure affected by the issuance of the permit, including whether the permit closes a sidewalk, bicycle lane, or other public pedestrian or bicycle path;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The duration for which the portion of a sidewalk, bicycle lane, or other public pedestrian or bicycle path will be closed, including the start and end date for the closure;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A brief explanation of the reason for issuing the permit to close a portion of a sidewalk, bicycle lane, or other public pedestrian or bicycle path; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A description of or plan showing any safe accommodation provided for pedestrians and bicyclists, as required by <cite path="§10-1141.03|(f)">§ 10-1141.03(f)</cite>, or, in the event that a safe accommodation is not provided for pedestrians and bicyclists, an explanation for the absence of a safe accommodation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If complete data about the permit is not available at the time of publication, DDOT shall publish the information that is available at the time of publication, and update the data as additional information becomes available.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-155" eff="2016-10-08" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-155" eff="2016-10-08" path="§104" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-03-29" doc="D.C. Law 22-77" eff="2018-03-29" path="§2|(c)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-03-29" doc="D.C. Law 22-77" eff="2018-03-29" path="§2|(c)|(2)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
