<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-1831</num>
  <heading>Major Crash Review Task Force.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Major Crash Review Task Force ("Task Force"), which shall consist of the following members:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department, or the Chief's designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Director of the District Department of Transportation, or the Director's designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Office of Planning, or the Director's designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A representative from the Bicycle Advisory Council who is selected by the Bicycle Advisory Council;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A representative from the Pedestrian Advisory Council who is selected by the Pedestrian Advisory Council; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A representative from the Multimodal Accessibility Advisory Council who is selected by the Multimodal Accessibility Advisory Council.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall review every crash handled by the Major Crash Unit of the Metropolitan Police Department and recommend to the Mayor and the Council changes to the District's statutes, regulations, policies, and infrastructure that the Task Force believes would reduce the number of crashes in the District resulting in serious injury or death.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall begin review of a crash handled by the Major Crash Unit of the Metropolitan Police Department either:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Upon receipt of notice that the United States Attorney's Office for the District of Columbia and the Attorney General for the District of Columbia has declined to bring any prosecutions related to the crash; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If there is a criminal proceeding against an individual involved in the crash, the issuance of a final judgment in the criminal proceeding.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-155" eff="2016-10-08" path="VIII" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-155" eff="2016-10-08" path="ยง802" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
