<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-1501.02e</num>
  <heading>Issuance of arts and humanities motor-vehicle identification tags.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may make available for issue one or more arts and humanities motor-vehicle identification tags to enhance the public's awareness of the District's arts and humanities communities, works, and programming.  At the request of the Mayor, the Commission on Arts and Humanities ("Commission") shall provide to the Mayor proposed designs of the arts and humanities motor-vehicle identification tags, which the Commission may solicit from District residents.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A resident ordering an arts and humanities motor-vehicle identification tag designed and issued pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall pay a one-time application fee and a display fee each year thereafter, in amounts to be determined by the Mayor by rule.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Application fees and annual display fees collected pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be deposited into the Arts and Humanities Enterprise Fund, established by section 6a of the Commission on the Arts and Humanities Act, effective January 29, 1998 (D.C. Law 12-42; D.C. Official Code § 39-205.01).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="§2072|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§2072|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2018-07-30" eff="2018-07-30">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§2072|(a)">§ 2072(a) of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-434, July 30, 2018, 65 DCR 8200)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" eff="2018-10-03" path="§2072|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§2072|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2018-10-03" eff="2018-10-03">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§2072|(a)">§ 2072(a) of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-458, Oct. 3, 2018, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
