<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-110.02</num>
  <heading>Permits for the operation of a personal delivery device.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Personal Delivery Device Program ("PDD Program"), which shall be administered by the Department in accordance with <cite path="50|1A">this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Under the PDD Program, the Director may issue permits to eligible entities authorizing the operation of a PDD subject to any reasonable terms and conditions that the Director may require.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>To obtain a permit pursuant to this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Director, which shall include the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The eligible entity's contact information;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A certification by the eligible entity that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Each PDD that the eligible entity seeks to operate complies with the requirements of <cite path="50|1A">this chapter</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The person signing the application has reviewed the application and determined that the information provided in the application is true and accurate; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The person signing the application is authorized to sign and file the application;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The proposed geographic locations within the District where the eligible entity intends to operate PDDs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The number of PDDs the eligible entity intends to operate; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A nonrefundable application fee of $250.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the Director approves an application submitted pursuant to this section, the Director shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Issue a permit to the eligible entity, which shall be valid for one year after the date the permit is issued; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Require the eligible entity to pay a permit fee in an amount to be determined by the Director.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Director shall, by rule, establish procedures for the renewal of a permit issued pursuant to this section. The renewal procedures established pursuant to this subsection shall require the permit holder to pay a renewal fee in an amount to be determined by the Director.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-07-17" doc="D.C. Law 22-137" eff="2018-07-17" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-07-17" doc="D.C. Law 22-137" eff="2018-07-17" path="ยง3" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
