<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-1301.07a</num>
  <heading>Service of process on District residents.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Service of process may be made pursuant to the rules of the Superior Court on a defendant who is a resident and who was the owner or operator of a motor vehicle at the time such vehicle was involved in a collision on any public highway of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>When proof is made by affidavit that good faith efforts to serve a defendant pursuant to subsection (a) of this section have not succeeded, the court may order any other means of service that it considers appropriate in the circumstances and reasonably calculated to give actual notice, including by ordering that service be made upon the liability carrier to the defendant, the attorney the liability carrier retained, or the claims adjuster assigned to the claim. Such service shall be of the same legal force and validity as if served upon the defendant personally in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notice of service made pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall include a copy of the summons and complaint and shall be sent by certified mail without return receipt requested by the plaintiff, or the plaintiff's attorney, to the defendant at the defendant's last known address. The plaintiff has a duty  to exercise due diligence in the investigation of the last known address of the defendant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The methods of service provided in this section are in addition to any other means of service that may be provided by statute or rule for obtaining jurisdiction over a defendant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "resident" shall include any person who is a resident of the District at the time of the collision or who was not a resident of the District at the time of the collision but subsequently became a resident of the District and is a resident of the District at the time process is sought to be served on the person as a result of such collision.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 83-2-ch222" path="ยง7a">May 25, 1954, 68 Stat. 123, ch. 222, ยง 7a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-04-27" doc="D.C. Law 23-274" eff="2021-04-27" path="ยง1301" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
