<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-2353.01</num>
  <heading>Autonomous vehicles study.</heading>
  <text>By July 1, 2019, the District Department of Transportation, in consultation, as needed, with the Office of the Chief Financial Officer or other District agencies or organizations such as DC Surface Transit, shall make publicly available a study that evaluates and makes recommendations regarding the effects of autonomous vehicles on the District, including:</text>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The effect on the District's economy, including economic development and employment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The impact on the District government's revenue, including motor vehicle excise taxes, motor vehicle registration fees, motor vehicle fuel taxes, residential parking permit fees, parking meter revenue, fines and fees relating to moving infractions or parking, standing, stopping, and pedestrian infractions, and commercial parking taxes;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The impact on the District's infrastructure, traffic control systems, road use, congestion, curbside management, and public space;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The impact on the District's environment and public health;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The impact on public safety in the District, including the safety of other road users such as pedestrians and bicyclists;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The impact on the District's disability community;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The impact on the various transportation modes in the District, including mass transit, shared-use vehicles, and public and private vehicles-for-hire; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The need for and use of autonomous vehicle data, including data from autonomous vehicle manufacturers and public and private vehicle-for-hire companies.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-278" type="History" path="§4a">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 19-278, § 4a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-07-30" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" eff="2018-07-30" path="§6102" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§6102" codified:display="Note" app="2018-07-30" eff="2018-07-30">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-434" path="§6102">§ 6102 of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-434, July 30, 2018, 65 DCR 8200)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-03" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" eff="2018-10-03" path="§6102" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§6102" codified:display="Note" app="2018-10-03" eff="2018-10-03">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-458" path="§6102">§ 6102 of Fiscal Year 2019 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2018 (D.C. Act 22-458, Oct. 3, 2018, 65 DCR 11212)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§6112" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
