<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-2301.12</num>
  <heading>Reciprocity for non-moving and ATE fines.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may establish reciprocal agreements with states or other jurisdictions that provide for the suspension of vehicle registrations or driver's licenses for vehicles registered in that state or jurisdiction that accrue more than an amount, to be determined in negotiations with the states or other jurisdictions, of non-moving violation fines and automated traffic enforcement fines in the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may permit a percentage of the money recovered from the payment of citations and fines due to suspended vehicle registrations or driver's licenses be paid to the state or jurisdiction in which the vehicle is registered or the driver is licensed as payment for the state or jurisdiction's cooperation in the reciprocal agreement.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall enter into negotiations with Virginia and Maryland to establish reciprocal agreements as described in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall transmit a report to the Council by September 30, 2021, which describes the results or progress of the negotiations required by this subsection, the contents of any reciprocal agreement agreed upon, and the expected financial gain or loss resulting from any reciprocal agreement agreed upon.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-104" type="History" path="ยง112">Sept. 12, 1978, D.C. Law 2-104, ยง 112</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-12-23" doc="D.C. Law 23-158" eff="2020-12-23" path="ยง11" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
