<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-2204.01</num>
  <heading>Aggressive driving.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>It shall be a violation of this section if a person violates 3 or more of the following provisions at the same time or during a single and continuous period of driving within the course of one mile:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Section 2000.4 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (18 DCMR § 2000.4);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Section 2200 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (18 DCMR § 2200);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Section 2201.6 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (18 DCMR § 2201.6);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Section 2201.9 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (18 DCMR § 2201.9);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Section 2202.4 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (18 DCMR § 2202.4);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Section 2205 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (18 DCMR § 2205);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Section 2210.1 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (18 DCMR § 2210.1);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Section 2220 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (18 DCMR § 2220);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Section 2405.1(e) of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (18 DCMR § 2405.1(e)); or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text><cite path="§50-2201.04">§ 50-2201.04</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The penalty for violating this section shall be a fine of $200 and 2 traffic points.  The penalties prescribed by this subsection shall be applied in addition to any other penalties provided by law for the offenses listed in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In addition to any penalty described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, a person who violates this section shall complete traffic school, as approved by the Department of Motor Vehicles, within 90 days of the date on which the infraction is established.  Failure to successfully complete the traffic school shall result in the suspension of the driver's license or privilege to operate a motor vehicle in the District for a period to be determined by the Department of Motor Vehicles.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A violation of this section shall be processed and adjudicated under the provisions applicable to moving violations set forth in <cite path="50|23|II">subchapter II of Chapter 23 of this title</cite>.
        </text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-155" eff="2016-10-08" path="VI" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-155" eff="2016-10-08" path="§604" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-155" type="Editor's Notes" path="§703" history="false" app="2016-10-08" eff="2016-10-08">For requirement of the issuance of rules to implement title 7 of Law 21-155, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-155">§ 703 of D.C. Law 21-155</cite>.
      </annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-155" eff="2016-10-08" path="§703" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
