<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-2361.02</num>
  <heading>Transit Rider Advisory Council.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Transit Rider Advisory Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The TRAC shall be composed of 11 members appointed as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director of DDOT, or the Director’s designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Office of Planning, or the Director’s designee; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Nine community representatives who are District residents who regularly use local transit and who do not receive a salary from, do business with, or lobby the District government, appointed as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Each Ward Councilmember shall appoint one community representative; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The Chairperson of the Council committee with oversight over DDOT shall appoint one community representative.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The community representatives shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, with initial staggered appointments of 3 community representatives appointed for one year, 3 community representatives appointed for 2 years, and 3 community representatives appointed for 3 years. The community representatives to serve the one-year term, the community representatives to serve the 2-year term, and the community representatives to serve the 3-year term shall be determined by lot at the first meeting of the TRAC.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment to the position that became vacant. Community representatives who are appointed to fill vacancies that occur before the expiration of a community representative’s full term shall serve only the unexpired portion of the community representative’s term.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A chairperson shall be elected from among the community representatives at the first meeting of the TRAC, for a term of 2 years, and every 2 years thereafter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The TRAC shall meet on a quarterly basis, and more often as needed, at times to be determined by the chairperson of the TRAC at the first meeting of the TRAC.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>DDOT shall provide the TRAC with an annual operating budget, which shall include funds to maintain a website where the TRAC shall provide a public listing of members, meeting notices, and meeting minutes.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124" eff="2016-06-22" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124" eff="2016-06-22" path="§601" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124" eff="2016-06-22" path="§302" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" codified:display="Note" app="2016-06-22" eff="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124" path="§302">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-124" path="">D.C. Law 21-124</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-124" path="§601">§ 601 of D.C. Law 21-124</cite> provided that the addition of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-124" path="§302">§ 302 of D.C. Law 21-124</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§7011" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2016-10-08" eff="2016-10-08"><cite doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§7011">Section 7011 of D.C. Law 21-160</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-124" path="§601">§ 601 of D.C. Law 21-124</cite>. Therefore the changes made to this section by D.C. Law 21-124 have been given effect.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§7011" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
