<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-2531.02</num>
  <heading>Repeat Parking Violation Pilot Zones.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may establish Repeat Parking Violation Pilot Zones for the purpose of dissuading repeat parking violations, managing curbside parking, and reducing congestion caused by repeat parking violations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if a person who violates Chapter 24 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations in a Repeat Parking Violation Zone was previously found liable for a violation of Chapter 24 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations in a Repeat Parking Violation Zone within the same 12-month period, the fine for the second violation shall be triple the fine otherwise provided by law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if a person who violates Chapter 24 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations in a Repeat Parking Violation Zone was previously found liable for 2 or more violations of Chapter 24 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations in a Repeat Parking Violation Zone within the same 12-month period, the fine for the third or subsequent violation shall be quadruple the fine otherwise provided by law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Within one year after April 11, 2019, the Mayor shall submit to the Council a report describing efforts to mitigate repeat parking violations, as described in subsections (b) and (c) of this section. The report shall identify, at a minimum:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The number of violations of Chapter 24 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations that were subject to the enhanced penalties in subsection (b) of this section; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The number of violations of Chapter 24 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations that were subject to the enhanced penalties in subsection (c) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-279" type="History" path="ยง2b">Nov. 25, 2008, D.C. Law 17-279, ยง 2b</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-04-11" doc="D.C. Law 22-298" eff="2019-04-11" path="ยง3" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
