<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-2301.10</num>
  <heading>Reports to Department of Public Works and the District Department of Transportation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Before the 10th day of each month, the Department shall transmit a report to the Department of Public Works ("DPW") and the District Department of Transportation ("DDOT") with the following information from the previous month:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The number of answers filed for parking infractions, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The number of "admit" answers, including ticket payments, filed for parking infractions;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The number of "admit with explanation" answers filed for parking infractions; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The number of "deny" answers filed for parking infractions, including:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The number of determinations of liability of respondents who deny the commission of parking infractions; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The number of dismissals of respondents who deny the commission of parking infractions;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The most common reasons for the dismissal of respondents who deny the commission of parking infractions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The badge numbers of the officers whose notices of infraction most frequently resulted in the dismissal of respondents who deny the commission of parking infractions;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>On a quarterly basis, the Department shall transmit a report to DPW and DDOT describing relevant trends in parking infraction adjudication and dismissals of respondents who deny the commission of parking infractions.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="1978-09-12" doc="D.C. Law 2-104" eff="1978-09-12" path="ยง110" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124" eff="2016-06-22" path="ยง201" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
