<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-2201.04b</num>
  <heading>All-terrain vehicles and dirt bikes.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No person shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Operate an all-terrain vehicle or dirt bike on public property, including any public space in the District; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Park, stand, or stop an all-terrain vehicle or dirt bike on public property, including any public space in the District.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply to a person who is in the process of immediately loading an all-terrain vehicle or dirt bike in or on a vehicle, trailer, or other storage container for the purpose of transporting the all-terrain vehicle or dirt bike to another jurisdiction or to private property in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All-terrain vehicles or dirt bikes shall not be registered with the Department of Motor Vehicles.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person violating subsection (a)(1)(A) of this section shall upon conviction be fined no more than the amount set forth in <cite path="§22-3571.01">§ 22-3571.01</cite>, or incarcerated for no more than 30 days, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In addition to the penalties described in subsection (c) of this section, a person who is convicted of violating subsection (a)(1)(A) of this section shall, upon a second or subsequent conviction for violating subsection (a)(1)(A) of this section, have his or her driver's license, or privilege to operate a motor vehicle in the District, suspended for one year from the date of conviction; provided, that the period of suspension shall toll during a period of incarceration.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Attorney General for the District of Columbia, or his or her assistants, shall prosecute violations of this section, in the name of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>An all-terrain vehicle or dirt bike operated in violation of this section shall be subject to forfeiture pursuant to the standards and procedures set forth in <cite path="41|3">Chapter 3 of Title 41</cite>.
            </text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 68-2-ch443" path="§9b">Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 443, § 9b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-289" type="History">as added Apr. 5, 2005, D.C. Law 15-289, § 2(d), 52 DCR 1446</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-266" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-266, § 102(d), 59 DCR 12957</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 271(b), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 102(d) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-51, April 17, 2013,  60 DCR 6344, 20 DCSTAT 1360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 271(b) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 102(d) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-3, January 29, 2013,  60 DCR 2762, 20 DCSTAT 410).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of (c), see § 102(d) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-508, October 26, 2012, 59 DCR 12774).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 102(d) of Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-429, July 30, 2012,  59 DCR 9387).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in <cite path="§22-3571.01">§ 22-3571.01</cite>” for “not more than $1000 [$250]” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-266">D.C. Law 19-266</cite> substituted “$250” for “$1,000” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-155" eff="2016-10-08" path="§607" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-03-29" doc="D.C. Law 22-77" eff="2018-03-29" path="§3|(a)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-03-29" doc="D.C. Law 22-77" eff="2018-03-29" path="§3|(a)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-03-29" doc="D.C. Law 22-77" eff="2018-03-29" path="§3|(a)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2018-03-29" doc="D.C. Law 22-77" eff="2018-03-29" path="§3|(a)|(4)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
