<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-2201.03b</num>
  <heading>Regulations for shared fleet devices.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>, shall issue rules implementing the provisions of <cite path="§50-2201.03c">§ 50-2201.03c</cite>, including establishing:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Terms and conditions for a SFD permit;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An application process for obtaining a SFD permit;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A process by which a permit may be revoked if the permitted operator does not comply with the terms and conditions of the SFD permit, <cite path="§50-2201.03c">§ 50-2201.03c</cite>, or regulations issued pursuant to this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The term for which a SFD permit lasts before requiring renewal;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Penalties and fines for violations of the terms and conditions of the SFD permit, <cite path="§50-2201.03c">§ 50-2201.03c</cite>, or regulations issued pursuant to this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The number of shared fleet devices each permitted operator may operate in the public right-of-way;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The process a permitted operator shall follow and the criteria a permitted operator shall meet, including an explanation of how each criterion is weighted, in order to increase its fleet size;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Insurance requirements for permitted operators, which:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Shall include liability insurance in an amount not less than $1 million per incident, that each permitted operator shall carry; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>May include a required minimum aggregate amount of liability insurance; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The amount of the performance bond permitted operators shall provide to operate in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 68-2-ch443" path="§6b">Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 443, § 6b</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-203" eff="2021-03-16" path="§101|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
