<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-301.10a</num>
  <heading> For-Hire Vehicle Advisory Council.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a For-Hire Vehicle Advisory Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The FHVAC shall be composed of 11 members appointed as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director of the DFHV, or the Director’s designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Director of the District Department of Transportation, or the Director’s designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Nine community representatives, who do not work for the District government, appointed by the Mayor as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Two District residents who operate public or private vehicles-for-hire in the District;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Two representatives of companies providing vehicle for-hire industry services in the District;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Two representatives of the hospitality or tourism industry in the District; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Three District residents, unaffiliated with the vehicle for-hire industry, who regularly use public or private vehicles-for-hire in the District.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The community representatives shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, with initial staggered appointments of 3 community representatives appointed for one year, 3 community representatives appointed for 2 years, and 3 community representatives appointed for 3 years. The community representatives to serve the one-year term, the community representatives to serve the 2-year term, and the community representatives to serve the 3-year term shall be determined by lot at the first meeting of the FHVAC.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Each community representative shall serve until the appointment of a successor. No community representative shall serve more than 2 consecutive terms, which shall not include an appointment to fill a vacancy due to removal, resignation, or death of a member. The Mayor may remove a community representative for cause. An appointment to fill a vacancy occurring during a term due to removal, resignation, or death of a member shall be made in the same manner as other appointments and for the remainder of the unexpired term.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A chairperson shall be elected from among the 9 community representatives at the first meeting of the FHVAC, for a term of 2 years, and every 2 years thereafter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The FHVAC shall meet on a quarterly basis, and more often as needed, at times to be determined by the chairperson of the FHVAC at the first meeting of the FHVAC.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The DFHV shall provide the FHVAC with an annual operating budget, which shall include funds to maintain a website where the FHVAC shall provide a public listing of members, meeting notices, and meeting minutes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The purpose of the FHVAC shall be to advise the DFHV on all matters related to the regulation of the vehicle for-hire industry.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At least once every 6 months, the Director of the DFHV, or the Director’s designee, shall meet with the chairperson of the FHVAC to discuss recommendations provided by the FHVAC to the DFHV.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Following each meeting held pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, the DFHV shall make publicly available all recommendations discussed between the DFHV and the FHVAC, the DFHV’s decision in response to the recommendations, and an explanation of the decision made by the DFHV.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="1986-03-25" doc="D.C. Law 6-97" eff="1986-03-25" path="§11a" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124" eff="2016-06-22" path="§601" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124" eff="2016-06-22" path="§401|(l)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" path="§401|(l)" codified:display="Note" app="2016-06-22" eff="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-124" path="">D.C. Law 21-124</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-124" path="§601">§ 601 of D.C. Law 21-124</cite> provided that the addition of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-124" path="§401|(l)">§ 401(l) of D.C. Law 21-124</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-06-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-124" eff="2016-06-22" path="§401|(l)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§7011" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2016-10-08" eff="2016-10-08"><cite doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§7011">Section 7011 of D.C. Law 21-160</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-124" path="§601">§ 601 of D.C. Law 21-124</cite>. Therefore the changes made to this section by D.C. Law 21-124 have been given effect.
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§7011" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
