<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<section xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library">
  <num>50-533</num>
  <heading>Appeals.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the insured disputes the validity of a purported cancellation or nonrenewal, the insured may send, within 15 calendar days of receipt of the notice of intent to cancel or not to renew, written notification to the Commissioner of the reasons the insured believes the action by the insurer is invalid. The Commissioner shall, upon receipt, immediately send the insurer a copy of the notification.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Unless the matter referred to in subsection (a) of this section has been settled, the Commissioner shall determine, within 45 calendar days of receipt of the notification of appeal, whether the cancellation or nonrenewal was authorized under the terms of this title and shall notify immediately the insured and the insurer in writing of the decision.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the Commissioner determines that a policy was improperly cancelled or not renewed, the policy in question shall be considered to be in effect and to have been in effect from the date of notification of cancellation or nonrenewal.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the Commissioner determines that a policy was properly cancelled or not renewed, the policy in question shall be considered to be cancelled or not renewed as of the cancellation or nonrenewal date given in the notice sent by the insurer pursuant to section 402 or as of the date of determination by the Commissioner, whichever is later. The insured shall pay any portion of the required premium or cost to the insurer for the insurance coverage in effect and provided by the insurer for which the insured has not paid.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Decisions of the Commissioner shall be appealable pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 
          <em>et seq.</em>).
        </text>
  </para>
  <annotations />
</section>