<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-741</num>
  <heading>Transportation Electrification program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 180 days after October 1, 2019, the Mayor shall establish a transportation electrification program ("program") that shall require that all public buses, passenger- and light-duty vehicles associated with privately-owned fleets with a capacity of 50 or more passengers or light-duty vehicles licensed to operate in the District of Columbia, commercial motor carriers, limousine-service vehicles, and taxis certified to operate by the District to be only zero-emission vehicles in the District by year 2045.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The transition to zero emission vehicles will be phased in as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By 2030, 50% of public buses, passenger- and light-duty vehicles associated with privately-owned fleets with a capacity of 50 or more passengers or light-duty vehicles licensed to operate by the District of Columbia, commercial motor carriers, limousine-service vehicles, and taxis certified to operate by the District of Columbia shall be low-or-zero-emission vehicles.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By 2035,75% of public buses, passenger- and light-duty vehicles associated with privately-owned fleets with a capacity of 50 or more passengers or light-duty vehicles licensed to operate by the District of Columbia, commercial motor carriers, limousine-service vehicles, and taxis certified to operate by the District of Columbia shall be low-or-zero-emission vehicles.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>By 2040, 90% of public buses, passenger- and light-duty vehicles associated with privately-owned fleets with a capacity of 50 or more passengers or light-duty vehicles licensed to operate by the District of Columbia, commercial motor carriers, limousine-service vehicles, and taxis certified to operate by the District of Columbia shall be low-or-zero-emission vehicles.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>By 2045, 100% of all public buses, passenger- and light-duty vehicles associated with privately-owned fleets with a capacity of 50 or more passengers or light-duty vehicles licensed to operate by the District of Columbia, commercial motor carriers, limousine-service vehicles, and taxis certified to operate by the District of Columbia shall be zero emission vehicles.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Public Service Commission may consider an application by the electric company to promote transportation electrification through utility infrastructure ownership and other programs and incentives, including if such application has been made before October 1, 2019.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Public Service Commission may approve the application if it finds that it is in the public interest, consistent with the District's public climate change commitments as determined by the Mayor, and consistent with <cite path="§34-1101">§ 34-1101</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may authorize non-compliance fees to be assessed against an owner or operator for failure to meet the standards set forth in this section or rules issued pursuant to this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Fees collected pursuant to this subsection may be used to construct and maintain electrification infrastructure.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By January 1, 2022, and every 2 years thereafter, each private vehicle-for-hire company shall develop a greenhouse gas emissions reduction plan. The plan shall include proposals on how to meet targets and goals for reducing emissions by:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Increasing the proportion of participating drivers with zero-emission vehicles using private vehicle-for-hire companies; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Increasing the proportion of vehicle-miles completed by zero-emission vehicles relative to all vehicle-miles.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By February 1, 2022, and every 2 years thereafter, each private vehicle-for-hire company shall submit the greenhouse gas emissions reduction plan required by paragraph (1) of this subsection to the Public Service Commission and to the chairperson of the Council committee with oversight of the Public Service Commission. Any confidential or trade secret information furnished pursuant to this paragraph shall be confidential.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>, shall issue rules to implement this section.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-741" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§50-741">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-257" path="">D.C. Law 22-257</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-257" path="§601">§ 601 of D.C. Law 22-257</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-257" path="§502">§ 502 of D.C. Law 22-257</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2019-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-257" eff="2019-03-22" path="V" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-03-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-257" eff="2019-03-22" path="§502" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 22-257" path="§502" codified:display="Note" app="2019-03-22" eff="2019-03-22">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-257" path="">D.C. Law 22-257</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-257" path="§601">§ 601 of D.C. Law 22-257</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-257" path="§502">§ 502 of D.C. Law 22-257</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-16" path="§7164" type="Applicability" history="false" display-template="" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-09-11"><cite doc="D.C. Law 23-16" path="§7164">Section 7164 of D.C. Law 23-16</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-257" path="§601">§ 601 of D.C. Law 22-257</cite>. Therefore the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-257">D.C. Law 22-257</cite> has been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§7164" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
