<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-904.01</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
      </text>
  <heading>Department of Motor Vehicles Kiosk Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Department of Motor Vehicles Kiosk Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Mayor in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All convenience fees collected from the operation of the Department of Motor Vehicles' self-service kiosks shall be deposited in the Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Money in the Fund shall be used to pay the costs of installing, renting, operating, maintaining, and providing supplies for the Department of Motor Vehicles' self-service kiosks.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited in the Fund but not expended in a fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "self-service kiosk" means a hardware device with specialized integrated software that enables users to conduct transactions related to the Department of Motor Vehicles' services without the need for assistance from Department of Motor Vehicles staff.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-175" type="History" path="§1825a" display="false">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-175, § 1825a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-175" type="History" path="§1825a">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-175, § 1825a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§6072" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§6072" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§6072" codified:display="Note" app="2021-08-23" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§6072">§ 6072 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
