<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-921.32</num>
  <heading>DC Circulator.</heading>
  <text>The Department shall have the power to:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Plan, develop, finance, operate, control, and regulate the DC Circulator, including fares, charges, tickets, fines, and the establishment of routes and schedules;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Sell space on and within DC Circulator vehicles or other assets for the display of advertisements and enter into one or more agreements with entities to sell such space on such vehicles or other assets in return for a fee, a percentage of such revenues, or as a gift or donation of services approved by the Mayor;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Enter into contracts with third parties, including WMATA for the procurement, construction, operation, and maintenance of DC Circulator vehicles or other assets; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Enter into agreements to allow the private sponsorship of vehicles, equipment, and facilities used in the DC Circulator program, and the placement of a corporate logo, slogan, or other indicia of sponsorship on the vehicles, equipment, or facilities, and on related websites and social media; provided, that a proposed private sponsorship agreement entered into pursuant to this paragraph shall be submitted, before execution, to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. The agreement submitted to the Council shall include detailed information about the proposed private sponsorship agreement, including, if the agreement contemplates the placement of a corporate logo, slogan, or other indicia of sponsorship on the vehicles, equipment, or facilities, or websites or social media, a drawing depicting how the vehicles, equipment, or facilities, or websites or social media, will appear. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed private sponsorship agreement by resolution within this 45-day review period, the proposed private sponsorship agreement shall be deemed approved.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137" type="History" path="§11b">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, § 11b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-225" type="History">as added Mar. 6, 2007, D.C. Law 16-225, § 3(e), 53 DCR 10232</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 3(e) of District Department of Transportation DC Circulator Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-3, January 16, 2007,  54 DCR 1439).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 3(d) of District Department of Transportation DC Circulator Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-321, March 23, 2006,  53 DCR 2557).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 3(d) of District Department of Transportation DC Circulator Temporary Amendment Act of 2006 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-134">D.C. Law 16-134</cite>, June 16, 2006, law notification  53 DCR 5762).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§50-921.33">§ 50-921.33</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§6072|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-07-20" eff="2017-07-20">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§6072|(b)">§ 6072(b) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104, July 20, 2017, 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-07-20" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" eff="2017-07-20" path="§6072|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§6072|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-10-24" eff="2017-10-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§6072|(b)">§ 6072(b) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167, Oct. 24, 2017, 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-10-24" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" eff="2017-10-24" path="§6072|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§6072|(b)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§6072|(b)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§6072|(b)|(3)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
