<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-921.25</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation with identical permanent legislation that will become effective in January, 2022.*
      </text>
  <heading>ATE system revenue designation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund, the Vision Zero Enhancement Omnibus Amendment Act Implementation Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Director of the District Department of Transportation ("Director") in accordance with subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>There shall be deposited in the Fund the amount by which the projected local funds revenue from fines generated from the automated traffic enforcement system, authorized by <cite path="§50-2209.01">§ 50-2209.01</cite>, for that fiscal year exceeds $98,757,000.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Money in the Fund shall be used according to the following order of priority:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>To implement the Vision Zero Enhancement Omnibus Amendment Act of 2020 [D.C. Law 23-158] including to pay recurring costs;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>To enhance the safety and quality of pedestrian and bicycle transportation, including education, engineering, and enforcement efforts designed to calm traffic and provide safe routes.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Director is authorized to enter into intra-District transfers from the Fund and other agreements with the Department of Health, Department of Motor Vehicles, Department of Public Works, and Metropolitan Police Department as necessary to implement provisions of the Vision Zero Enhancement Omnibus Amendment Act of 2020 [D.C. Law 23-158].</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137" type="History" path="§9n" display="false">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, §  9q</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137" type="History" path="§9n">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, §  9q</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§6102" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§6102" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§6102" codified:display="Note" app="2021-08-23" eff="2021-08-23">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-159" path="§6102">§ 6102 of Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-159, Aug. 23, 2021, 68 DCR 008602)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
