<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>24-221.01c</num>
  <heading>Credits for good behavior, rehabilitation programs, work details, and special projects.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person sentenced for a misdemeanor whose conduct complies with institutional rules shall be eligible to receive good time credits of up to 3 credits per calendar month for good behavior, as prescribed by applicable rules.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person sentenced for a misdemeanor who demonstrates successful participation in one or more rehabilitation programs, work details, or special projects shall be eligible to receive good time credits of up to 3 credits per calendar month for each such program, detail, or project, as prescribed by applicable rules.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No person shall receive more than 10 credits per calendar month under sections <cite path="§24-221.01">§ 24-221.01</cite> and this section combined; except, that during a period for which a public health emergency has been declared pursuant to <cite path="§7-2304.01">§ 7-2304.01</cite>, the Department of Corrections shall have discretion to award additional credits beyond the limits described in this subsection to effectuate the immediate release of persons sentenced for misdemeanors, including pursuant to <cite path="§24-221.01">§ 24-221.01</cite> and this section, consistent with public safety.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Good time credits shall be computed from the day on which a person is first incarcerated. In a case in which the person is later sentenced for a misdemeanor, the good time credits shall not be awarded until after a sentence is imposed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-218" type="History" path="§3c">Apr. 11, 1987, D.C. Law 6-218, § 3c</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-372" type="History">as added May 17, 2011, D.C. Law 18-372, § 2(a), 58 DCR 7</annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-06-30" doc="D.C. Law 21-125" eff="2016-06-30" path="§501" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-06-08" doc="D.C. Act 23-328" eff="2020-06-08" path="§706|(a)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
