<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>24-403.01a</num>
  <heading>Good time credit for felony offenses committed before August 5, 2000.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a defendant who is serving a term of imprisonment for an offense committed between June 22, 1994, and August 4, 2000, shall be retroactively awarded good time credit toward the service of the defendant's sentence of up to 54 days for each year of the defendant's sentence imposed by the court, subject to determination by the Bureau of Prisons that during those years the defendant has met the conditions provided in 18 U.S.C. § 3624(b).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An award of good time credit pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall apply to the minimum and maximum term of incarceration, including the mandatory minimum; provided, that in the event of a maximum term of life, only the minimum term shall receive good time.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a defendant who is serving a term of imprisonment for an offense committed before June 22, 1994, shall be retroactively awarded good time credit toward the service of the defendant's sentence of up to 54 days for each year of the defendant's sentence imposed by the court, subject to determination by the Bureau of Prisons that during those years the defendant has met the conditions provided in 18 U.S.C. § 3624(b).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An award of good time credit pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Shall apply to any mandatory minimum term of incarceration; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Is not intended to modify how the defendant is awarded good time credit toward any portion of the sentence other than the mandatory minimum.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 72-1-ch492" path="§3a-1">July 15, 1932, 47 Stat. 697, ch. 492, § 3a-1</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-405" eff="2020-08-19" path="§706|(b)|(1)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
