<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1031.12a</num>
  <heading>Home Composting Incentive Program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Home Composting Incentive Program ("Program"), to be administered by the Mayor, to provide rebates and vouchers to encourage residential property owners and lessees to purchase and use a home composting system.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To be eligible for the rebate provided for in this section, a residential property owner or lessee shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>After July 17, 2018, purchase a home composting system;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Complete the training described in subsection (f) of this section; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Submit a rebate claim to the Mayor in a manner to be determined by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Upon approval of a rebate claim submitted pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, the Program shall provide a rebate up to $75 per residential address; provided, that the amount of the rebate shall not exceed the purchase price of the home composting system.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Rebates shall be sent to the residential property owner or lessee within 30 days after the rebate claim is approved.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Rebates shall be contingent upon the availability of funds.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>To be eligible for the voucher provided for in this section, a residential property owner or lessee shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Complete the training described in subsection (f) of this section; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Submit a voucher application to the Mayor in a manner to be determined by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Upon approval of a voucher application submitted pursuant to subsection (d) of this section, the Program shall provide a voucher up to $75 per residential address.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Vouchers shall be sent to the residential property owner or lessee within one week after the voucher application is approved.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Vouchers shall be contingent upon the availability of funds.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, or a contractor selected by the Mayor, shall provide in-person training for District residents on proper handling and processing of organic materials that will be turned into compost, including training for residents interested in both outdoor composting and vermicomposting.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(1A)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, during a period of time for which the Mayor has declared a public health emergency pursuant to <cite path="§7-2304.01">§ 7-2304.01</cite>, the Mayor, or a contractor selected by the Mayor, may provide the training required by paragraph (1) of this subsection remotely through videoconference.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall create educational materials for District residents regarding how to use home composting systems in a manner that avoids creating public nuisances.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1031.12a" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§8-1031.12a">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-146" path="">D.C. Law 22-146</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-146" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 22-146</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-146" path="§2|(b)">§ 2(b) of D.C. Law 22-146</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-154" type="History" path="§112a">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-154, § 112a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2015-02-26" doc="D.C. Law 20-154" eff="2015-02-26" path="I" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-07-17" doc="D.C. Law 22-146" eff="2018-07-17" path="§2|(b)" prefix="as amended" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 22-146" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2018-07-17" eff="2018-07-17">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-146" path="">D.C. Law 22-146</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-146" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 22-146</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-146" path="§2|(b)">§ 2(b) of D.C. Law 22-146</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-07-17" doc="D.C. Law 22-146" eff="2018-07-17" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-168" path="§7036" type="Applicability" history="false" app="2018-10-30" eff="2018-10-30"><cite doc="D.C. Law 22-168" path="§7036">Section 7036 of D.C. Law 22-168</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-146" path="§4">§ 4 of D.C. Law 22-146</cite> removing the applicability restriction impacting this section. Therefore the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-146">D.C. Law 22-146</cite> has been given effect.
          </annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-10-30" doc="D.C. Law 22-168" eff="2018-10-30" path="§7036" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-405" eff="2020-08-19" path="§309" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
