<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1031.04</num>
  <heading>Mandatory adequate waste collection.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A private collection property owner shall provide adequate waste collection service, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Supplying waste containers to make source separation accessible for individuals discarding solid waste at the property; provided, that the containers shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Be capable of containing reasonably anticipated source-separated waste generated at the location; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Bear or be near visible signage indicating the category of source-separated material by visuals or description or shall comply with a color scheme established by the Mayor;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Annually communicating information to an individual discarding solid waste at the property regarding the types of materials that must be source separated at the property;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Ensuring annual training on the property's source separation requirements of any janitorial staff employed at the property; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Designating an agent responsible for implementing the requirements of <cite path="8|10A">this chapter</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may require a private collection property owner to submit a source separation plan outlining the steps the property owner will take to implement the requirements of <cite path="8|10A">this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All private collection properties shall separate their excess edible food for donation for human consumption to the maximum extent practicable.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2015-02-26" doc="D.C. Law 20-154" eff="2015-02-26" path="I" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2015-02-26" doc="D.C. Law 20-154" eff="2015-02-26" path="§104" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(d)|(1)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(d)|(1)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(d)|(1)|(C)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" eff="2021-03-16" path="§6|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="notfunded" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(d)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(d)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" path="§2|(d)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2021-03-16">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-211" path="">D.C. Law 23-211</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-211" path="§6">§ 6 of D.C. Law 23-211</cite> provided that the change made in subsection (b) of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-211" path="§2|(d)">§ 2(d) of D.C. Law 23-211</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(d)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
