<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1041.04</num>
  <heading>Registration and shortfall fees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>
              A manufacturer that sold less than 100 units of covered electronic equipment in the District in the previous calendar year shall be exempt from paying an annual registration fee.
            </text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For an individual manufacturer that sold at least 100 units but less than 250 units of covered electronic equipment in the District in the previous calendar year, the individual manufacturer's application for registration under <cite path="§8-1041.03">§ 8-1041.03</cite> shall be accompanied by a registration fee of $500.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For an individual manufacturer that sold 250 or more units of covered electronic equipment in the District in the previous calendar year, the manufacturer's application for registration under <cite path="§8-1041.03">§ 8-1041.03</cite> shall be accompanied by a registration fee of $1,000.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A partnership's application for registration under <cite path="§8-1041.03">§ 8-1041.03</cite> shall be accompanied by a registration fee in the amount of the sum of its member manufacturers' registration fees, or $10,000, whichever is less.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A representative organization's application for registration under <cite path="§8-1041.03">§ 8-1041.03</cite> shall be accompanied by a registration fee in the amount of $10,000.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A manufacturer participating in a partnership or representative organization shall be exempt from paying an individual annual registration fee.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Beginning January 1, 2017, if a manufacturer or partnership did not comply with <cite path="§8-1041.05|(a)|(1)">§ 8-1041.05(a)(1)</cite> or <cite path="§8-1041.05|(a)|(2)">§ 8-1041.05(a)(2)</cite> in the previous calendar year, the manufacturer's or partnership's application for registration under <cite path="§8-1041.03">§ 8-1041.03</cite> shall be accompanied by a shortfall fee. The shortfall fee shall be determined by multiplying the difference of the weight of covered electronic equipment collected and recycled or reused by the manufacturer or the partnership and the manufacturer's minimum collection share by $0.30 or the sum of the partnership's member manufacturers' minimum collection shares by $0.30.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may increase the fees and modify the fee structures established by this section through rulemaking.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Fees collected under this section shall be deposited in the Product Stewardship Fund established by <cite path="§1-325.381">§ 1-325.381</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2015-02-26" doc="D.C. Law 20-154" eff="2015-02-26" path="I" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2015-02-26" doc="D.C. Law 20-154" eff="2015-02-26" path="§118" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§6032|(e)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§6032|(e)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§6003|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-07-20" eff="2017-07-20">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-104" path="§6003|(b)">§ 6003(b) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-104, July 20, 2017, 64 DCR 7032)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-07-20" doc="D.C. Act 22-104" eff="2017-07-20" path="§6003|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§6003|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2017-10-24" eff="2017-10-24">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-167" path="§6003|(b)">§ 6003(b) of Fiscal Year 2018 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-167, Oct. 24, 2017, 64 DCR 10802)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2017-10-24" doc="D.C. Act 22-167" eff="2017-10-24" path="§6003|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-12-13" doc="D.C. Law 22-33" eff="2017-12-13" path="§6003|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
