<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1031.13</num>
  <heading>Reporting requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>On February 28, 2016, and annually thereafter, the Mayor shall provide a solid waste diversion update to the Council that shall include, at a minimum:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The total tonnage of solid waste collected in the District, from both private collection and public collection properties;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A breakdown of the total tonnage reported in paragraph (1) of this subsection by the individual tonnage of solid waste that was collected for delivery to recycling, composting, landfill, incineration, and any other waste processing or disposal facilities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The names, locations, and tonnage of solid waste delivered to the recycling, compost, landfill, incineration, and other waste processing or disposal facilities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A calculation of the District's solid waste diversion rate for the previous year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A calculation of the District's per-capita solid waste generation for the previous year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A summary of efforts made by District agencies and facilities to meet the requirements of §§ <cite path="§8-1031.04">8-1031.04</cite> and <cite path="§8-1031.04a|(a)">§ 8-1031.04a(a)</cite> and <cite path="§8-1031.04a|(b)">(b)</cite>, broken down by agency, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A description of each agency's waste collection services;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The name of the designated person responsible for compliance at each agency; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>All activities each agency has taken in the preceding year in furtherance of §§ <cite path="§8-1031.04">8-1031.04</cite> and <cite path="§8-1031.04a|(a)">§ 8-1031.04a(a)</cite> and <cite path="§8-1031.04a|(b)">(b)</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>A description of the Mayor's waste diversion goals for the remainder of the calendar year, including specific targets, plans for meeting those targets, and planned waste diversion programs.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>On January 31, 2018, and every 4 years thereafter, the Mayor shall issue a waste characterization study describing solid waste generation, collection, recycling, composting, diversion, and management in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2015-02-26" doc="D.C. Law 20-154" eff="2015-02-26" path="I" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2015-02-26" doc="D.C. Law 20-154" eff="2015-02-26" path="§113" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" eff="2021-03-16" path="§6|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(l)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(l)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(l)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" path="§2|(l)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2021-03-16">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-211" path="">D.C. Law 23-211</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-211" path="§6">§ 6 of D.C. Law 23-211</cite> provided that the change made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-211" path="§2|(l)">§ 2(l) of D.C. Law 23-211</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(l)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§7203" type="History" display="false"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
