<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-151.13a</num>
  <heading>CRIAC Assistance Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Clean Rivers Impervious Area Charge Assistance Fund ("Fund"), which shall be administered by the Mayor in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Revenue from the following sources shall be deposited in the Fund:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Such amounts as may be appropriated to the Fund; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any amounts appropriated in Fiscal Year 2019 for the implementation of the financial assistance programs authorized by <cite path="§34-2202.16b">§ 34-2202.16b</cite> that remain unspent at the end of that fiscal year.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Money in the Fund shall be used to pay for the costs of implementing the financial assistance programs authorized by <cite path="§34-2202.16b">§ 34-2202.16b</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, during a period of time for which the Mayor has declared a public health emergency ("PHE") pursuant to <cite path="§7-2304.01">§ 7-2304.01</cite>, and for 105 calendar days thereafter, money in the Fund may be used to assist low-income residential customers located in the District of Columbia with the payment of an outstanding water bill balance; except, that not less than $1.26 million of funding allocated in the fiscal year in which the PHE occurs shall be reserved to assist nonprofit organizations located in the District with the payment of impervious area charges, pursuant to <cite path="§34-2202.16b|(a)">§ 34-2202.16b(a)</cite>, and not less than $360,000 of funding allocated in the fiscal year in which the PHE occurs shall be reserved to assist residential customers with the payment of impervious area charges, pursuant to <cite path="§34-2202.16b|(b)">§ 34-2202.16b(b)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-51" type="History" path="§113a">Feb. 15, 2006, D.C. Law 16-51, § 113a</annotation>
    <annotation codify:doc="D.C. Code" path="§6062" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-07-22" doc="D.C. Act 23-91">
          For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-91" path="§6062">§ 6062 of the Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-91, July 22, 2019</cite>, 66 DCR 8497).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Act 23-91" eff="2019-07-22" path="§6062" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation codify:doc="D.C. Code" path="§6062" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2019-09-11" eff="2019-09-04" doc="D.C. Act 23-112">
          For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-112" path="§6062">§ 6062 of the Fiscal Year 2020 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-112, Sept. 4, 2019</cite>, 66 DCR 11964).
        </annotation>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Act 23-112" eff="2019-09-04" path="§6062" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2019-09-11" doc="D.C. Law 23-16" eff="2019-09-11" path="§6062" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 23-405" path="§307|(a)" codified:display="Note" app="2020-08-19" eff="2020-08-19">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-405" path="§307|(a)">§ 307(a) of Coronavirus Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2020 [Effective August 19, 2020 through October 8, 2020] (D.C. Act 23-405, Aug. 19, 2020, 67 DCR 10235)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2020-08-19" doc="D.C. Act 23-405" eff="2020-08-19" path="§307|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-09" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" eff="2020-10-09" path="§307|(a)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-10-09" doc="D.C. Law 23-130" eff="2020-10-09" path="§307|(a)|(2)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
