<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1537</num>
  <heading>Rules; enforcement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>, may issue rules to implement the provisions of <cite path="8|15A">this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Civil fines and penalties may be imposed as sanctions for an infraction of the provisions of <cite path="8|15A">this chapter</cite> or any rules issued under the authority of <cite path="8|15A">this chapter</cite>, pursuant to <cite path="2|18">Chapter 18 of Title 2</cite> ("Civil Infractions Act").  Enforcement and adjudication of an infraction shall be pursuant to the Civil Infractions Act.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In addition to the enforcement authority provided to the Mayor under the Civil Infractions Act, the Mayor may seek injunctive relief or other appropriate remedy in any court of competent jurisdiction to enforce compliance with the provisions of <cite path="8|15A">this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For the purpose of enforcing the provisions of <cite path="8|15A">this chapter</cite>, or any rule issued pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor may, upon the presentation of appropriate credentials to the owner, operator, or agent in charge, enter upon any public or private land in a reasonable and lawful manner during normal business hours for the purpose of sampling, inspection, and observation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If denied access to any place while carrying out the activities described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Mayor may apply to a court of competent jurisdiction for a search warrant.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> added (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see ยง 6172(f) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation app="2014-12-17" doc="D.C. Law 20-142" eff="2014-12-17" path="IV" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2014-12-17" doc="D.C. Law 20-142" eff="2014-12-17" path="ยง407" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2015-10-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-36" eff="2015-10-22" path="ยง6172|(f)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
