<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1531</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of <cite path="8|15A">this chapter</cite>, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Compostable" means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Made solely of materials that break down into, or otherwise become part of, usable compost in a safe and timely manner in an appropriate program; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Once the Mayor has published the list of compostable materials described in <cite path="§8-1031.03|(b)">§ 8-1031.03(b)</cite>, identified on that list;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(1A)</num>
      <text>"Disposable food service ware" means containers, bowls, plates, trays, cartons, cups, lids, straws, forks, spoons, knives, napkins, and other items that are designed for one-time use for beverages, prepared food, or leftovers from meals prepared by a food service entity. The term "disposable food service ware" shall not include items composed entirely of aluminum.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Expanded polystyrene" means blown polystyrene and expanded and extruded foams that are thermoplastic petrochemical materials utilizing a styrene monomer and processed by a number of techniques, including fusion of polymer spheres (expandable bead polystyrene), injection molding, foam molding, and extrusion-blow molding (extruded foam polystyrene).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2A)</num>
      <text>"Expanded polystyrene container" means a container, such as a cooler or ice chest, made of expanded polystyrene that is not wholly encapsulated or encased within a more durable material.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Expanded polystyrene food service products" means food containers, plates, hot and cold beverage cups, meat and vegetable trays, egg cartons, and other products made of expanded polystyrene and used for selling or providing food.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3A)</num>
      <text>"Expanded polystyrene packing material" means material, such as packing peanuts, made of expanded polystyrene used to hold, cushion, or protect items packed in a container for shipping, transport, or storage.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Food service entity" means full-service restaurants, limited-service restaurants, fast food restaurants, cafes, delicatessens, coffee shops, supermarkets, grocery stores, vending trucks or carts, food trucks, cafeterias, including those operated by or on behalf of District departments and agencies, and other entities selling or providing food within the District for consumption on or off the premises.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>"Recyclable" means made solely of materials that can be recycled using the District's recycling collection program and identified on the list of recyclable materials described in <cite path="§8-1031.03|(b)">§ 8-1031.03(b)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>"Retailer" means a person engaged in retail sales in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> substituted “prepared by a food service entity” for “prepared by a food service business” in (1); in (4), substituted “entity” for “business,” substituted “cafeterias” for “business or institutional cafeterias,” and substituted “and other entities” for “and other businesses”; and added (5).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 6172(a) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-142">D.C. Law 20-142</cite>: Section 502(f) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-142">D.C. Law 20-142</cite> provided that §§ 401, 402, and 406 of the act shall apply as of December 17, 2014.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2014-12-17" doc="D.C. Law 20-142" eff="2014-12-17" path="IV" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2014-12-17" doc="D.C. Law 20-142" eff="2014-12-17" path="§401" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2015-10-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-36" eff="2015-10-22" path="§6172|(a)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2015-10-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-36" eff="2015-10-22" path="§6172|(a)|(2)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2015-10-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-36" eff="2015-10-22" path="§6172|(a)|(2)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2015-10-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-36" eff="2015-10-22" path="§6172|(a)|(2)|(C)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2015-10-22" doc="D.C. Law 21-36" eff="2015-10-22" path="§6172|(a)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§6034|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§6034|(a)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§6034|(c)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-04-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-76" eff="2020-04-16" path="§2|(a)|(1)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-04-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-76" eff="2020-04-16" path="§2|(a)|(2)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2020-04-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-76" eff="2020-04-16" path="§2|(a)|(3)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
