<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-173.25</num>
  <heading>Executive director; powers and duties; personnel authority.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board shall appoint an Executive Director who shall be an employee of the Authority, but who shall not be a member of the Board, and who shall serve at the pleasure of the Board and receive such compensation as shall be fixed by the Board. The Executive Director shall administer, manage, and direct the affairs and activities of the Authority in accordance with the policies, control, and direction of the Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall be a District resident within 180 days of his or her appointment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Authority shall have independent personnel authority, including the authority to establish its own personnel system.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text><cite path="1|6">Chapter 6 of Title 1</cite> shall not apply to employees of the Authority.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Within 6 months after the first meeting of the Board, the Board shall create policies, practices, and procedures for:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Hiring employees, which shall include a preference for hiring District residents, or individuals who become District residents within 180 days of their becoming an employee of the Authority, that is comparable to the degree of preference established in <cite path="1|6">Chapter 6 of Title 1</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Establishing the terms and conditions of employment for employees of the Authority.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-08-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-155" eff="2018-08-22" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-08-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-155" eff="2018-08-22" path="ยง205" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
