<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-173.51</num>
  <heading>Annual report and 3-year assessment; contents.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Authority shall publish on its website and submit to the Mayor and the Council an annual report of its activities for the preceding year. The annual report shall set forth:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A complete financial statement for the preceding fiscal year, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The total amount of loans, loan guarantees, credit enhancements, and bonds issued over the lifetime of the Authority, and the amount issued in the preceding fiscal year;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The total amount of loan payments due to the Authority and repaid to the Authority in the preceding fiscal year;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The total amount of loans forgiven by the Authority in the preceding fiscal year;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The total amount of loan payments due to the Authority in the succeeding fiscal year;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The total amount of bond debt payments payed [paid] by the Authority in the preceding fiscal year and owed by the Authority in the succeeding fiscal year; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>The total amount spent on administrative costs in the preceding fiscal year and expected to be spent in succeeding fiscal year;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A description of all sustainable projects and programs and accomplishments, including total energy generated or saved from completed clean energy projects;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The names, pay schedules, titles, and place of residence of all new employees; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Plans for the next fiscal year, and recommendations for any needed action on the part of the Mayor or Council with respect to the purposes of the Authority.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In addition to the annual report required by subsection (a) of this section, the Authority shall, within 4 years after August 22, 2018, conduct an assessment of the Authority's activities in its first 3 years of operation and provide a report to the Mayor and Council that includes recommendations on whether there is a need for additional public funding for the Authority.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-08-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-155" eff="2018-08-22" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-08-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-155" eff="2018-08-22" path="ยง501" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
