<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1771.05a</num>
  <heading>Protection against repeal of federal standards.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If any of the energy or water conservation standards issued or approved for publication by the Office of the United States Secretary of Energy as of January 19, 2017, pursuant to the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (Parts 430-431 of Title 10 of the Code of Federal Regulations) ("2017 federal standard"), are withdrawn, repealed, or otherwise voided, the minimum energy or water efficiency level permitted in the District of Columbia for such products shall be set at the 2017 federal standard, and the product shall not be sold, leased, or rented, offered for sale, lease, or rent, or installed in the District unless the efficiency of the product meets or exceeds the 2017 federal standard.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to any federal energy or water conservation standard set aside by a court upon the petition of a person who will be adversely affected, as provided in 42 U.S.C. § 6306(b).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-64" type="History" path="§6a">Dec. 11, 2007, D.C. Law 17-64, § 6a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-195" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(e)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 23-195" path="§2|(e)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2021-03-16">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-195" path="">D.C. Law 23-195</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-195" path="§3">§ 3 of D.C. Law 23-195</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-195" path="§2|(e)">§ 2(e) of D.C. Law 23-195</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-195" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(e)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
