<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1731.04</num>
  <heading>Invasive plants and nonindigenous nuisance species.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite> shall issue rules to list invasive plants and nonindigenous nuisance species; provided, that the Mayor shall not list the species <em>Felis catus</em>as a nonindigenous nuisance species.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in <cite path="§8-1731.07">§ 8-1731.07</cite>, no person shall knowingly import, transport, offer for sale, sell, purchase, give, receive, plant, spread, or introduce into the District or District waters any invasive plant listed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in <cite path="§8-1731.07">§ 8-1731.07</cite> no person shall knowingly possess, import, transport, offer for sale, sell, purchase, give, receive, breed, or introduce into the District or District waters an animal belonging to a nonindigenous nuisance species listed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>It shall not be a violation of subsection (b) or (c) of this section to possess, import, transport, offer for sale, sell, purchase, give, receive, or introduce into the District:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An invasive plant listed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section if it is dead and no longer capable of growth and reproduction;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An animal belonging to a nonindigenous nuisance species listed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section if it is dead or no longer capable of reproduction; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An animal belonging to a nonindigenous nuisance species listed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section that is domesticated.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2017-05-19" doc="D.C. Law 21-282" eff="2017-05-19" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-05-19" doc="D.C. Law 21-282" eff="2017-05-19" path="§204" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
