<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-173.24</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on October 19, 2021. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite path="§8-173.24(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
  <heading>Operations of the Green Finance Authority Board.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The powers of the Authority shall be vested in and exercised by the Board. The Board may take action at a meeting held at a time and place fixed by its bylaws.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Within 60 days after 6 of the voting members of the Board have been appointed, the Board shall adopt bylaws, guidelines, and procedures governing its meetings and decision-making processes. The procedures shall include a formal means for a member of the Board to submit their dissent from any decision of the Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The presence of 4 voting Board members shall constitute a quorum of the Board for the transaction of business. A 2/3 vote of the voting members present shall be necessary for the Board to take any official action.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Board shall meet at least 6 times each year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Authority's fiscal year shall coincide with the fiscal year of the District government.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Authority shall provide staff resources to the Board and coordinate the involvement of staff from the Department and the Office of the CFO, and any other appropriate agency or organization, as necessary.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Board shall have access to all records of the Authority.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-08-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-155" eff="2018-08-22" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-08-22" doc="D.C. Law 22-155" eff="2018-08-22" path="§204" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2021-07-21" doc="D.C. Act 24-121" eff="2021-07-21" path="§2|(b)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-07-21" doc="D.C. Act 24-121" eff="2021-07-21" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 24-121" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-07-21" eff="2021-07-21">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 24-121" path="§2|(b)">§ 2(b) of Green Finance Authority Board Quorum Emergency Amendment Act of 2021 (D.C. Act 24-121, July 21, 2021, 68 DCR 007330)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
