<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-181.02</num>
  <heading>Commission on Climate Change and Resiliency.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Commission on Climate Change and Resiliency to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Assess the potential effects of climate change on the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Assess the District's ability to adapt to and mitigate the effects of climate change;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Assess the District's ability to prepare for, respond to, and recover from severe, adverse weather events;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Identify vulnerabilities related to climate change effects and preparedness and prepare recommendations to the Council and the Mayor to mitigate those vulnerabilities; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Provide comments and recommendations to all District agencies on climate change adaptation and vulnerability mitigation plans.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall have 16 voting members, who shall be appointed as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Eight voting members appointed by the Mayor, including a chairperson.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The voting members appointed by the Mayor shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, with initial staggered appointments of 4 voting members appointed for 3 years and 4 voting members appointed for 2 years.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Eight voting members appointed by the Chairman of the Council.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The voting members appointed by the Chairman of the Council shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, with initial staggered appointments of 4 voting members appointed for 3 years and 4 voting members appointed for 2 years.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The voting members shall have demonstrable expertise in at least one of the following areas:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Emergency preparedness;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Energy;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Environmental justice;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Environmental science;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Insurance;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Natural resources;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Public health; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Transportation.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment to the position that became vacant. Voting members who are appointed to fill vacancies that occur before the expiration of a voting member's full term shall serve only the unexpired portion of the voting member's term.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>All initial appointments to the Commission shall be made within 60 days after February 18, 2017.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall consult with and seek the advice of the following agencies and entities as appropriate:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Department of Energy and Environment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Office of Planning;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The District Department of Transportation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Department of Health;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The Department of General Services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The Office of People's Counsel;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The Public Service Commission;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The Mayor's Office of Budget and Finance;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>The Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>The Office of the City Administrator;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>The Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>Local electric, gas, and telecommunications utilities.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall invite federal partners, including the General Services Administration, the Architect of the Capitol, the Department of Defense, the Department of Homeland Security, the United States Army Corps of Engineers, the National Capital Planning Commission, and the National Parks Service to participate in its discussions and planning.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2017-02-18" doc="D.C. Law 21-185" eff="2017-02-18" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-02-18" doc="D.C. Law 21-185" eff="2017-02-18" path="ยง3" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
