<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1865.02</num>
  <heading>Outdoor dining with dogs.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of District law or regulation to the contrary, a food establishment may permit dogs in outdoor dining areas or designated portions thereof, or in unenclosed sidewalk cafés.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A food establishment that permits dogs in outdoor dining areas or unenclosed sidewalk cafés may restrict types of dogs based on a dog's size or temperament.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A food establishment that permits dogs in outdoor dining areas or unenclosed sidewalk cafés shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Post signage outside the food establishment clearly stating that dogs are permitted in outdoor dining areas of the food establishment or in an unenclosed sidewalk café adjacent to the food establishment, along with any restrictions on dogs based on size or temperament;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide an entrance that does not require dogs to enter an indoor dining area or an area in which food is being stored or prepared to access the outdoor dining area or the unenclosed sidewalk café;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide patrons with waste bags and a sanitary means of disposing of waste bags;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Meet the requirements of section 503.1 of Title 25A of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (25A DCMR § 503.1), by ensuring that food employees do not care for or handle dogs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Require a patron to keep the patron's dog in a carrier or on a leash at all times; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Prohibit a patron from leaving the patron's dog unattended.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A food establishment may require a patron to take the patron's dog off the food establishment's premises or away from the food establishment's unenclosed sidewalk café.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Nothing in <cite path="8|18|VII">this subchapter</cite>, shall be construed to prevent live animals, as described in section 3214.2(b) and (c) of Title 25A of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (25A DCMR § 3214.2(b) and (c)), from accessing a food establishment.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1865.02" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§8-1865.02">
      For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-154" path="§3">§ 3 of Dining with Dogs Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-154, Oct. 23, 2017, 64 DCR 10760)</cite>.
    </codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-1865.02" type="Temporary Legislation" history="false" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§8-1865.02">
      For temporary (225 days) creation of of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-38" path="§3">§ 3 of Dining with Dogs Temporary Act of 2017 (D.C. Law 22-38, Jan. 17, 2018, 64 DCR 12300)</cite>.
    </codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2018-05-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-91" eff="2018-05-05" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2018-05-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-91" eff="2018-05-05" path="§3" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-91" path="§3" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" app="2018-05-05" eff="2018-05-05">
      For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 22-154" path="§3">§ 3 of Dining with Dogs Emergency Act of 2017 (D.C. Act 22-154, Oct. 23, 2017, 64 DCR 10760)</cite>.
    </annotation>
    <annotation app="2018-05-05" doc="D.C. Law 22-91" eff="2018-05-05" path="§3" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-91" path="§3" type="Temporary Legislation" history="false" app="2018-05-05" eff="2018-05-05">
      For temporary (225 days) creation of of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 22-38" path="§3">§ 3 of Dining with Dogs Temporary Act of 2017 (D.C. Law 22-38, Jan. 17, 2018, 64 DCR 12300)</cite>.
    </annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
