<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-2231.02</num>
  <heading>Fishing licensure by covered establishments.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may sell licenses and licensure endorsements for recreational fishing in District waters.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may authorize a covered establishment to sell licenses and licensure endorsements for recreational fishing in District waters; provided, that the covered establishment:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Designates and provides contact information for an agent to receive communication and notices from the Mayor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Operates a lawful establishment that is open to the public and maintains regular business hours;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Demonstrates the ability to efficiently maintain an operation to sell licenses and licensure endorsements for recreational fishing in District waters;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Demonstrates financial stability and responsibility;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Provides a physically secure and readily-accessible location in an area where the public may obtain licenses and licensure endorsements for recreational fishing in District waters; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Employs sufficient personnel to efficiently accommodate purchasers of licenses and licensure endorsements for recreational fishing in District waters.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In determining whether the covered establishment meets the requirements set forth in subsection (b) of this section, the Mayor may consider business performance records, business practices, financial resources, record of indebtedness, and other factors relating to financial reliability of the covered establishment, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The location at which the covered establishment intends to sell licenses and licensure endorsements for recreational fishing in District waters, including the covered establishment's proximity to other sellers of licenses and licensure endorsements for recreational fishing in District waters;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The number of customers who frequent the location;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The volume of sales at the location; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The days and hours of operation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall develop an application for a covered establishment to obtain authorization pursuant to subsection (b) of this section. An owner, partner, director, or officer authorized to bind the covered establishment may complete and file the application on behalf of the covered establishment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may develop criteria and an application for renewal of a covered establishment's authorization to sell licenses and licensure endorsements for recreational fishing in District waters. If the Mayor denies a renewal application, the covered establishment may submit an application pursuant to subsection (d) of this section to obtain authorization to sell licenses and licensure endorsements for recreational fishing in the District waters.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Authorizations to sell licenses and licensure endorsements for recreational fishing in District waters shall be:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Issued in the name of the covered establishment; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Valid for a period to be determined by the Mayor and shall expire at midnight of the last day of the period determined by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Any covered establishment authorized under subsection (b) of this section shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Accurately and promptly report transactions and sales as required by the Mayor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Make all financial settlements and payments promptly; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Hold in trust all monies received from the sale of fishing licenses, until such monies are transferred to the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may, by regulation, require a covered entity that applies for authorization or renewal of authorization pursuant to subsection (b) or (d) of this section to pay an application fee, and may prorate such fees or costs based on the period of the authorization.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>Upon expiration of an authorization, a covered establishment shall cease selling licenses and licensure endorsements for recreational fishing in District waters, unless and until the covered establishment's authorization is renewed or reissued.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2017-05-19" doc="D.C. Law 21-282" eff="2017-05-19" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-05-19" doc="D.C. Law 21-282" eff="2017-05-19" path="ยง302" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
