<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-241.03</num>
  <heading>Certification of mold assessment and remediation professionals.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director shall issue licenses and may issue certifications for conducting indoor mold assessment and remediation in the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In licensing a person to conduct indoor mold assessment or remediation, the Director may recognize certification programs of other states or independent bodies that the Director determines to be sufficient to ensure professional conduct of indoor mold assessment or remediation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No person shall engage in the business of residential indoor mold assessment or remediation unless the person is certified and licensed in accordance with requirements promulgated by the Director.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Director shall maintain a publicly available list of all certified indoor mold assessment and remediation professionals in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Director shall establish reasonable and necessary fees to administer this section, including fees for certifications and licenses. The fees shall be set, at a minimum, in an amount sufficient to recover the costs of administering this section. All fees collected under this subsection shall be deposited into the Indoor Mold Assessment and Remediation Fund established under <cite path="§8-241.07">§ 8-241.07</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-135" type="History" path="§304">Sept. 9, 2014, D.C. Law 20-135, § 304, 61 DCR 6767</annotation>
    <annotation app="notfunded" doc="D.C. Law 23-188" eff="2021-03-16" path="§5|(a)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="notfunded" doc="D.C. Law 23-188" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 23-188" path="§2|(b)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2021-03-16">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-188" path="">D.C. Law 23-188</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-188" path="§5">§ 5 of D.C. Law 23-188</cite> provided that the change made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-188" path="§2|(b)">§ 2(b) of D.C. Law 23-188</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-188" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(b)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
  <para placeholder="Not Funded">
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Not Funded.</text>
  </para>
</section>
