<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-352</num>
  <heading>Green Yards Recognition Program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Green Yards Recognition Program, which shall be administered by the Department of Energy and Environment, to encourage District property owners and lessees to maintain their grounds using only safe and sustainable practices.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Within 120 days of February 18, 2017, the Program shall establish and publish online a guide to safe and sustainable grounds maintenance, including recommendations for best practices and a list of minimum practices. At a minimum, the list of minimum practices shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Participation in at least one of the Department's Riversmart programs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Use of integrated pest management for pest control;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Use of only organic pesticides or minimum risk pesticides; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Use of only electric- or battery-powered lawn care equipment, to the extent that such equipment is reasonably available to consumers.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No later than 30 days after the publication of the guide required by subsection (b) of this section, the Department shall make available online a form allowing a District property owner or lessee to voluntarily certify to the Department that the District property owner or lessee is in compliance with the list of minimum practices published pursuant to subsection (b) of this section. The form shall include an option allowing the District property owner or lessee to order a Program yard sign pursuant to subsection (d) of this section at the time the owner or lessee submits the voluntary certification.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Department shall design a Program yard sign that affirms a District property owner or lessee's compliance with the list of minimum practices published pursuant to subsection (b) of this section. The Department may charge a fee to the District property owner or lessee to cover the cost of production of the Program yard signs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Department may cancel the voluntary certification of a District property owner or lessee upon learning that the District property owner or lessee is not in compliance with the list of minimum practices published pursuant to subsection (b) of this section. A District property owner or lessee whose certification has been canceled may not submit another voluntary certification of compliance for one year following the cancellation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Department may expand the Program to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Recognize varying types or levels of voluntary compliance with the recommendations in the guide to safe and sustainable grounds maintenance published pursuant to subsection (b) of this section; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Incorporate awards, or other methods of recognition, and incentives for participants in the Program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2017-03-11" doc="D.C. Law 21-222" eff="2017-03-11" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2017-03-11" doc="D.C. Law 21-222" eff="2017-03-11" path="ยง3" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
