<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-752</num>
  <heading>Commercial trash compactor acquisition grant program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is established a commercial trash compactor acquisition grant program to financially assist a business in the acquisition through purchase or lease of a commercial trash compactor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The CTC program shall be administered by the Mayor pursuant to the Grant Administration Act; provided, that, notwithstanding <cite path="§1-328.14|(1)">§ 1-328.14(1)</cite>, the CTC program grant application process may be established with an open-ended closing, allowing a business to apply for a grant and for the grantor, subject to subsection (b)(1) of this section, to approve a grant at any time, in accordance with rules issued pursuant to <cite path="8|7C">this chapter</cite> or the notice established pursuant to <cite path="§1-328.13|(c)">§ 1-328.13(c)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A grant shall be awarded in priority order of receipt of the grant application to the extent that the funds allocated for this purpose in an approved annual budget and financial plan or available pursuant to subparagraph (B) of this paragraph are sufficient to allow the grant.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Funds allocated for the CTC program shall not exceed $2 million per fiscal year.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The total amount of grants for Fiscal Year 2017 shall not exceed $1 million.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of § 47-368.06, grants that may be awarded pursuant to <cite path="8|7C">this chapter</cite> may include grants that the Mayor or an agency receives through an intra-District transfer, a memorandum of understanding, or a reprogramming from an agency lacking grant-making authority.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Subject to subsection (b)(1) of this section, the grantor shall award a grantee a grant in an amount:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Not to exceed $9,000 toward the leasing of an commercial trash compactor; the amount to be based on terms and length of time of the lease; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Not to exceed $13,500 for the purchase of a commercial trash compactor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Chief Financial Officer may audit the accounts of a business receiving a CTC program grant up to 3 years following the issuance of the grant.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2015-03-11" doc="D.C. Law 20-223" eff="2015-03-11" path="§202" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-223" path="§301|(b)|(2)" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="2015-03-11" eff="2015-03-11"><cite doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§7013|(b)">Section 7013(b)(1) of D.C. Law 21-160</cite> provided that this section shall apply as of October 1, 20016.
                </annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-223" path="§301|(b)|(2)" type="Editor's Notes" history="false" app="2015-03-11" eff="2015-03-11"><cite doc="D.C. Law 21-160" path="§7013|(b)">Section 7013(b)(2) of D.C. Law 21-160</cite> provided that after September 30, 2017, this section shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.
                </annotation>
    <annotation app="2016-10-08" doc="D.C. Law 21-160" eff="2016-10-08" path="§7013|(a)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
