<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-771.08</num>
  <heading>Immunity from liability; confidential information.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of <cite path="28|45">Chapter 45 of Title 28</cite>, a producer and a battery stewardship organization may negotiate, enter into agreements with, share the burdens of their operation with, and conduct business with each other in accordance with <cite path="8|7E">this chapter</cite> in ways that may affect competition. No producer or battery stewardship organization shall be prosecuted, held liable, or subject to penalties or damages under <cite path="28|45">Chapter 45 of Title 28</cite> for actions conducted in accordance with <cite path="8|7E">this chapter</cite>, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The creation, implementation, or management of a battery stewardship organization and any battery stewardship plan regardless of whether it is submitted, denied, or approved;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The cost and structure of a battery stewardship plan;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The types or quantities of batteries being recycled or otherwise managed pursuant to <cite path="8|7E">this chapter</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The establishment, administration, or disbursement of environmental handling fees or fee schedules, if applicable, to be collected at the point-of-sale for covered batteries and covered battery-containing products.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Financial, production, and sales data reported to the Mayor by a battery stewardship organization shall not be subject to disclosure under <cite path="2|5|II">subchapter II of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite> or any other law or regulation; except, that the Mayor may release a summary form of the data that does not disclose individual producer information.</text>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation applicability="effective" type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Code" path="§8-771.08" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§8-771.08">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-211" path="">D.C. Law 23-211</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-211" path="§6">§ 6 of D.C. Law 23-211</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-211" path="§2|(q)">§ 2(q) of D.C. Law 23-211</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</codify:annotation>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-154" type="History" path="§135">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-154, § 135</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(q)" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(q)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" path="§2|(q)" codified:display="Note" app="2021-03-16" eff="2021-03-16">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-211" path="">D.C. Law 23-211</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-211" path="§6">§ 6 of D.C. Law 23-211</cite> provided that the creation of this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 23-211" path="§2|(q)">§ 2(q) of D.C. Law 23-211</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2021-03-16" doc="D.C. Law 23-211" eff="2021-03-16" path="§2|(q)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
