<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>41-162.03</num>
  <heading>Action involving another state or foreign country.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Administrator may request that the Attorney General join another state or foreign country to examine and seek enforcement of <cite path="41|1A">this chapter</cite> against a putative holder.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>On request of another state or foreign country, the Attorney General may commence an action on behalf of the other state or country to enforce, in the District, the law of the other state or country against a putative holder subject to a claim by the other state or country, if the other state or country agrees to pay costs incurred by the Attorney General in the action.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Administrator may request the official authorized to enforce the unclaimed property law of another state or foreign country to commence an action to recover property in the other state or country on behalf of the Administrator.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Administrator may request that the Attorney General pursue an action on behalf of the District to recover property subject to <cite path="41|1A">this chapter</cite> but delivered to the custody of another state if the Administrator believes the property is subject to the custody of the Administrator.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Administrator, with the approval of the Attorney General, may retain an attorney in the District, another state, or a foreign country to commence an action to recover property on behalf of the Administrator and may agree to pay attorney's fees based in whole or in part on a fixed fee, hourly fee, or a percentage of the amount or value of property recovered in the action.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Expenses incurred by the District in an action under this section may be paid from property received under <cite path="41|1A">this chapter</cite> or the net proceeds of the property subject to appropriations.  Expenses paid to recover property may not be deducted from the amount that is subject to a claim under <cite path="41|1A">this chapter</cite> by the owner.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="VII|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="ยง7074" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
