<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>41-153.04</num>
  <heading>Holder domiciled in the District.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b) of this section or <cite path="§41-153.02">§ 41-153.02</cite> or <cite path="§41-153.03">§ 41-153.03</cite>, the Administrator may take custody of property presumed abandoned, whether located in the District, another state, or a foreign country, if the holder is domiciled in the District or is the District or a governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality of the District; and:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Another state or foreign country is not entitled to the property because there is no last-known address of the apparent owner or other person entitled to the property in the records of the holder; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The state or foreign country of the last-known address of the apparent owner or other person entitled to the property does not provide for custodial taking of the property.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Property is not subject to custody of the Administrator under subsection (a) of this section if the property is specifically exempt from custodial taking under the law of the District or the state or foreign country of the last-known address of the apparent owner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a holder's state of domicile has changed since the time property was presumed abandoned, the holder's state of domicile in this section is deemed to be the state where the holder was domiciled at the time the property was presumed abandoned.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="VII|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§7020" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
