<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>41-160.05</num>
  <heading>Evidence of unpaid debt or undischarged obligation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A record of a putative holder showing an unpaid debt or undischarged obligation is prima facie evidence of the debt or obligation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A putative holder may establish by a preponderance of the evidence that there is no unpaid debt or undischarged obligation for a debt or obligation described in subsection (a) of this section or that the debt or obligation was not, or no longer is, a fixed and certain obligation of the putative holder.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A putative holder may overcome prima facie evidence under subsection (a) of this section by establishing by a preponderance of the evidence that a check, draft, or similar instrument was:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Issued as an unaccepted offer in settlement of an unliquidated amount;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Issued but later was replaced with another instrument because the earlier instrument was lost or contained an error that was corrected;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Issued to a party affiliated with the issuer;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Paid, satisfied, or discharged;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Issued in error;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Issued without consideration;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Issued but there was a failure of consideration;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Voided not later than 90 days after issuance for a valid business reason set forth in a contemporaneous record; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Issued but not delivered to the third-party payee for a sufficient reason recorded within a reasonable time after issuance.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In asserting a defense under this section, a putative holder may present evidence of a course of dealing between the putative holder and the apparent owner or of custom and practice.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="VII|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="ยง7062" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
