<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>41-160.11</num>
  <heading>Report by Administrator at request of Mayor.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Pursuant to a request of the Mayor, the Administrator shall compile and submit a report containing information about property presumed abandoned for the preceding fiscal year for the District. The information requested may include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The total amount and value of all property paid or delivered under this subtitle to the Administrator;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The name of and amount paid to each contractor under section 7066 and the percentage the total compensation paid to all contractors under section 7066 bears to the total amount paid or delivered to the Administrator as a result of all examinations performed under section 7066;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The total amount and value of all property paid or delivered by the Administrator to persons that made claims for property held by the Administrator under this subtitle and the percentage the total payments made and value of property delivered to claimants bears to the total amounts paid and value delivered to the Administrator; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The total amount of claims made by persons claiming to be owners.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The report under subsection (a) of this section is a public record subject to public disclosure without redaction under the District of Columbia Freedom of Information Act, effective March 25, 1977 (D.C. Law 1-96; D.C. Official Code ยง 2-531 <em>et seq.</em>).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="VII|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="ยง7068" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
