<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>41-154.02</num>
  <heading>Content of report.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The report required under <cite path="§41-154.02">this section</cite> shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be signed by or on behalf of the holder and verified as to its completeness and accuracy;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If filed electronically, be in a secure format approved by the Administrator that protects confidential information of the apparent owner in the same manner as required of the Administrator and the Administrator's agent under <cite path="41|1A|XIV">subchapter XIV of this chapter</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Describe the property;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Except for a traveler's check, money order, or similar instrument, contain the name, if known, last-known address, if known, and Social Security number or taxpayer identification number, if known or readily ascertainable, of the apparent owner of property with a value of $50 or more;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>For an amount held or owing under a life or endowment insurance policy or annuity contract, contain the name and last-known address of the insured, annuitant or other apparent owner of the policy or contract and of the beneficiary;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>For property held in or removed from a safe-deposit box, indicate the location of the property, where it may be inspected by the Administrator, and any amounts owed to the holder under <cite path="§41-156.06">§ 41-156.06</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Contain the commencement date for determining abandonment under <cite path="41|1A|II">subchapter II of this chapter</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>State that the holder has complied with the notice requirements of <cite path="§41-156.07">§ 41-156.07</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Identify property that is a non-freely transferable security and explain why it is a non-freely transferable security; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Contain other information the Administrator prescribes by rules.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A report under <cite path="§41-154.01">§ 41-154.01</cite> may include personal information as defined in <cite path="§41-164.01">§ 41-164.01</cite> about the apparent owner or the apparent owner's property to the extent not otherwise prohibited by federal law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a holder has changed its name while holding property presumed abandoned or is a successor to another person that previously held the property for the apparent owner, the holder shall include in the report under <cite path="§41-154.01">§ 41-154.01</cite> its former name or the name of the previous holder, if any, and the known name and address of each previous holder of the property.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="VII|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§7025" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
