<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>41-160.09</num>
  <heading>Administrator's contract with another to conduct examination.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In this section, "related to the Administrator" means an individual who is:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Administrator's spouse, partner in a civil union, domestic partner, or reciprocal beneficiary;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Administrator's child, stepchild, grandchild, parent, stepparent, sibling, step-sibling, half-sibling, aunt, uncle, niece, or nephew;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A spouse, partner in a civil union, domestic partner, or reciprocal beneficiary of an individual under paragraph (2) of this subsection; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any individual residing in the Administrator's household.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Administrator may contract with a person to conduct an examination under<cite path="41|1A|X">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the person with which the Administrator contracts under subsection (b) of this section is:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An individual, the individual may not be related to the Administrator; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A business entity, the entity may not be owned in whole or in part by the Administrator or an individual related to the Administrator.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>At least 60 days before assigning a person under contract with the Administrator under subsection (b) of this section to conduct an examination, the Administrator shall demand in a record that the person to be examined submit a report and deliver property that is previously unreported.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If the Administrator contracts with a person under subsection (b) of this section:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The contract may provide for compensation of the person based on a fixed fee, hourly fee, or contingent fee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A contingent fee arrangement may not provide for a payment that exceeds 10 percent of the amount or value of property paid or delivered as a result of the examination, except for contracts in force on August 23, 2021; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>On request by a person subject to examination by a contractor, the Administrator shall deliver to the person a complete and unredacted copy of the contract and any contract between the contractor and a person employed or engaged by the contractor to conduct the examination.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A contract under subsection (b) of this section is subject to public disclosure without redaction under <cite path="2|5|II">subchapter II of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="VII|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="ยง7066" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
