<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>41-153.01</num>
  <heading>Address of apparent owner to establish priority.</heading>
  <para>
    <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
    <text>In <cite path="41|1A|III">this subchapter</cite>, the following rules apply:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The last-known address of an apparent owner is any description, code, or other indication of the location of the apparent owner that identifies the state, even if the description, code, or indication of location is not sufficient to direct the delivery of first-class United States mail to the apparent owner.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the United States postal zip code associated with the apparent owner is for a post office located in the District, the District is deemed to be the state of the last-known address of the apparent owner unless other records associated with the apparent owner specifically identify the physical address of the apparent owner to be in another state.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the address under paragraph (2) of this subsection is in another state, the other state is deemed to be the state of the last-known address of the apparent owner.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The address of the apparent owner of a life or endowment insurance policy or annuity contract or its proceeds is presumed to be the address of the insured or annuitant if a person other than the insured or annuitant is entitled to the amount owed under the policy or contract and the address of the other person is not known by the insurance company and cannot be determined under <cite path="ยง41-153.02">ยง 41-153.02</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="VII|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="ยง7017" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
