<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>41-164.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions; applicability.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In <cite path="41|1A|XIV">this subchapter</cite>, "personal information" means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Information that identifies or reasonably can be used to identify an individual, such as first and last name in combination with the individual's:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Social security number or other government-issued number or identifier;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Date of birth;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Home or physical address;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Electronic-mail address or other online contact information or Internet provider address;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Financial account number or credit or debit card number;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Biometric data, health or medical data, or insurance information; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Passwords or other credentials that permit access to an online or other account;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Personally identifiable financial or insurance information, including nonpublic personal information defined by applicable federal law; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any combination of data that, if accessed, disclosed, modified, or destroyed without authorization of the owner of the data or if lost or misused, would require notice or reporting under§§ <cite path="§28-3851">28-3851</cite> to <cite path="§28-3864">28-3864</cite> and federal privacy and data security law, whether or not the Administrator or the Administrator's agent is subject to the law.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A provision of <cite path="41|1A|XIII">subchapter XIII of this chapter</cite> that applies to the Administrator or the Administrator's records applies to an Administrator's agent.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="VII|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§7082" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
