<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>41-164.08</num>
  <heading>Indemnification for breach by agent.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a claim is made or action commenced arising out of an event described in <cite path="§41-164.07|(a)">§ 41-164.07(a)</cite> relating to confidential information possessed by an Administrator's agent, the Administrator's agent shall indemnify, defend, and hold harmless a holder and the holder's affiliates, officers, directors, employees, and agents as to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any claim or action and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A liability, obligation, loss, damage, cost, fee, penalty, fine, settlement, charge, or other expense, including reasonable attorney's fees and costs, established by the claim or action.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Administrator shall require an Administrator's agent that will receive confidential information required under <cite path="41|1A">this chapter</cite> to maintain adequate insurance for indemnification obligations of the Administrator's agent under subsection (a) of this section. The agent required to maintain the insurance shall provide evidence of the insurance to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Administrator not less frequently than annually; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The holder on commencement of an examination and annually thereafter until all confidential information is returned or destroyed under <cite path="§41-164.06|(e)">§ 41-164.06(e)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="VII|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§7089" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
