<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>41-164.07</num>
  <heading>Security breach.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except to the extent prohibited by law other than <cite path="41|1A">this chapter</cite>, the Administrator or Administrator's agent shall notify a holder as soon as practicable of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A suspected loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or destruction of confidential information obtained from the holder in the possession of the Administrator or an Administrator's agent; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any interference with operations in any system hosting or housing confidential information that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Compromises the security, confidentiality, or integrity of the information; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Creates a substantial risk of identity fraud or theft.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as necessary to inform an insurer, attorney, investigator, or others as required by law, the Administrator and an Administrator's agent may not disclose, without the express consent in a record of the holder, an event described in subsection (a) of this section to a person whose confidential information was supplied by the holder.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If an event described in subsection (a) of this section occurs, the Administrator and the Administrator's agent shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Take action necessary for the holder to understand and minimize the effect of the event and determine its scope; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Cooperate with the holder with respect to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Any notification required by law concerning a data or other security breach; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A regulatory inquiry, litigation, or similar action.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="VII|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="ยง7088" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
