<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>41-164.03</num>
  <heading>When confidential information may be disclosed.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When reasonably necessary to enforce or implement <cite path="41|1A">this chapter</cite>, the Administrator may disclose confidential information concerning property held by the Administrator or the Administrator's agent only to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An apparent owner or the apparent owner's personal representative, attorney, other legal representative, relative, or agent designated under <cite path="§41-163.03">§ 41-163.03</cite> to have the information;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The personal representative other legal representative, relative of a deceased apparent owner, agent designated under <cite path="§41-163.03">§ 41-163.03</cite> by the deceased apparent owner, or a person entitled to inherit from the deceased apparent owner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Another department or agency of the District or the United States;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The person that administers the unclaimed property law of another state, if the other state accords substantially reciprocal privileges to the Administrator of the District if the other state is required to maintain the confidentiality and security of information obtained in a manner substantially equivalent to <cite path="41|1A|XIV">this subchapter</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A person subject to an examination as required by <cite path="§41-160.04|(6)">§ 41-160.04(6)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in <cite path="§41-164.02|(a)">§ 41-164.02(a)</cite>, the Administrator shall include on the website or in the database required by <cite path="§41-155.03">§ 41-155.03</cite> the name of each apparent owner of property held by the Administrator. The Administrator may include in published notices, printed publications, telecommunications, the Internet, or other media and on the website or in the database additional information concerning the apparent owner's property if the Administrator believes the information will assist in identifying and returning property to the owner and does not disclose personal information except the home or physical address of an apparent owner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Administrator and the Administrator's agent may not use confidential information provided to them or in their possession except as expressly authorized by <cite path="41|1A">this chapter</cite> or required by law other than <cite path="41|1A">this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="VII|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§7084" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
