<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>41-164.06</num>
  <heading>Security of information.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a holder is required to include confidential information in a report to the Administrator, the information must be provided by a secure means.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If confidential information in a record is provided to and maintained by the Administrator or Administrator's agent as required by <cite path="41|1A">this chapter</cite>, the Administrator or agent shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Implement administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to protect the security, confidentiality, and integrity of the information required by  §§ <cite path="§28-3851">§ 28-3851</cite> to <cite path="§28-3864">§ 28-3864</cite> and federal privacy and data security law whether or not the Administrator or the Administrator's agent is subject to the law;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Protect against reasonably anticipated threats or hazards to the security, confidentiality, or integrity of the information; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Protect against unauthorized access to or use of the information that could result in substantial harm or inconvenience to a holder or the holder's customers, including insureds, annuitants, and policy or contract owners and their beneficiaries.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Administrator:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>After notice and comment, shall adopt and implement a security plan that identifies and assesses reasonably foreseeable internal and external risks to confidential information in the Administrator's possession and seeks to mitigate the risks; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Shall ensure that an Administrator's agent adopts and implements a similar plan with respect to confidential information in the agent's possession.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Administrator and the Administrator's agent shall educate and train their employees regarding the plan adopted under subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Administrator and the Administrator's agent shall in a secure manner return or destroy all confidential information no longer reasonably needed under <cite path="41|1A">this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="VII|A" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2021-08-23" doc="D.C. Act 24-159" eff="2021-08-23" path="§7087" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
